<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3.xsd" version="0.3" xml:lang="en">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>Stuyclopedia</sitename>
    <base>http://www.stuyclopedia.com/Main_Page</base>
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.15.1</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
    <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0" />
      <namespace key="1">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4">Stuyclopedia</namespace>
      <namespace key="5">Stuyclopedia talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6">File</namespace>
      <namespace key="7">File talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15">Category talk</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>694</title>
    <id>119</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1047</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-11T06:15:44Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1244591903</username>
        <id>5</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Stuypulse]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Stuypulse]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Biology</title>
    <id>249</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94480</id>
      <timestamp>2011-08-04T05:19:55Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>AngelSlayervrNv</username>
        <id>111</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt; [http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 stuyclopedia]&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 &gt;&gt;stuyclopedia&lt;&lt;]&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 stuyclopedia!]&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Calculus AB</title>
    <id>93</id>
    <revision>
      <id>96732</id>
      <timestamp>2013-04-03T05:20:18Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>69.114.3.22</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Calculus AB
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = MC1X/MC2X
| teachers      = Mr. Gary Jaye, Mr. Sebastian Stoenescu, Mr. Usoroh, Ms. Ferrara
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = [[Precalculus]] (pre- or co-req)
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Fourth floor|Fourth]]
| website       = 
}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Calculus BC</title>
    <id>83</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95071</id>
      <timestamp>2011-11-20T19:42:25Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.46.169.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Ms. Pascu */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Calculus BC
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = MC3X/MC4X
| teachers      = [[Ms. Deena Avigdor|Ms. Avigdor]], [[Mr. Jim Cocoros|Mr. Cocoros]], and [[Ms. Joy Schimmel|Ms. Schimmel]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = [[Precalculus]] (pre- or co-req)
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = [[Calculus (textbook)|Calculus]]
| floor         = [[Fourth floor|Fourth]]
| website       = 
}}

'''AP Calculus BC''' is a full-year single-period [[Advanced Placement]] course that teaches the calculus of functions of a single variable, typically learned in the first year of college. The course material includes all of the topics taught in [[AP Calculus AB]] along with other topics, one of the largest being series.

==Curriculum==
The curriculum begins with a discussion of functions and graphs, specifically in regard to limits and continuity. Students are then presented with the concept of the derivative at a point and the derivative as a function as well as techniques and rules for calculating derivatives. Applications of the derivative are then explained. The anti-derivatives and integral are introduced along with various methods for obtaining numerical approximations for integrals. Properties and applications of the integral are discussed, with a large discussion of its use for finding volumes of figures formed by rotating curves about the x and y axes. After volume, the derivatives and anti-derivatives of ''e''&lt;sup&gt;x&lt;/sup&gt; and the natural logarithm are introduced and used with concepts students have already learned. 

The spring term begins with more techniques of integration. Differentials are further discussed after their previous brief mention. The last topic, and the one found most difficult due to its counterintuitiveness, is series. Students are taught how to discern convergent and divergent series. Taylor series and polynomial approximations by using series are the last topic before the [[AP exam]]. After the students take the [[AP exam]] in May, hyperbolic functions are discussed.

==Teaching style==
===Ms. Avigdor===
Ms. Avigdor's class and teaching style are efficient and structured. There isn't a single idle moment during class time. Each session will consist of a do-now, lesson, and thorough review of homework. The lessons are relatively straightforward, consistent, and traditional. Most students call her class challenging but fair.

====Grading policy====
Grade is determined by dividing the total number of points you have earned by the total possible points and multiplying by 100.  The possible points for each kind of assessment are listed as follows:
*Tests &amp;mdash; 100 points
*Final &amp;mdash; 100 points, counting as one or two exams
*Quests &amp;mdash; 20&amp;ndash;25 points
*Quizzes &amp;mdash; 10&amp;ndash;25 points
*Group work &amp;mdash; 10&amp;ndash;30 points
Participation and extra credit assignments also contribute.

===Mr. Cocoros===
[[Mr. Jim Cocoros]] is generally considered both an informative and fun teacher. He often uses mnemonic devices and self invented terminology (i.e. &quot;pothole&quot; to refer to a discontinuity), rather than traditional mathematical terminology. Many students benefit from this style of teaching and find his tests relatively easy.  

Mr. Cocoros often begins the lesson with a do now, during which he often plays a topical song from his iPod. He also generally has an aim, which is usually a pun on the day's lesson. He usually then goes into a more traditional lecture on the day's topic, though he punctuates it with questions for the class, practice problems, and his trademark humor. Homework is assigned practically nightly, and is relatively substantial (about 10-20 problems a night). Homework is collected before class in boxes placed outside the math office. This allows him to check the homework and return it during class, which is helpful when homework is reviewed during class.

Mr. Cocoros is known for covering the AP curriculum more slowly than other teachers. He often finishes the material on the day before the AP test. He recognizes this fact and often jokes about it. This is in part caused by his choice to cover a number of proofs not on the AP curriculum. He also takes a number of days off in the fall to write college recommendations, delaying the curriculum.

===Ms. Pascu===


====Grading policy====

==AP exam==
Students who take AP Calculus BC are expected to take the [[AP exam]] in May. The topics and skills tested on the exam are outlined on the [http://www.collegeboard.com/student/testing/ap/calculus_bc/topic.html?calcbc CollegeBoard course topic outline site]:

The test consists of two sections. Section I contains two sets of multiple choice questions: Part A consists of 28 questions in 55 minutes, during which calculators aren't allowed, and Part B consists of 17 questions in 50 minutes, in which calculators are allowed. Section II contains two sets of free-response questions: Part A contains 3 questions to be done in 45 minutes with a graphing calculator; Part B also contains 3 questions to be done in 45 minutes, but without a calculator.  During Part B, you may go back to Part A, but you may not use your calculator. Approximately 60% of the questions are shared between the AP Calculus BC exam and the AP Calculus AB exam. 

==External links==
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/math_descriptions/maxa.html Stuyvesant course description site] in the [http://math.stuy.edu/ Mathematics department site]
*[http://www.collegeboard.com/student/testing/ap/sub_calbc.html?calcbc CollegeBoard course description site]
*{{Wikipedia|Advanced Placement Calculus}}
*[http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/apc/public/repository/ap09_CalculusBC_GradeDistributions.pdf CollegeBoard May 2009 AP Calculus BC Exam Grade Distributions]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Chemistry</title>
    <id>87</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97151</id>
      <timestamp>2013-07-07T22:29:27Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.21.14.74</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Teaching Style */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Chemistry
| department    = [[Chemistry and Physics department|Chemistry and Physics]]
| code          = SC3X/SC4X
| teachers      = [[Mr. Steven O'Malley]] and [[Ms. Jee Paik]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Science elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Chemistry]], [[Precalculus]], [[Regents Physics]] 
|  textbooks     = Chemistry by Zumdahl and Zumdahl
| floor         = [[Ninth floor|Ninth]]
}}
'''AP Chemistry''' is a full year, ''double-period'' [[Advanced Placement]] course that teaches preparatory chemistry for college. This course is the continuation of the [[Regents Chemistry]] course. It is considerably more difficult than the Regents Chemistry course, due to the fact that students do not have such a detailed reference table to get answers from. Key topics include stoichiometry, matter, atomic structure, bonding, solution chemistry, kinetics, equilibrium, acids and bases, and redox and electrochemistry. Since the class is based on math, the student should have basic algebra skills.

Although the class is a double period class, every other day, students get the second period free. This counts as a science free. This class is taught by [[Dr. Steven O'Malley]] and [[Ms. Jee Paik]]. 

==Curriculum==
The curriculum follows the order of subjects in the textbook, Chemistry, by Zumdahl and Zumdahl. The first term begins with basic concepts such as measurement and significant figures. The next topic is matter, which includes properties of matter, discussion of elements, and states of matter. These topics take up the first few weeks of the semester. The next few topics discussed deal with stoichiometry, acid-base reactions, and bonding. These topics are fairly large, and take up most of the semester. The semester ends with the topics of gases and solutions. 

==Teaching Style==

===Dr. O'Malley===

===Ms. Paik===

==Labs==
There are about 8 labs per term in this class. Most of them are based on Regents labs with additional material from the AP course, such as the calorimeter lab. A few labs are brand new to the student, such as the spectrophotometer lab. Labs are held in room 903.

Lab reports are typed up and handed into the teacher on a specified due date. Lab work is done during class time once ever 2-3 weeks, during which data is collected. The typed up reports include the aim, data, results, error, and conclusion. They are graded out of 10, like the Regents labs are.

==AP exam==
The AP exam has changed in the past few years. The new exam is broken down into the following:
*Section I (90 minutes, no calculator)
**75 multiple &amp;mdash; 50%
*Section II 
**Part A (55 minutes, calculator)
***Equilibrium problem &amp;mdash; 10%
***Other problem &amp;mdash; 10%
***Other problem &amp;mdash; 10%
**Part B (40 minutes, no calculator)
***Reactions question &amp;mdash; 5%
***Essay question &amp;mdash; 7.5%
***Essay question &amp;mdash; 7.5%
The multiple choice questions are broken down into the following:
*Structure of matter &amp;mdash; 20%
*States of matter &amp;mdash; 20%
*Reactions &amp;mdash; 35-40%
*Descriptive chemistry &amp;mdash; 10-15%
*Laboratory &amp;mdash; 5-15%

==External links==
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/chem_phys_descriptions/scx3.html/ Stuyvesant course description site] in the [http://chem.stuy.edu/?p=home/ Chemistry department site]
*[http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/apc/public/repository/ap08_chemistry_coursedesc.pdf/ College board course description site]
*{{Wikipedia|Advanced Placement Chemistry}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Computer Science</title>
    <id>86</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3461</id>
      <timestamp>2010-10-17T00:36:13Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1347632498</username>
        <id>8</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>rw</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Computer Science
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = MLX1 and MLX2
| teachers      = Varies by year
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = full year
| fills         = [[senior elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Introduction to Computer Science]] (Prereq)
| pre/coreq_for = [[System Level Programming]], [[Computer Graphics]] (Prereq)
| textbooks     = [[Head First Java]], [[The Java API]], An unused Java textbook
| floor         = [[Third floor|Three]]
| website       = wiki.stuy.edu/cs
}}

'''AP Computer Science''', officially '''AP Computer Science A''', is a one-year [[Advanced Placement]] computer science course typically taken in Junior or Senior year.  It is one of the most popular AP courses.  The first semester teaches students how to program in Java, including object-oriented programming, classes, interfaces, polymorphism, searching, recursion, basic sorts, big-O notation and GUI programming.  The second semester focuses on sorts data structures, specifically merge sort, quick sort, linked lists, queues, stacks, trees, binary search trees, heaps, maps, hash tables, and the big-O measurements for all of them.

Originally, there were two AP tests and courses for computer science, A and AB.  The A course was equivalent to the first semester, while the AB course was equivalent to both.  Because the A course was vastly more popular than the AB course, the [[College Board]] has pulled the AB course.  However, at Stuyvesant, the full course is still taught.

==Curriculum==

The first semester is primarily learning how to program in Java. The exact progression of topics depends on the teacher, but typically, the class will start by learning about object-oriented programming, move to polymorphism, and finally, write a few searching and sorting algorithms and analyze their efficiency using big-O notation.  At some point, the class will also learn how to program GUI's.  There is sometimes a final project for the first semester; the point is to demonstrate knowledge of the Java language, not to show a deep understanding of principles beyond the basic ones (an understanding of polymorphism should be demonstrated).  There may or may not be a final exam for the first term, depending on the teacher.

The second semester is generally more difficult.  The focus is on understanding various data structures and their advantages and disadvantages.  Big-O notation will be heavily used in the second semester to explain the efficiency of various algorithms and data structures.  There will be a final project at the end of the semester to show an understanding of data structures.  There may or may not be a final exam.

==Teaching Style==

===Mr. DW===
Mr. DW's class is fairly relaxed and informal.  He assigns occasional homework, due at 2 AM.  

===Mr. Zamansky===
Mr. Zamansky's class is also fairly relaxed.  He frequently assigns small homeworks that add up to become part of a larger project.  Homework is submitted through subversion, and he grades it when he is able to.  It is sometimes possible to submit late homework: he will take anything as long as it is submitted before he grades it.

===Mr. Platek===
Mr. Platek has a basic teaching style, mixing lecture and lab periods where students work on programming exercises or projects. He is considered by many students to be dry in manner, particularly due to his soft voice. Homework assignments are given relatively regularly and are submitted through an online submission site. Approximately two tests are given per semester, usually formed of questions from past AP tests. Mr. Platek regularly reincludes identical questions on his tests to make sure students review questions they get wrong.

===Mr. Brooks===

==AP Exam==

The Computer Science A exam is widely considered among the easiest of the AP exams. It tests only material covered in the first term, as the A test was originally meant to be an alternative to the more difficult data-structure-heavy AB test.  It is rarely accepted for any sort of college credit (unlike the AB test), but students should take it anyway for college applications.

The test has a multiple-choice section and a free-response section that requires students to write programs.

==Textbooks==

There are three texts for the course.  The official textbook is rarely, if ever, used.  

The online Java API contains all the commands in Java.  There are two versions of the API: the AP version, and the real version.  The real version is highly recommended, as the AP version is incomplete (it only contains commands and classes relevant to the AP exam) and some parts of it are actually incorrect.  However, to study for the AP, students should use the AP version as the incorrect commands and classes are what are used in the test.

The third textbook is HeadFirst Java.  While reading is rarely given as a homework assignment, the book is a very good reference, especially for teaching things not taught in the class that may be useful for projects (such as inner classes and exception handling)</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP European History</title>
    <id>258</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95195</id>
      <timestamp>2011-12-10T22:02:47Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.27.116.34</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with 'The AP European History course is a yearlong sophomore course that follows the AP Euro curriculum. It is taught by [[Josina Dunkel]] and renowned for its advanced discussions and…'</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The AP European History course is a yearlong sophomore course that follows the AP Euro curriculum. It is taught by [[Josina Dunkel]] and renowned for its advanced discussions and readings, paired with an intensive workload. Students are encouraged to take the course along with European Literature.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Music Theory</title>
    <id>82</id>
    <revision>
      <id>662</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-01T03:52:48Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>/* External links */  wrote out AP in wikilink</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Music Theory
| department    = [[Music and Fine Arts]]
| code          = AUUX1/AUUX2
| teachers      = [[Mr. Joseph Tamosaitis]]
| typical_year  = [[Sophomore]], [[Junior]], or [[Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Senior elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[First]]
| website       = 
}}
'''AP Music Theory''' is a full-year [[Advanced Placement]] class on basic college level music theory and ear training. This course focuses mainly on classical music before the 20th century, though some portions of the course do include other music, such as jazz and contemporary music. Topics include scales, intervals, style, rhythm, form, analysis, seventh chords, figured bass, counterpoint, dictations (melodic and harmonic), and sightsinging. Starting from the 2009-2010 school year, this class is taught first period, as opposed to second period in previous years. [[Mr. Joseph Tamosaitis]] is the only teacher of AP Music Theory, of which there is only one class.

==Curriculum==
The course begins with a review of writing, identifying, and hearing scales, intervals, and triads. After a week of review, the course moves onto basic composition. This includes four-part voice leading and composition of a bass line using figured bass and Roman numerals. Meanwhile, students will also start practice with melodic and two-part dictation and sightsinging.

After basic composition, students will analyze scores, which include cadences, motives, modulation, texture, form, and rhythmic and meter organization. At this point in the curriculum, students will also be broadening their aural skills. They will be asked to sightsing more complicated melodies, write out four-part dictations, identify errors in rhythm and pitch, recognize instrumentation, and describe melodic, harmonic, and tonal organization.

==Teaching style==
Mr. Tamosaitis is flexible when teaching the AP Music Theory curriculum. He moves at the pace that is comfortable for the class; consequently, the time it takes to teach the curriculum changes every year. Sometimes, a slow pace will result in less time for a later topic. Also, he may teach the curriculum in an order different from what is recommended by [[College Board]] depending on the strengths and weaknesses of the class in each topic. 

If he teaches a lesson that is more related to ear training, such as sightsinging or dictations, he usually works with the class on a practice sightsinging exercise or dictation. Then, if it is sightsinging, he asks each student to sing an example alone. If it is a dictation, he plays another dictation after the example, but each student works alone to write out this second dictation. He then collects the work at the end of the period and grades all the dictations by the next day.

If he teaches a lesson that is more related to theory, he introduces the new topic, writing any crucial points on the board, and then gives students practice problems (often old AP problems) to apply the new material. These include identifying chords, completing chord resolutions, and analyzing musical works. Like dictations, he may collect these problems at the end of the class and grade them by the next day. 

Mr. Tamosaitis wants students to go beyond an AP level. He is willing to work with more advanced students on material past the AP exam, such as sightsinging in alto clef and identifying and resolving augmented sixth chords. However, he asks that all students attempt to sightsing in solfege, which is not an AP requirement.

After the AP exam, Mr. Tamosaitis encourages students to put the material they have just learned over the past year to use. He splits up the class into several groups of four or five people and allows them to compose their own music and perform it on the last day of classes. Students may compose whatever kind of music they want to, so even this final composition allows students to go beyond AP material.

===Grading policy===
Though there are no set percentages used to calculate a student's final grade, the grade is based mainly upon effort, attendance, and a few practice AP exams during the second term.

==AP exam==
Though students taking the AP Music Theory course are expected to take the AP exam, many students each year choose not to take it. This may be due to Mr. Tamosaitis's pace in the curriculum. Even though he does cover most of the course, he does not spend much time on vocabulary used in the exam, which can be a major part of the multiple choice section. While the percentage of students in the class taking the exam varies every year, it is not uncommon to see less than half the students take the exam. Each type of question is weighed as follows:
*Multiple choice (75 questions)&amp;mdash;45%
*Free response (7 questions)&amp;mdash;45%
*Sightsinging (2 melodies of about four to eight bars)&amp;mdash;10%
Though students tend to have mixed responses about the multiple choice and free response sections, most students agree that the sightsinging section is the easiest since both melodies are mainly diatonic.

The final grade is broken up into two subscores: an aural and a nonaural grade. The aural grade involves questions with aural stimulus, when a excerpt of music is played on a CD player and questions relating to that excerpt are to be answered. The nonaural grade involves all other test questions. When students receive their AP results over the summer, they receive the aural grade, the nonaural grade, and the overall grade. Stuyvesant students tend to receive a 4 on one part, a 5 on the other part, and a 5 on the overall grade.

==External links==
*[http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/apc/public/repository/ap08_music_coursedesc.pdf Collegeboard course description]
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/art&amp;music_descriptions/utx1.html Stuyvesant course description]
*{{Wikipedia|Advanced Placement Music Theory}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Physics B</title>
    <id>78</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97153</id>
      <timestamp>2013-07-07T22:32:19Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.21.14.74</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Physics B
| department    = [[Chemistry and Physics department|Chemistry and Physics]]
| code          = SP1X/SP2X
| teachers      = [[Mr. John Avallone]]
| typical_year  = [[Sophomore year|Sophomore]], [[Junior year|Junior]], or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Science elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Physics]]
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Eighth floor|Eighth]]
| website       = http://teacherweb.com/NY/StuyvesantHighSchool/MrAvallone/index.html (Avallone)
}}
'''AP Physics B''' is a full-year, single-period [[Advanced Placement]] course that teaches preparatory physics for college. This course is the continuation of the [[Regents Physics]] course, and gives a wider scope of knowledge of the physical world. Key topics include linear mechanics, rotational motion, energy, springs and pendulums, thermodynamics, fluid dynamics, electricity and magnetism, waves and optics, light, quantum mechanics, and relative theory. [[Mr. John Avallone]] teaches this course. 

Contrary to the information on the [http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/chem_phys_descriptions/spx1.html Stuyvesant course site], [[Precalculus]] is ''not'' needed as a prerequisite or a corequisite. However, basic algebra and trigonometry skills are needed to take the course. Most of the course focuses on concept rather than mathematical formulas, although formulas are used to help students to understand some of the concepts. 

==Curriculum==
The Fall term consists of the first three units. The first unit deals with Newtonian motion, including kinematics, Newton's laws of motion, energy, momentum, rotation, oscillation, and gravitation. The second unit deals with fluid mechanics, which is a new topic not mentioned in the Regents Physics course. This unit deals with Archimedes' Principle, hydrostatics, continuity, and Bernoulli's equation. The third unit deals with thermal physics. This unit includes heat, temperature, kinetic theory, and mechanical systems involving heat energy. 

The Spring term begins with discussion of electricity and magnetism, and discusses charge, electric fields and forces, circuits, currents, resistance, magnetic fields, and electromagnetic induction. The next unit focuses on waves and optics. This unit goes in-depth on the movement of waves, wave interference, diffraction, refraction, light properties, lenses, and mirrors. The next unit takes ideas from the wave unit and integrates it to discuss atomic and nuclear physics. This unit includes quantum physics, atomic structure, wave-particle duality, nuclear reactions, and mass-energy equivalence. The final unit, perhaps the most interesting, is the relativity unit, which discusses Einstein's relativity theory and its meaning.

==Teaching style==
===Mr. Avallone===
[[Mr. John Avallone]] is a relatively lax teacher and emphasizes the learning aspect of the class. In fact, he does not care about the AP test. He feels that his class is solely a learning experience, and that whomever would like to take the AP test will be fully prepared for it by the end of the year. He uses an interactive learning experience structured on physics demonstrations, such as a few using a stuffed Narwhal.

Mr. Avallone's class begins with an introduction to the topic via some demonstration or a straightforward example, but seldom a [[Do Now]], and goes into the topic of the day. Mr. Avallone then explains the concept of the topic. If the topic is mathematical, such as Bernoulli's equation,  he gives a few practice problems for the rest of the period. If the topic is more conceptual, such as black body radiation, Mr. Avallone goes in depth on the topic. In addition, often he stresses dimensional analysis as the best way to &quot;guess&quot; formulas, and recommends that his students apply these skills on a test.

Mr. Avallone also teaches topics not in the curriculum, such as moment of inertia, because he feels that the student will not truly understand how the world works without understanding some of the basic physical concepts that are not part of the curriculum.

Tests are given in a standard fashion, with about six tests per term. Mr. Avallone's tests are considered by many to be relatively difficult. His tests are considered more fun by his students, evidenced by the tendency of most of his students to giggle during his tests(often aliens and narwhals can be found in the questions). Students tend to score below average, but Mr. Avallone allows each student two resubmissions of tests; the student redoes the problems he or she got wrong, and gets back half the points he or she lost, or if the entire class does subpar, the class would often a free test submission with the [[square root curve]], depending on Mr. Avallone's choice. (For example, a 76 becomes an 88 and a 90 becomes a 95 under the first curve, and a 64 becomes an 80 and an 81 becomes a 90 under the square root curve.) This extra resubmission may or may not be allowed to be combo-ed with the existing &quot;half-credit&quot; resubmission.

===Grading Policy===
*Participation &amp;mdash; 5%
*Homework &amp;mdash; 5%
*Labs &amp;mdash; 10%
*Tests &amp;mdash; 60%
*Final &amp;mdash; 20%

==Labs==
There are about 8 labs per term in AP Physics B. Most of them are revamped versions of Regents labs, with extra additions to fit the AP curriculum. For example, the photogate timer lab is slightly changed with the addition of rotational motion and rotational energy. Other labs are brand new to students, such as the electric field lab.

Labs are done in a lab notebook; this may be a graph paper book, a binder, or a folder filled with papers. They are graded the same way as Regents labs. Labs are held in room 827.

==AP exam==
Students who take AP Physics are expected to take the [[AP exam]] in May. The test is based on the following percentage goals as stated in the [http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/apc/public/repository/ap07_physics_coursedesc.pdf/ college board course description site]:
*Newtonian mechanics &amp;mdash; 35%
*Fluid mechanics &amp;mdash; 15%
*Electricity and magnetism &amp;mdash; 25%
*Waves and optics &amp;mdash; 15%
*Atomic and nuclear physics &amp;mdash; 10%
The test consists of 70 multiple choice questions in 90 minutes, during which calculators or reference table with formulas aren't allowed, and 7 short answer questions in 90 minutes, during which calculators are allowed and reference tables with formulas will be given.

Most students consider the multiple choice to be harder, due to the lack of a reference tables and calculators. The short answers are usually broken down into parts, so really there are more than 7 questions. Nonetheless, Stuyvesant students typically score 4s and 5s on this test.

==External links==
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/chem_phys_descriptions/spx1.html Stuyvesant course description site] in the [http://phys.stuy.edu/?p=home Physics department site]
*[http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/apc/public/repository/ap07_physics_coursedesc.pdf/ College board course description site]
*{{Wikipedia|Advanced Placement Physics B}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Physics C</title>
    <id>103</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97154</id>
      <timestamp>2013-07-07T22:33:59Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.21.14.74</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Physics C
| department    = [[Chemistry and Physics department|Chemistry and Physics]]
| code          = SP3X/SP4X
| teachers      = [[Dr. Jamal Ali]]
| typical_year  = [[Senior year|Senior]] with some [[Junior year|Juniors]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Science elective requirement]], [[Senior elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Physics]] (Pre-), [[AP Calculus AB]] (pre-), [[AP Calculus BC]] (pre- or co-)
| pre/coreq_for = Advanced physics courses that are never actually offered
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Eighth floor|Eighth]]
| website       = 
}}

AP Physics C is a full-year, double period[[Advanced Placement]] course roughly equivalent to a first-year college physics course.  Much like [[AP Physics B]] is a continuation of [[Regents Physics]], but Physics C  only focuses on two topics: Mechanics and Electricity and Magnetism.  However, it goes into far more depth than B and, as a result, far more colleges accept credit from the C tests than the B test.  Also unlike Physics B, C is a calculus based course.  If a student has not yet taken calculus, they must take [[AP Calculus BC]] at the same time, as it is the only course that teaches the necessary material fast enough.  For students who have not yet taken calculus, a brief crash course is offered at the beginning.

The course is taught by [[Dr. Jamal Ali]].

Note that thermodynamics and few other subjects are not covered in Physics C but are frequently covered in first-year college physics classes.  The student is either responsible to cover these on their own time or otherwise take a class in those subjects (some colleges have such a class).

'''''Note''''': It is sometimes possible to take [[AP Calculus AB]] and Physics C at the same time.  This requires special permission from the the department chairs.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AP Psychology and Research</title>
    <id>88</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97156</id>
      <timestamp>2013-07-07T22:40:30Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.21.14.74</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Tests and homework */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = AP Psychology
| department    = [[Biology and Earth Science]]
| code          = SY1X/SY2X
| teachers      = [[Ms. Marianna Reep]]
| typical_year  = [[Senior]] or [[Junior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Senior Elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Living Environment]]
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = Psychology and Life
| floor         = [[Seventh]]

}}
'''AP Psychology and Research''' is a full year social science [[Advanced Placement]] course on introductory psychology. Psychology is the study of the mind and mental processes, especially in relation to behavior. The major topics discussed throughout the course include behavior, perception, memory, cognition, intelligence, and psychological disorders, among other topics. There are only two classes, and the class is currently being taught solely by [[Ms. Marianna Reep]].

Although the [http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/bio_descriptions/sfx1.html Stuyvesant course site] states that [[Regents Living Environment]] must be taken as a prerequisite, it can be taken as a corequisite for juniors who took [[Regents Physics]] as a freshman.

==Curriculum==
The course strictly follows the sequence of chapters in the textbook: Myers' Psychology for AP. The fall term consists of the first seven to eight chapters of the textbook, which will discuss the history and definitions of psychology, the biological and evolutionary basis of behavior, the senses and perception, consciousness and the mind, learning, memory, cognition, and intelligence.

The spring term continues with the remaining chapters in the textbook, which consists of human development, motivation, emotion and health, human personality, psychological disorder and their treatments, social cognition and relationships, and social processes and culture.

==Teaching Style==
===General===
[[Ms. Marianna Reep]] is a very interactive teacher who is generally easy to get along with, and is not very strict with her grading policy. She does not solely lecture during class, and will sometimes provide interactive demonstration of a certain concept being studied then. She fully prepares all of her students for the AP exam. 

Ms. Reep's class does not have a general structure that is followed every day. However, during days in which she gives a lecture, she will usually pose a question or ask her students to perform a paper and pencil task. After explaining the answer or the purpose of the exercise, she will use an overhead projector and display her handwritten notes on the board. She will elaborate on her notes and answer any questions, then proceed to the next sheet. Ms. Reep almost never writes on the board.

===Tests and homework===
Ms. Reep will usually assign reading from the textbook to do as homework, and she occasionally asks students to outline the text or assigns questions for students to answer.

Her tests are usually all multiple-choice and generally straightforward, testing students on concepts learned in the textbook. Some of her questions may be difficult, but most of the questions are simply a test of knowledge. The test is usually around 45 to 60 questions long, yet most students will finish long before time is up, giving them ample time to check. Ms. Reep also asks that each student's final answers on the NCS form be slashed in ink (as to prevent the changing of answers after students receive their tests back.

At the end of the first term, students complete book reports on psychology books of their choice.

At the end of the year, Ms. Reep will ask her students to form into groups of the students' choice and do a presentation on a topic in psychology of the students' choice. Most groups will pair a video or a skit with a powerpoint presentation that can be anywhere from 15 minutes to the entire period. 

There are neither labs nor class trips in this course.

===Grading Policy===
NOTE: Ms. Reep never gives exact numbers for anything but the outlines.
*Participation &amp;mdash; 10%
*Homework/Outlines &amp;mdash; 10%
*Tests &amp;mdash; 60-70%
*Projects &amp;mdash; 10-20%

==AP Exam==
The AP Exam consist of two parts. The first part is multiple choice, and consists of 100 questions in 1 hour and 10 minutes (70 minutes). It accounts for 2/3 of the exam grade. The second section includes two questions, both of which has two parts. These are long answer questions that should be written in paragraphs, but does not necessarily need a introduction or conclusion, as there are only 50 minutes in this section for 2 questions and their 4 subsections. 

Though the test's lack of time may prove difficult, most Stuyvesant students are well prepared for the test, and according to Ms. Reep, almost everyone in her class who takes the exam get a 5.

==External links==
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/bio_descriptions/sfx1.html Stuyvesant course description site]
*{{Wikipedia|Advanced Placement Psychology}}
*[http://wps.ablongman.com/ab_gerrig_psychlife_17/ Companion website for textbook]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>AUYSO</title>
    <id>206</id>
    <revision>
      <id>4114</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-08T04:04:07Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SkyCL</username>
        <id>77</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Symphony Orchestra]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Symphony Orchestra]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>A Cappella</title>
    <id>204</id>
    <revision>
      <id>4108</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-08T03:54:23Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SkyCL</username>
        <id>77</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox clubpub
| name             = A Cappella
| type             = [[Clubs#Entertainment|Entertainment]]
| founded_in       = ????
| president        = Billy Yang
| vice_pres        = 
| secretary        = 
| treasurer        = 
| other_officers   = 
| teacher_advisor  = 
| size             = ????
| meeting_freq     = As announced
| meeting_day      = As announced
| meeting_room   = Room 133
| publication_freq = 
| website          = 
}}

'''A cappella''' [[Italian language|Italian]] for &quot;in the manner of the chapel&quot; music is solo or group vocal or singing without instrumental sound, or a piece intended to be performed in this way. A cappella was originally intended to differentiate between Renaissance polyphony and Baroque concertato style.  In today's a cappella, a sizable group of musically talented students serenade the student body in such manner, to bring a smile to each and every student.

==Faculty Advisors==
Please check back later.

==Composition==
Just like the chorus and choir, a cappella students are divided into a general 6 sections, based on vocal range. The following are the general vocal ranges associated with each voice type using scientific pitch notation where middle C=C4. Some singers within these voice types may be able to sing somewhat higher or lower&lt;:
* Soprano: C4 – C6
* Mezzo-soprano: A3 – A5
* Contralto: F3 – F5
* Tenor: C3 – C5
* Baritone: F2 – F4
* Bass: E2 – E4</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Advanced Algebra</title>
    <id>89</id>
    <revision>
      <id>84902</id>
      <timestamp>2011-07-17T18:55:38Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Carroll4REAB</username>
        <id>97</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Advanced Algebra
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = MM8A/MM8B
| teachers      = [[Mr. Edward Lostal]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Fourth floor|fourth]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Advanced Algebra'''

==Curriculum==

==Teaching style==
===Mr. Lostal===

====Grading policy====

==External links==</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Algebra II and Trigonometry</title>
    <id>269</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97179</id>
      <timestamp>2013-08-12T20:26:57Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>98.113.18.3</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Different teachers have different teaching styles. */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Algebra II and Trigonometry
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = MRS21, MRS22
| teachers      = [[TBA]]
| typical_year  = [[Freshman year|Freshman]] or [[Sophomore year|Sophomore]]
| terms         = Fall, Spring
| fills         = [[Senior Graduation Requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Geometry]]*
| pre/coreq_for = [[Pre-calculus]], [[Statistics]], [[AP Statistics]]
| textbooks     = [[TBA]]
| floor         = [[Third floor|Three]], [[Fourth floor|Four]]
| website       = TBA
}}

'''Algebra II and Trigonometry''' is a two-term mathematics course that is required by NYC Department of Education. This course prepares students for its own regents and covers the basics for future mathematics courses. Much of this course will seem like review for many students, but this feeling is deceptive as some teachers are aware of the abilities of certain students and make up for them with increased workloads and stricter grading policies.

Though it is mainly taken by sophomores, it is possible for a freshman with sufficient ability to take it, and in some cases a junior who is one year behind in math will also take it.

==Curriculum==
The first semester of this course will start off by covering the different sets of numbers, including but not limited to irrational and imaginary numbers. Quadratic/polynomial and systems of equations are dealt with, along with different graphs. As mentioned above, much of this will seem like review.

The second semester involves sequences and series. Also, the basic trigonometric identities are covered. They are analyzed on the unit circle. Trigonometric functions are graphed. Different laws of trigonometric identities are covered along with Pythagorean identities, and they are used to find areas of polygons. The end of the semester covers statistics and probability, but the statistics covered here are merely inferences of reference charts used on the regents.

==Teaching style==
=====Different teachers have different teaching styles.=====

===Mr. Lostal===
====Class====
Mr. Lostal employs a straightforward teaching method that allows for little interference. His motto is &quot;Hollywood Math&quot;, and occasionally he will use a physical performance to explain a concept.

Upon entering the class, students are expected to sit down quietly and start the [[Do Now]] written on the board, or whatever work given. This is when he most frequently checks homework. While he is teaching the class, students are encouraged to ask questions, though not on all instances. Two (or more) &quot;secretaries&quot; are employed from the class, and they are instructed by Mr. Lostal to give class participation points in the form of &quot;100s&quot;. They also give &quot;0s&quot; (infractions) and record homework checks. A secretary is almost completely well off when it comes to class participation.

Mr. Lostal's teaching method offers little room for change; whatever he says is law, and all problems must be done almost exactly his way. Very rarely can a student propose a better method to solve a problem.

Students are sometimes expected to work on the board. These students are most likely chosen randomly.

In many cases a class can end much after the end bell.

====Homework====
Mr. Lostal's homework is either very difficult or very easy, depending on one's perspective. The difficulty lies in the length - because he expects you to copy his steps, one problem can take up half a page. He assigns pages from his own handouts, and he gives as much as 80 questions a night. The easy part of this is that they are all regents questions and take little thinking to solve.

Mr. Lostal claims to check homework randomly, although he mostly checks those who do not perform well on tests. He checks all classes on the same days, meaning if one class is checked, all other classes will be checked too. He announces that he can check homework at any time of the period, but he mostly checks while students are working. Homework problems are put up on the board in most cases. They are candidates for the test.

====Tests====
Tests in this class are deceptively hard for some, and excessively easy for others. While all questions are regents questions from the homework, Mr. Lostal can take off many points for not following his exact method for a question. This can sometimes lead a decent math student to failure. A student who quickly catches on his patterns can easily guarantee a 100 or more on all of his tests.

All tests are out of 105-115 (mostly 110), so a student is allowed a 1 question leeway for a 100. Students who score high are expected to help those who score low.

A test is announced 1-3 weeks in advance. They can also be pushed back.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>American Studies</title>
    <id>254</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94929</id>
      <timestamp>2011-09-09T03:28:21Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>74.72.214.65</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Grading Policy */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = American Studies
| department    = English and History
| code          = H55X (AP U.S. History 1), H56X (AP U.S. History 2), E66X (AP English Language and Composition 1), E67X (AP English Language and Composition 2)
| teachers      = [[Mr. Francis]], [[Ms. Plafker]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior]]
| terms         = Both
| fills         = Humanities requirement
| pre/coreqs    = 92% average or higher in both History and English
| pre/coreq_for = 
| floor         = 
| website       =
}}

American Studies is an innovative course that combines Advanced Placement US History and AP English Language and Composition. Ms. Plafker teaches the social studies portion, and Mr. Francis teaches the English portion. The primary aim of the American Studies course is to explore the concept of an American Identity. Mr. Francis's class occupies Room ___, while Ms. Plafker's class occupies Room ___. In between the two classrooms is a collapsible wall that allows the two rooms to merge into one. Students usually attend one class and then the other, but by virtue of the collapsible wall the two classes sometimes merge and a double-period American Studies course takes place. The distinctiveness of the class helps to foster a sense of community among all American Studies students. 

=AP US History - American Studies=
==Curriculum==
AP US History - American Studies is like a typical AP United States History survey course. However, as stated before, the American Studies course explores the theme of an American identity, thus the Ms. Plafker's class has a tendency to emphasize social and cultural history. For example, pop culture is a topic that Ms. Plafker's American Studies class may explore more than Mr. Sandler's or Mr. Stern's AP US History class.

The first semester covers American history roughly up to 1900, while the second semester covers from 1900 to present-day. Ms. Plafker does a good job of finishing the curriculum on time.

Ms. Plafker is very innovative in her class lessons. She avoids lectures when possible, and emphasizes small-group discussion. A typical class period usually involves small-group discussion about a reading or a series of primary document, followed by a sharing of ideas amongst the entire class. Her classroom lessons are intended to enhance the material studied at home, not to repeat it.
Having been said, homework is an important part of her class. Like many AP US History classes across the country, topics are moved through quickly and lots of material has to be digested nightly.

==Grading Policy==
* Homework: 30%
* Exams/Quizzes: 35%
* Participation: 15%
* Term Project: 20%
Ms. Plafker intentionally de-emphasizes tests in her grading policy. She argues that she puts more emphasis on aspects of the grade that are more in the student's control, such as completing homework and participating in class. 

=AP English Language and Composition - American Studies Curriculum=
==Curriculum==
Mr. Francis offers a good survey of American literature, starting from a unit on Puritan literature up to a unit on the Transcendentalists in the fall, and continuing with a survey of 20th century American novels in the spring semester. These spring semester novels include E. L. Doctorow's ''Ragtime'', Francis Scott Fitzgerald's ''The Great Gatsby'', and Tony Kushner's ''Angels in America.
Like most English classes, Mr. Francis's class is largely discussion-based. However, it is still an AP class so it is more difficult than your typical English class. Nearly all class sessions are discussions on the previous night's reading. About three to four essays are assigned per semester, and rarely is class time given to peer edit. Mr. Francis's essay topics are creative and push you to think outside of the box, thus many times they are very difficult as well. 
==Grading Policy==
* Class work: ~35% 
* Homework: ~15%
* Grades on essays: ~50%
The class work portion of the grade for Mr. Francis's class includes attentiveness and participation in class discussions. The homework portion includes completing assigned reading and bringing in essays on time. According to Mr. Francis's syllabus, &quot;In order to receive full credit for class participation, you should participate about once per class period. A student will not receive a final grade above 88 if he or she never contributes to discussion.&quot; Students also tend to find Mr. Francis to be a harsh essay grader.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Asian-Oriental Music Promotion Organization (AMPO)</title>
    <id>250</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94481</id>
      <timestamp>2011-08-04T05:41:52Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>MishelXxCKk</username>
        <id>112</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt; [http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 organization]&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 &gt;&gt;organization&lt;&lt;]&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 organization!]&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Calculus</title>
    <id>85</id>
    <revision>
      <id>597</id>
      <timestamp>2010-01-02T05:42:05Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with ''''Calculus''' is the mathematical study of change, focusing on functions, limits, derivatives, integrals, and infinite series.  It is generally taken in the freshman year of col…'</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">'''Calculus''' is the mathematical study of change, focusing on functions, limits, derivatives, integrals, and infinite series.  It is generally taken in the freshman year of college, but at Stuyvesant, students can typically take it as early as junior year by &quot;doubling up&quot; with [[precalculus]].  They can choose from three calculus courses, depending on their skill and desire at math, and their grades.  They are listed as follows in order of increasing difficulty and depth:
*[[Calculus Applications]]
*[[AP Calculus AB]]
*[[AP Calculus BC]]
Note that with successful completion of either of the latter two and the accompanying AP exam, students can receive college credit.

After students take either of the AP Calculus courses, they may take [[Multivariate Calculus]] in the fall term of the following year, and [[Differential Equations]] in spring.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>College Decisions 2012</title>
    <id>259</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95382</id>
      <timestamp>2011-12-16T03:57:40Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SkyCL</username>
        <id>77</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[College decisions of the class of 2012]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[College decisions of the class of 2012]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>College decisions of the class of 2010</title>
    <id>124</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97189</id>
      <timestamp>2013-09-15T04:20:22Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>24.213.201.201</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Cornell University */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The following is a list of colleges and their attendees of the Class of 2010.


Abbreviations:
* 3/2 - Dual Math and Engineering Degree
* AAP - College of Architecture, Art, and Planning
* A/S - Arts and Sciences
* BA/MD - Bachelor of Arts and Doctor of Medicine
* BPE - Business and Political Economy
* BS/DO - Bachelor of Sciences and Doctor of Osteopathic Medicine
* CALS - College of Agriculture and Life Sciences
* CAS - College of Arts and Science
* CBA - College of Business Administration
* COM - Communications
* CUNY - City University of New York
* ENG - Engineering
* ERC - Eleanor Roosevelt College
* ESIA - Elliott School of International Affairs
* HE - College of Human Ecology
* ILR - Industrial and Labor Relations
* L&amp;S - College of Letters and Science
* PharmD - Doctor of Pharmacy
* PLME - Program in Liberal Medical Education
* SEAS - School of Engineering and Applied Science
* SEBS - School of Environmental and Biological Sciences
* SFS - Edmund A. Walsh School of Foreign Service
* SOM - School of Management
* SUNY - State University of New York
* WISE - Women in Science and Engineering


==Allegheny College==

* Islam &quot;Isaac&quot; Ahmed
* Christine Tadare

==American University==

* Carolyn Brill
* Kevin Lu

==Amherst College==

* Shahzad &quot;Sean&quot; Anwar
* Kimberly Bain
* Alda Chan
* Sylvia Ngo

==Bard College==

* Lazar &quot;Lawrence&quot; Bozic

==Barnard College==

* Tasmeha Chowdhury
* Tina Kuo
* June Wang
* Yuan Yuan Wang
* Jamie Yu

==Baruch College (CUNY)==

* Abraham Lin
* Eliza Cen (Honors)
* Jeremy Chan (Macaulay Honors)
* Jerry Chan (Honors)
* Anna Deng
* Kevin He (Honors)
* Doris Hu (Macaulay Honors)
* Peky Huang (Macaulay Honors)
* George Kruchin (Macaulay Honors)
* Ga Young Kwon (Macaulay Honors)
* Darren Lin (Honors)
* Fion Mak (Macaulay Honors)
* Dustin Moy (Macaulay Honors)
* Kevin Mui (Honors)
* Chong  No (Macaulay Honors)
* Raisa Shnayder (Macaulay Honors)
* Marcin Skok (Macaulay Honors)
* James &quot;Jaymz&quot; Sun (Macaulay Honors)
* Victoria Tsang (Macaulay Honors)
* Lauren Woo (Honors)
* David Zhang (Macaulay Honors)
* Shan &quot;Jason&quot; Wu (Honors)
* Litang &quot;Lawrence&quot; Yen
* David Zeng
* Michael Zhan
* Sammy Zheng

==Bates College==

* Singha Hon

==Beloit College==

* Athiththan &quot;T-H&quot; Selvendran

==Bentley University==

* Eric Chang
* Han &quot;David&quot; Li

==Binghamton University (SUNY)==

* Tousif Ahsan
* Alejandra Basaldua
* Brandon Chan
* Kenneth Chan (SOM)
* Jianpei &quot;Benjamin&quot; Cheung
* Nicholas Chew
* Kimchi &quot;Albert&quot; Cho
* Tiffany Choi (SOM)
* Michelle Dea
* Kevin Hsu
* Mingmei &quot;Maggie&quot; Huang
* Michael Huang (SOM)
* Thomas Huzij
* Alice Illioaei (SOM)
* Ruchi &quot;Rachel&quot; Jain
* Gabriel Karkenny
* Alan Kim
* Victor Kong
* Min Lee
* Ronald Leong
* Rebecca Li
* Caritta Mai
* Dina Mayzel
* Anna Menkova
* Kasun Navarathna
* Tasfia T. Nayem
* Jason Ng
* David Park
* Jennifer Reyes
* Justin Siu
* Orion Taylor
* Ernie Tsai
* Justin Wu
* Cora Yi
* Priscilla Zhao

==Boston College==

* Jaimie An
* Ellie Hou
* Rebecca Lee
* Arthur Yuen

==Boston University==

* Charles Chan
* Ruthia Chen
* Liwei &quot;Leo&quot; Cheng
* Bryant Hua
* Geraldine Lai (COM)
* Annemarie Lam
* Connie Li
* Kevin &quot;KG&quot; Liang
* Brian Lyu
* Cheyanne Sinclair
* Randal So

==Bowdoin College==

* Devika &quot;D-Dawg&quot; Gurung
* Adrienne Hanson
* Imelda Ko
* Matthew Leiwant
* Beatriz Malibiran

==Brandeis University==

* Candice Bautista
* Jenny Cheng
* Christopher Han
* Ravinder &quot;Kasun&quot; Kaler
* Justy Kosek
* Sam Liang
* Elaine Liu
* Vivian Zeng

==Brooklyn College (CUNY)==
* Kenneth Peng (Macaulay Honors)
* Wesley &quot;Wes&quot; Schierenbeck
* Kiran Sury (Macaulay Honors + BA/MD)
* Max Temnogorod (Macaulay Honors)

==Brown University==

* Steven Arroyo
* John Connuck (Connor)
* Emma Gilsanz
* Denny Kim (PLME)
* Hayward Leach
* Emily Matteson
* Rosanna Sobota
* Kamil &quot;Malik&quot; Witek
* Luyu Zhang

==Carnegie Mellon University==

* Alif &quot;Adrian&quot; Alam
* Zenon Travis Cheng
* Thomas Chu
*(Alexander) Duda
* Ronny Ho
* Max Illfelder
* Sara Li
* Carmen Lin
* Cristina Shin
* Jennifer Shin
* Marco &quot;Marcus&quot; Talabacu
* Brian Tang

==Case Western Reserve University==

* Asama &quot;Jamal&quot; Khan
* Jeremy Na
* Brandon Vu

==City College (CUNY)==

* Oark &quot;Pernell&quot; Ahmed (Sophie Davis- BS/MD)
* Cassandra Lee (Macaulay Honors)
* Michelle Newman (Sophie Davis- BS/MD)
* Moin &quot;Mitchell&quot; Sattar (Sophie Davis- BS/MD)

==Colby College==

* Bette Ha

==Colgate University==

* Dominika Burek
* Claire Littlefield

==Columbia University==

* Emily Cen (SEAS)
* Julia Chen
* Rena &quot;Rebecca&quot; Chen (where did Rebecca come from?)
* Robert Colgan
* Patrick Fu (SEAS)
* Kyle &quot;Homicide&quot; Hom (SEAS)
* Calvin Hu 
* Richard &quot;A-Wax&quot; Hue
* Yang Li
* Anna Mai (SEAS)
* Michael May
* Efthymios Philip Mixalis Xaralabos &quot;Friday&quot; Papageorgiou (SEAS)
* Shivam &quot;Stanley&quot; Pappu (SEAS)
* Boris Polyak
* Nzingha Prescod
* Bessie Rentzler
* Andrew Ryba (SEAS)
* Floyd Patrick St. Bernard-Springer
* Jacob &quot;Faggot Brain&quot; Sunshine
* Shaoxiang &quot;Shao&quot; Wang (SEAS)
* Sean Wong
* Laura Ye (SEAS)
* Chris Yeung
* Emma Ziegellaub-Eichler

==Cooper Union==

* Andrew Apollonsky (ENG)
* Nicolas Avrutin (ENG)
* Daniel Cho (ENG)
* Robert Gruener (ENG)
* John Han (ENG)
* George &quot;Zeus&quot; Holevas (ENG)
* Steven Lee (ENG)
* Miriam Lorbert (ENG)
* Jordan Perr-Sauer (ENG)

==Cornell University==
* Thomas Berg (ENG)
* Valeryan Besselyanov (A/S)
* Regina Burd (ILR)
* Ashleigh Bowie (ILR)
* Jenny Chan (A/S)
* Evan Chen (ENG)
* Jonathan Chen (ENG)
* John Cheng (A/S)
* Benjamin Diamond (A/S)
* Bin Bin &quot;Kevin&quot; Fan (A/S)
* Jiahao &quot;Jonathan&quot; Feng (ENG)
* Gary He (CALS)
* Andrew Huang (A/S)
* Michelle &quot;Sydney&quot; Huang (ILR)
* Katherine Kennedy (CALS)
* Josef Kushner (HE)
* Jack Li (ENG)
* Ke &quot;Kevin&quot; Liu (A/S)
* Steven Lau (ENG)
* Shu &quot;Kathy&quot; Lei (ENG)
* Brian Lin (CALS)
* Jie Lin (ENG)
* Andrew Lui (ENG)
* Eileen Kim (ENG)
* Matthew Miller (ENG)
* Richard Nelson-Chow (AAP)
* Toshi &quot;Timothy&quot; Noguchi (ENG)
* Kai Sam Ng (ILR)
* Kent Pan (CALS)
* Sean Patel (CALS)
* Kevin &quot;Ke&quot; Qiu (ENG)
* Alexandra &quot;Alex&quot; Sagianis (ENG)
* Gene &quot;Jean&quot; Shin (ENG)
* James Slade (AAP)
* Fedor &quot;Fred&quot; Sosin (ENG)
* Daniel Suh (HE)
* Vania Sung (ENG)
* Beiyu &quot;Latisha&quot; Tang (A/S)
* Kathy Tin (HE)
* Alex Ting (ENG)
* Winnie Tong (A/S)
* Vinny Wang (ENG)
* Emily Wine (CALS)
* Carol Wu (ENG)
* Victoria Wu (ENG)
* Robert Zhang (ENG)
* Sarah Zhao (ENG)

==Dartmouth College==

* Jenny Che
* Gavin Huang
* Curtis Lim
* David Rice
* Robin Wang
* Danny Wong
* Yifeng &quot;Anthony&quot; Zhao

==Davidson College==

* Avril Coley

==Dickinson College==

* Gabriel Deceus

==Duke University==

* Nicole Leung
* James &quot;Jim&quot; Posen
* Tony Shan

==Emory University==

* Christie Chen (Oxford)
* Yun Cho
* Sahil Goswami
* Your Mother
* Hyde Kwan

==Franklin &amp; Marshall College==

* Micah Wood

==Fordham University==

* Naadia Chowdhury
* Harrysh &quot;Harry&quot; Indranathan
* Leena Mancheril
* JinSuk &quot;Brian&quot; Woo
* Victoria Yang (CBA)
* Irene Zaman (CBA)

==Georgetown University==

* Sarah Kaplan (SFS)
* Evan Smith (SFS)

==George Washington University==

* Vincent Chou
* Katie Dease (BA/MD)
* Matthew &quot;Lunchbox&quot; DeGioia (ESIA)
* Sofiya Elyukin
* Kelly Quinn
* Kristin Singh
* Alice Zhang

==Gettysburg College==

* Shota &quot;Samuel&quot; Hasui

==Grinnell College==

* Lucy Marcus
* Brian Silberberg

==Harvard College==

* Ian Armstrong
* Junghwa &quot;Peter&quot; Cha
* Andrew Chow
* Rebecca Elliott
* Chelsea Grant
* Aviva Hakanoglu
* Sandesh &quot;Sandouche&quot; Kumar Kataria
* Marlee Melendy
* Lily Ostrer
* Mohammed Rahman
* Myhra Sadiq
* Xiaoxiao Wu
* Kenny Yu

==Harvey Mudd College==

* Spencer &quot;Spike&quot; Harris
* Ling-li &quot;Lisa&quot; Lam

==Haverford College==

* Taha &quot;Theodore&quot; Ahsin

==Hunter College (CUNY)==

* Hui Ting &quot;Jane&quot; Jiang (Macaulay Honors)
* Patrick Rozgonyi (Macaulay Honors)
* Keith-Andrew Rueca
* Yu &quot;Kevin&quot; Wang (Macaulay Honors)

==Johns Hopkins University==

* Leonard &quot;Leo&quot; Trevor Ernst
* Ali Greenberg
* Keryce Henry
* Briana Last
* Jack Margolis
* Richard Meehan
* Joseph Puma
* Yevgeniy &quot;Yevgenz&quot; Rudoy

==Kenyon College==

* Sarah Cohen-Smith
* Catherine Dwyer
* Casey Griffin

==Macalester College==

* Alejandro Perez

==Marlboro College==

* Joon Ho &quot;Paul&quot; Lee
* Jan Raphael-Cornel

==Massachusetts College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences==

* Evgeniy &quot;Eugene&quot; Chernov (PharmD)
* Jennifer Ko (PharmD)

==Massachusetts Institute of Technology==

* Seth Berg
* Jun Yan &quot;Angela&quot; Chu
* David Huang
* Marta Krason
* David Luciano
* Wacira &quot;Walter&quot; Maina
* Elizabeth &quot;Betsy&quot; Soukup
* Nilu Zhao

==McGill University==

* Sara Hassan
* Thomas Ng
* Katerina Patouri
* John Simon
* Raveen &quot;A-Wax&quot; Sugantharaj
* Vanessa Ventola

==Middlebury College==

* Andrew Fong

==Mount Holyoke College==

* Eva Lau

==New York Institute of Technology==

* Danial Khan

==New York University==

* Waqaas &quot;William&quot; Afzal (Stern)
* Ailei &quot;Albert&quot; Ai (ENG @ CAS/Poly)
* Omosefe &quot;Amanda&quot; Aiyevbomwan (Stern)
* Anastasios &quot;Tasso&quot; Kronos &quot;Oskar&quot; Bountouvas
* Philip Chan (Stern)
* Clifford &quot;The Big Red&quot; Chang
* Vinay &quot;Victor&quot; Chodha (Stern)
* Agnes Choi (Tisch)
* Abbie Chung
* Christina Dai (CAS)
* Daniel Fleishman (Stern BPE)
* Zack Goldberg (CAS)
* Ellen Halpin (ENG @ CAS/Poly)
* Jenny Hu (Stern)
* Uma Huggins
* Hyeeun &quot;Faith&quot; Jeong (CAS)
* Irvin &quot;Erwin&quot; Khaytman (Stern)
* Donna Koo (CAS)
* Kaitlyn Kwan (CAS)
* Richard Lam (Stern BPE)
* Zi &quot;Zara&quot; Lin (CAS)
* Aimee Lo (CAS)
* David Lu (Stern)
* Orpita &quot;Susan&quot; Maula (CAS)
* Tasnima &quot;Anna&quot; Mohaimin
* Loren &quot;Laura&quot; Oumarova
* Mahdi &quot;Maximillian&quot; Raza (Stern)
* Yevgeniy &quot;Eugene&quot; Sandler (Stern)
* Petros &quot;Peter&quot; (Rock) Skaliaranis
* Victoria Seto
* Brandon Sirkisoon (ENG @ CAS/Poly)
* John Sun
* Johnny Szeto (LSP)
* Syed &quot;Smith&quot; M. Tahmid (ENG @ CAS/Poly)
* Yun &quot;Janet&quot; Tang (Steinhardt)
* Alexander Van Tuyn (Stern)
* Cindy Wang (CAS)
* Lance Wong (Stern)
* Jianpei &quot;Benjamin&quot; Xie
* Annie Yang (Steinhardt)
* Billy Yang (Stern)
* ZhiMei &quot;May&quot; Yang (CAS)
* Lisa Young (Steinhardt)
* Jennifer Yue (Stern)
* Adeline Zelyony (CAS)
* Cathy Zhu (Tisch)
* Xiaofeng &quot;Frank&quot; Zhu (Stern)

==Northeastern University==

* Derrick &quot;Fungus&quot; Fung
* Billy Guo
* Soo &quot;Susan&quot; Kim
* Calvin Koo
* Sam Lau
* Jiahon &quot;Carlos&quot; Liang
* Jiajeng &quot;John&quot; Ma
* Mohammed Naim Rahim
* Zachary Stromer
* Deanna Wong

==Northwestern University==

* Andrew Cook
* Nicholas Han
* Tiffany Kim
* Danielle Oberdier (Medill)
* Shirley Xu

==Oberlin College==

* Dylan Cohen

==Occidental College==

* Drake Berglund

==Parsons The New School For Design==

* Robert Earl Vinluan

==Princeton University==

* Luc Cohen
* Jack Greisman
* Alexander Jaffe
* Kashyap &quot;Kenneth&quot; Rajagopal
* Thomas Truongchau
* Allegra &quot;Angela&quot; Wiprud

==Queens College (CUNY)==

* Owen Duffy (honors)

==Reed College==

* Audrey Augenbraum
* Nisa Beceriklisoy
* Noah &quot;The Ark&quot; Lezenby

==Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute==

* Helen Ko
* Nicholas Tantisujjatham &quot;Tornado&quot;

==Rochester Institute of Technology==

* Maciej &quot;Mac&quot; Bargiel
* Wayne Chin

==Rutgers University==

* Katrina Koon (SEBS)

==Scripps College==

* Szeyin &quot;Shelley&quot; Lee

==Seton Hall University==

* Pyotr &quot;Peter&quot; Malychev

==Skidmore College==

* Matthew Kugler

==St. John's University==

* Naveed &quot;Nelson&quot; Akter (PharmD)
* Ting &quot;Tina&quot; Chiu (PharmD)
* Nelson &quot;Naveed&quot; Chou (PharmD)
* Cindy Donald (Honors)
* Muhammad &quot;Martin&quot; Iqbal (PharmD)
* Ronald &quot;McDonald&quot; Kim (PharmD)
* Tina Kim (PharmD)
* Rebecca Kwan (PharmD)
* Clarissa Lam (Honors)
* Diana Lee (PharmD)
* Grace Lee (PharmD)
* Jenniffer Lee (PharmD)
* Yujin &quot;Eugene&quot; Moon (PharmD)
* Daniel Oh (PharmD)
* Daniel Suh (PharmD)
* Kristi Truong (PharmD)
* Victoria Wong (PharmD)
* Shang &quot;Jimmy&quot; Yang (PharmD)
* Alex Yu (PharmD)
* Leon Zhao (PharmD)

==Stanford University==

* Julia Landauer
* Annalise Lockhart

==Stony Brook University (SUNY)==

* Arthur Chan
* Michael Chen
* Olivia Cheng (WISE)
* Chris Cho
* Stephanie Chow
* Andriy &quot;Andrew&quot; Duyko (Honors)
* Kevin Hang
* Shahrier &quot;Clifton&quot; Hossain
* Farnam &quot;Prime Minister&quot; Kazi
* Lindsay &quot;Yung Humma&quot; Kwok
* Kenneth Lee
* Christine Lu
* Yong &quot;Donald&quot; Luo
* Kevin Luzong
* Lawrence Ly
* Adrienne Malaluan
* Charles Marquez
* Mark Mays
* Gleb &quot;George&quot; Nikonorov
* Bryan Nguyen
* Esteban &quot;Steven&quot; Pomboza
* Samantha Shetty (Honors)
* Igor Shtefanko
* Morgan Teeratananon
* Monika &quot;Moniqua&quot; Tuchowska (Honors)
* Shafir &quot;William&quot; Uddin
* Jeffrey Wu
* Diane Yam
* Simon Zheng

==SUNY Albany==

* Peter Li
* Daniel Navy

==SUNY Buffalo==

* Badruddoza &quot;James&quot; Khan
* Andrew Kim

==SUNY Geneseo==

* Justin Quintero
* Kevin Ho
* Jessica Ko
* Bibi Lewis
* Nicole Ly
* Rebecca Medrano
* Daniel &quot;Danny&quot; Peng
* Mateusz &quot;Matt&quot; Zukowski (3/2 at Columbia)

==SUNY Oswego==

* Megan Kale (Honors)

==SUNY New Paltz==

* Ray Min (BS/DO)
* Katherine Kennedy

==SUNY Purchase==

* Paola &quot;Paula&quot; Sokayeva

==Swarthmore College==

* Nick Gallo
* Howard Lam
* Jonghee &quot;Jennifer&quot; Quispe

==Syracuse University==

* Natasha Andaz
* Jacky Lixue
* Stephanie Shen
* Vinh &quot;Vincent&quot; Vo

==Texas Culinary Academy==

* Michael &quot;Mike&quot; Ding

==Tufts University==

* Elsa Thomas
* Ryoma &quot;Ronald&quot; Morisaki
* Emma Rosenbluth
* William Wong

==United States Air Force Academy==

* Ray Sou

==United States Military Academy==

* Ronald &quot;Ranny&quot; Choi
* Shaliya &quot;Timothy&quot; Dehipawala

==United States Naval Academy==

* Gregory Dinkel
* Joshua Lee
* James &quot;Jimmy&quot; Tse

==University of California, Berkeley==

* Alireza &quot;Waffles&quot; Mirafzal (L&amp;S)
* Sharada &quot;Krista&quot; Sridhar (L&amp;S)
* Lawrence Yen

==University of California, San Diego==

* Jeffrey &quot;Jeff&quot; Zhang (ERC)

==University of Chicago==

* Arun Abraham-Singh
* Shanniqua &quot;Shana&quot; Aguilar
* Tariqua &quot;Tara&quot; Anantharam
* Dove Barbanel
* Seferina &quot;Omosefe&quot; Berch
* Manuel Castro
* Emma Dries
* Asher Hudson
*(Robert E.) Lee Kuhn
* Pace &quot;Pedro&quot; Lee
* Marley-Vincent Lindsey
* Victor Ma
* Cassie Moy
* Alison Roberts
* Esther Schoenfeld
* Ava Woychuk-SexyMcMlinac

==University of Delaware==

* Kyla Alterman (Honors)

==University of Georgia==

* Alexander McKeever

==University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign==

* Brian Lai (ENG)

==University of Miami==

* Alberto Arias
* Feiyang &quot;Annie&quot; Zang (BS/MD)
* Christine Lam (Honors)

==University of Michigan==

* Rayna Foster
* Christine Ha
* Stephanie Jou
* Jacqueline Wu

==University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill==

* Ivy Lio

==University of Oklahoma==

* Garreth &quot;Patrick&quot; O'Brien (National Scholars)

==University of Pennsylvania==

* Shoshana Akabas
* Michael Block
* Margaret Borowczyk
* Alex Genshaft
* Amit &quot;Jacob&quot; Saha
* Zachary Weiner
* Jeffrey Roman (SEAS)
* Rosanna Sobota

==University of Pittsburgh==

* Yulong &quot;Kevin&quot; Zeng

==University of Richmond==

* Samiur &quot;Cezar&quot; Mashud
* Marina Tawfik

==University of Rochester==

* Marko &quot;Markus&quot; Oydanich
* Alexander &quot;Alex&quot; Sandler
* Kelvin Tam
* Xu &quot;Susan&quot; Yu
* Emily Zhang

==University of Southern California==

* Sara Carrion
* Martin Chen
* Garry Chien
* Jennie Lok
* Allan Lu
* Irene Ng
* Ethan Stumpf
* Cassandra Tang
* Meimei &quot;Jack&quot; Wong

==University of Texas at Austin==

* Haoran Gao
* Jaoran &quot;Jonathan&quot; Lee

==University of Virginia==

* Masudur &quot;Matthew&quot; Rahman (Echols)

==Vanderbilt University==

* Amy Lin
* Kristi Moy
* Kenneth &quot;Kenny&quot; Tan
* Kinari Sakamoto

==Vassar College==

* Carl Chen
* Kaylene George
* Kenneth &quot;Kenny&quot; Lee
* Vivian Tseng

==Villanova University==

* Stephanie Cheung
* Thomas Fabrizio
* Nashia &quot;Rebecca&quot; Kamal
* Peiyu &quot;Priscilla&quot; Lin
* Jennifer Zhu

==Wake Forest University==

* Kinari Sakamoto
* Michael Affuso

==Washington and Lee University==

* Haiying &quot;Henry&quot; Lin

==Washington University in St. Louis==

* Gabriel Hope
* Cody Levine
* Lily Pinchoff

==Wesleyan University==

* Molly Balsam
* Srotoshini &quot;Nicole&quot; Bhalobasha
* Jeremy Judelson
* Ayala &quot;Anna&quot; Mansky
* Opraha &quot;Winfrey&quot; Miles
* Mariana Quinn-Makawaia
* Jin &quot;Jean&quot; Suh

==Williams College==

* Alexandra &quot;Alex&quot; Albright
* Karina Moy
* Helen Song
* Dan Leng &quot;Danny&quot; Zhao

==Yale University==

* Stella Cao
* Clio &quot;Cassandra&quot; Contogenis
* Wenjing &quot;Jenny&quot; Dai
* Robert &quot;E&quot; Lee Hess II
* Julie Kim
* Regina Lief
* Alan Sage
* Shiyi &quot;Adeline&quot; Yeo</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>College decisions of the class of 2011</title>
    <id>190</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97328</id>
      <timestamp>2013-12-14T17:17:00Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>96.246.0.216</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The following is a list of colleges and their attendees of the Class of 2011.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Abbreviations:
* A/S - Arts and Sciences
* AAP - Architecture, Art, and Planning
* ALS - Agriculture and Life Sciences
* CAS - College of Arts and Science
* CALS - College of Agriculture and Life Sciences 
* CC - Columbia College
* CUNY - City University of New York
* ENG - Engineering
* ESIA - Elliott School of International Affairs
* HE - Human Ecology
* ILR - School of Industrial and Labor Relations
* MCS - Mellon College of Science
* Medill - Medill School of Journalism
* SEAS - School of Engineering and Applied Science
* SFS - School of Foreign Service 
* SUNY - State University of New York
* TSA - Tisch School of the Arts

&lt;br&gt;

== Allegheny College ==
*Shohad Mondol

==Amherst College==
*Nazir Khan
*Sage O'Neil
*Lawrence Yu

== Bard College ==
*Josiah Kyle-Shen
*Isaac Lapides

== Barnard College ==
*Amna Anwar
*Clare Hua
*Clarey Hung
*Tiana Stute
*Rebecca Temkin 
*Grace Zhou

== Bates College ==
*Eileen Lam
*Michael Jackson

== Bethany College ==
*William Bambury

== Boston College ==
*Ha Gyun Chung
*Lauren De Vito
*Victor Liang
*Lev Omelchenko

== Boston University ==
*Janus Chan
*Xiao Gao
*Latchmi Gopal
*Amy Guan
*Chris Hui
*Julia Kaplan
*Eugene Kim
*Leticia Kim 
*Inez Lee
*YongAn Lee
*Boey Li
*David Lin
*Lin Wen Ma
*Krzysztof Miezgiel
*Kaustabh Singh
*Lipi Thaker
*Eric Tom
*Jonathan Wong
*Queenie Yeung
*Kevin Zheng
*Matthew Zin

== Bowdoin College ==
*Libby Szuflita
*Hyemin Yi

== Brandeis University ==
*Davy Ran

== Brown University ==
*Andy Chen
*Shanna Chen
*Gabe Dorlhiac
*Catherine Gao
*Annalia Sunderland

== Bryn Mawr College ==
*Sophia Abbot
*Judy Chen
*Angie Koo
*Jessica Shum

== Bucknell University ==
*Ben Garner

== California Institute of Technology ==
*Linda Chio
*Ryeen Islam
*Sam Szuflita
*Yichi Zhang

== Carleton College ==
*Sarah Jang
*Lionel Jensen
*Zoe Levin

== Carnegie Mellon University ==
*Danica Chan (Tepper)
*Erica Chan
*Samantha Chiu
*Christopher Dabalsa (CIT)
*Laviniu Filimon (Tepper)
*Louie Gao
*Radowan Khan (H&amp;SS)
*Mahir Kothari (MCS)
*Zhuling Li (H&amp;SS)
*Rebecca Lin (MCS)
*David Lu (CIT)
*Doci Mou (CIT)
*Victoria Povolotsky (CIT)
*Lucy Qian (CIT)
*Ken Shiu (Tepper)
*Yimeng Xu (MCS)
*Jacqueline Yeung

== Claremont-McKenna ==
*Daniel Beer

== Colby College ==
*Andrew Kim
*Lillian Liang

== Colgate University ==
*Jasmine Hwang
*Michelle Sagalchik

== Columbia University ==
*Lea Beltramino (CC)
*Olivia Califano (CC)
*Stefan Garcia (CC)
*Tammuz Huberman (CC)
*Lisa Li (SEAS)
*Nafiz Mosharraf (CC)
*Jay Shim (SEAS Egleston Scholar)
*Matteo Singer (CC)
*Elizabeth Sun (CC)
*Andrei Tapai (CC)
*James Thompson (SEAS Egleston Scholar)
*Eigen Wang (CC)
*Sultan Zain (CC)

== Connecticut College ==
*William Barnes

== Cooper Union ==
*Ariel Eisenstadt (ENG)
*Austin Joa (ENG)
*Dennis Liang (ENG)
*Kelvin Lin (ENG)
*Saimon Sharif (ENG)
*William Tsui (ENG)

== Cornell University ==
*Nils Axen (AAP)
*Henry Becker (ILR)
*David Castillo (ENG)
*Susan Chen (ENG)
*Jensen Cheong (AAP)
*Megha Cherian 
*Scott Chiusano (A/S)
*Thomas Flagiello (HE)
*Vlad Fomin (HE)
*Tai Wei Guo (CALS)
*Mindy Ha (HE)
*Michael Hammer (A/S)
*Donald Hu (ENG)
*Andy Huang (ENG)
*Sarah Khalil (CALS)
*Katie Lembrikova (HE)
*Jeffrey Li (ENG)
*Ann Lu (ENG)
*Karen Paik (Hotel)
*Emma Pollack (A/S)
*Richard Quan (ENG)
*Sam Rabkin (A/S)
*Mohammad Radiyat (ENG)
*Abdullah Sayeem (ENG)
*Mark Shneerson (A/S)
*Anna Tsenter (CALS)
*Herman Wong (ENG)
*Billy Yang (HE)
*Jane Zelenko (Hotel)

== CUNY Baruch ==
*Yana Azova (Macaulay Honors)
*Angel Bao
*Megan Chiu (Macaulay Honors)
*Hannah Dhunda (Honors) 
*David Gong (Baruch Honors)
*Daniel Gorban
*Joanna Gustek (Macaulay Honors)
*James Hong (Macaulay Honors)
*Jacob Kelman 
*Devon Khan (Macaulay Honors)
*Derek Ku (Macaulay Honors)
*Linda Li
*Sweenly Liu (Baruch Honors)
*Miroslav Nemelivsky (Baruch Honors)
*Andrew Park
*Darwin Seeto (Baruch Honors)
*John Shin
*Carmen Shum (Macaulay Honors)
*Steven Teng (Baruch Honors)
*Sabiha Toni (Macaulay Honors)
*Kelvin Wu (Macaulay Honors)
*Helen Yuan (Baruch Honors)
*Darius Zhang (Macaulay Honors)

== CUNY Brooklyn ==
*Jessica Gordin 
*Mohit Kumar (BA/MD)
*Jessina Wong (Macaulay Honors)
*Allen Yevtuhkhov (Macaulay Honors)
*Mark Markov (Macaulay Honors)

== CUNY CCNY ==
*Anina Ahmad
*Nadia Hossain
*Mahtab Alam (Macaulay Honors)
*Zubair Bhuiyan (Macaulay Honors)
*Alexander David (Macaulay Honors)
*Amy Feng (Sophie-Davis)
*Shehab Hasan (Sophie Davis)
*Wilson Lai (Sophie-Davis)
*Tiffany Ma (CCNY Honors)
*Brian Sou (Sophie-Davis)
*David Sugarman (Macaulay Honors)

== CUNY Hunter ==
*Daniel Afonin (Macaulay Honors)
*Simon Ayzman (Macaulay Honors)
*Joseph Carrasco
*Sabrina Cortes
*Jacqueline Du
*Nada Elmansy (Macaulay Honors)
*Hossam Gamea 
*Pedro Gavallis
*Adehm Geller 
*Slava Gitelman
*Seong-Im Hong (Macaulay Honors)
*Andy Hsueh 
*Rita Kirzhner (Macaulay Honors)
*Jennifer Kwan
*Michael Lanci (Macaulay Honors)
*Raymond Liang (Macaulay Honors)
*Patrick Moy (Macaulay Honors)
*Kenneth Ng
*Igor Teslya (Macaulay Honors)
*Andrew Tse
*Kevin Tseng (Macaulay Honors)
*Soner Ture
*Felicia Wang
*Vincent Zhao

== CUNY Queens ==
*Abrar Rabbi

== Dartmouth College ==
*Sarah Cho
*Abbie Kouzmanoff
*Edwin Yung

== Duke University ==
*Oren Bukspan (Robertson Scholar)
*Becky Chao
*Anastasia Gazgalis
*Mao Hu
*Brendan Huang
*Rebecca Kim
*Marsha Kononenko
*Lalita Maraj
*Ashley Qian

== Eckerd College ==
*Samantha Sooknarine

== Emerson College ==
*Abie Sidell

== Emory University ==
*Raymond Fu (Oxford)
*Tony Tan
*Qiyang Zhang 

== Fashion Institute of Technology ==
*Brian Lukito

== Fordham University ==
* Farzana Spyder Ali
*Brian Chen
*Jeffrey Chin
*Tiffany Chow
*Catherine Chung
*Rob Hannan
*Mithi Hossain 
*Hui Yi Liang
*Ady Vijay

== Franklin &amp; Marshall College ==
*Jake Kaplan

== George Washington University ==
*Boris Wang (ESIA)
*Chapman Wei (BA/MD)

== Georgetown University ==
*Omika Jikaria (Walsh SFS)
*Joseph Jung
*Carolyn Lehman
*Karen Luo
*Sophia Weng

== Georgia Institute of Technology ==
*Sharif Mahfouz

== Hamilton College ==
*M.E. Ficarra

== Hampshire College ==
*Jaysa Alvarez

== Harvard College==
*Milo Beckman
*Tommy Chen
*Jao-Ke Chin-Lee
*Rosa Huang
*Joe Park
*Teresa Yan
*Faheem Zaman

== Harvey Mudd College ==
*Eric Kiss

== Haverford College ==
*Stephen Profeta
*Silvi Shameti

== Ithaca College ==
*Joanne Choi
*Jackson Li
*Yuanlin Liu

== Johns Hopkins University==
*Lindsay Bauer (BME)
*James Chen
*Laurence Goldinger
*Stephanie Hom
*Harry Ngai
*Sara Son
*Vasili Tzallas

== Johnson and Wales University==
*Ashley Milner

== Lehigh University ==
*Ariel Glassberg

== Massachusetts Institute of Technology ==
* Shilpa Agrawal
* Sarah Alkilany 
* John Bowler
* Jeffrey Castillo
* Stephanie Chen
* Jane Cotler
* Jonathan Lambert
* Kathy Lin
* Wilson Louie
* Daniel Mendelsohn
* Taylor Sutton

== McGill University ==
*Matteo Battistini
*Aiste Blaudziunas 
*Jessie Lawrence 
*Huei Lin
*Joseph Nemcock
*Paula Tsvayg

== Michigan State University ==
*Ronjini Hassan

== Middlebury College ==
*Priscilla Odinmah

== Mount Holyoke College ==
*Anitha Kandiah
*Shelley Li
*Alison Wong
*Cindy Yao
*Lu Yu

== Muhlenberg College ==
*Caitlin Eng
*Michael Kho

==New Jersey Institute of Technology==
*Ryan Cusack (AAP)

== New York University ==
*Ashish Bhandari (Stern)
*Jacques Cai (CAS)
*Katherine Chen (CAS)
*Michelle Chen (CAS)
*Antara Chowdhury (CAS)
*Olivia Chu (CAS)
*Keiji Drysdale (Stern)
*David Fulman (CAS)
*Jenny Grimberg (Stern)
*Rasheeq Haq (Stern)
*Alan Hin (Stern)
*Jackie Ho (Stern)
*Catherine Hong (CAS)
*Shatti Hoque (CAS)
*Jessica Huang (Steinhardt)
*Kevin Jin (Stern)
*Elaine Kwan (CAS) 
*Fannie Law (CAS)
*Catherine Lee (CAS)
*Gina Lee (CAS)
*Tom Lin (CAS)
*Ai Na Liu (CAS)
*Kenny Ma (CAS)
*Lorraine Ma (CAS)
*Nancy Ma (CAS)
*Victor Ma (CAS)
*Mahdi Mahmood (CAS)
*Emily Martin (Steinhardt)
*Jaimie Meyers (Steinhardt)
*Fanny Mei (LSP)
*Farihah Mridha (CAS)
*Sylvia Ou (CAS)
*Jenny Paperno (Stern)
*Kristy Paul (Steinhardt) 
*Vlad Pavlyuk (CAS)
*Jenny Qiu (CAS)
*Neveada Raventhiranathan (CAS)
*Samantha Seid (Gallatin)
*Chirag Shah (CAS)
*Jackson Sheng (Stern)
*Sharmin Sultana (CAS)
*Vivian Sze (Stern)
*Cheryl Tang (CAS)
*Shun Man Tse (CAS)
*Riho Tsuji (TSA)
*Nicholas Wolczynski (Stern)
*Tammy Wong (CAS)
*Daniel Zhang (CAS)
*Kevin Zhang
*Vivian Zhang (CAS)
*Daphne Zhen
*Kevin Zhen (CAS)
*Adam Zhou (CAS)
*Calvin Zhu (CAS)
*Ming Yang (Steinhardt)
*Kevin Zhen (CAS)

== Northeastern University ==
*Oscar Cheung (ENG)
*Fulton Hou (ENG)
*Jason Huang (ENG)
*Artem Sergeyenko
*Kevin Tan (Pharmacy)
*Brian Wan
*Alice Yoh

== Northwestern University ==
*Cory Behroozi (CAS)
*Jeffrey Bilik (CAS)
*Edward Cytryn (CAS)
*Charlie Gingold (CAS)
*Matthew Kim (CAS)
*Chris Lee (ENG)
*Charles Li (CAS)
*Clayton Li (CAS)
*Jenny Li (ENG)
*Jonathan Li
*Alexander Ng (ENG)
*Harry Poppick (ENG)
*Alexander Wong (Medill)

== NYU Polytechnic ==
*Dawei Chen
*Raymond Chu
*Elliot Cohen
*Abhimanyu Ghosh
*Mohammed Naim Rahman
*Tommy Su
*Wilson Zhang

== Oberlin College ==
*Miryam Coppersmith
*Marlena Goodman

==Ohio State University ==
*Samantha Wong
*Tony Xu

== Olin College of Engineering ==
*Melisa Lopardo

== Pennsylvania State University ==
*Sonya Som

== Pratt Institute ==
*Cristal King (AAP)
*Leevana Neemar (AAP)
*Kseniya Ostrovska (AAP)

== Princeton University ==
*Chester Dubov
*Miriam Holmes
*David Huang
*Varun Sharma
*Adam Yabroudi

== Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute ==
*Samara Ahmed
*Shanjeetha Kirupananthan
*Nancy Zhong

==Rhode Island School of Design==
*Daniela Gilsanz

== Rice University ==
*Zoe Wu
*Nicole Zhao

== Rochester Institute of Technology ==
*Winston Bui (CS)
*Stacy Chen (CS)
*Felix Handte (CS)
*Stella Lee (USP)
*Raymond Tse (CS)
*Kawah Wong

== Rutgers University ==
*Anya Krasitskaya
*Bobby Laungani (CAS)

== Sarah Lawrence College ==
* Alice Moscicki

== School of Visual Arts ==
*Swan Zhao

== Smith College ==
*Rose Moser

== Spelman College ==
*Kayla Davie

== St. John's University ==
*William Deng (Pharmacy)
*Amare Khalil
*James Kim (Pharmacy)
*John Liang (Pharmacy)
*Samantha Lee (Pharmacy)
*Stephanie Lim (Pharmacy)
*Kenny Ng (Pharmacy)
*Heather Noh (Pharmacy)
*Arooj Sharif (Pharmacy)
*Meiyi Shi
*Janice Sim (Pharmacy)
*Leon Vulis (Pharmacy)
*Zakey Zandani (Pharmacy)

== Stanford University ==
*Marveliz Santos

== SUNY Binghamton University ==
*Manfred Chan
*Wasi Ahmed
*Christina Bogdan 
*Disi Chen
*Sharon R. Cruz
*Jenny Fu
*Ricky Guan
*Ikram Hoque
*Gabriel Hwang
*Tina Ju
*Michelle Kim
*Wilson Li
*Edward Lin
*Lawrence Lin
*Peter Liu
*Brandon Luu
*Jason Pang
*Daniel Raykhlin
*Sarvar Usmanov
*Johnny Sun
*Bing Wang
*David Wang
*Eileen Wang 
*Warren Wong
*Andres Xu
*John Rong Zhang
*Bo Rong Zheng
*Stanley Zhao
*Johnny Wong
*Jonathan Zhou
*Roland Zhou

== SUNY Geneseo ==
*William Bambury
*Jennifer Chu
*Shannon Cornelius
*Jonathan Zhu

== SUNY Stony Brook University ==
*Sharmila Ahmed
*Hilton Au
*Pyee Aung
*Danna Balassyano
*Diana Belinsky 
*Gibryon Bhojraj
*Carlos Cedeño
*Stanley Chen 
*Charles Cheung
*Jimmy Cheung
*Anthony Chikva
*Danny Chin
*Amos Chiu
*Della Chu
*Karen Dai
*Vladislav Deskovitch
*Harris Dupre 
*William Huang
*Yolinda Huang
*Annie Kim
*Noori Kim
*Roy Kim
*Jane Ko
*Jennifer Kuo
*Andy Lam
*Michael Lavina
*Kenneth Lee
*Patrick Lee
*Raymond Lee
*Daniel Li
*Shirley Liang
*Bryan Hu
*Georgi Lukose
*Shrujal Parikh
*David Rances
*Lisa Ruan
*Anjan Bangladesh Saha
*Rohan Shah
*Gurdeep Singh 
*Kevin Su
*Victoria Tan
*Jonathan Tang
*Mathew Varghese 
*Amanda Weng
*Tracy Wong
*Brian Yan
*Justin Yang
*Kevin Yim
*Katherine Yiu
*Steven Young

== SUNY University at Buffalo==
*Usamah Ali Afzal
*Roman Char
*Justin Chung
*Jack Ding
*Mustafa Kamal
*Nathaniel Kheysin
*Raymond Sze
*Michael Wong

== SUNY University at Delhi ==
*Erica Liu

== Syracuse University ==
*Spencer Dong
*Michelle Hor

== Towson University ==
*Tareak Black 

== Trinity College ==
*Matthew Boccio
*Chloe Hirschowitz

== Tufts University ==
*Audrey Fleischner
*Joshua Poretz
*Elana Shapiro
*Michael Silverblatt
*Jack Zurier

== Tulane University ==
*Becca Scher 

== Union College ==
*Dena Elamrousi
*Sejal Khan
*Jakob Moran
*Agnes Park (BA/MD)

== United States Military Academy ==
*Bess Judd

== United States Naval Academy ==
*Saungwon Ko

== University of Aberdeen ==
*Konrad Wojnar

== University of California, Berkeley ==
*Peter Wysinski 
*Eric Xu

== University of California, Los Angeles ==
*George Kolyshev

== University of Chicago ==
*Sadie Bergen
*Laura Castelnuovo
*Daniel Frankel
*Maya Goldman
*Diana Hou
*Anya Krok
*Sara Lu
*Christopher Natoli
*Hannah O'Grady
*Amanda Pagul
*Jacob Pastor
*Vishal Prasad
*Shuwen Qian
*Adam Shaw
*Damian Sianakowicz
*Matthew Solomon
*Jasmine Wong

== University College London ==
*Daniel Hayeem

== University of Edinburgh ==
*Ariel Lerner
*Vainius Glinskis

== University of Massachusetts-Amherst ==
*Tiffany Lau
*Rebecca Zamdborg 

== University of Miami ==
*Casey LaMountain

== University of Michigan ==
*Aaron SungMo An
*John Chen
*Henry Liu
*Steven Louie
*Benjamin Park
*Michael Reid Jr.
*Jonathan Rim
*Sam Rim
*Xerxes Sanii
*Sean Tarmidi

== University of Notre Dame ==
*Antoinette Chan
*Wonkyu Lee
*Charles Shim (Mendoza)

== University of Pennsylvania ==
*Tobi Idowu
*Maria Torres
*Dorothy Weldon

== University of Pittsburgh ==
*Nick Heim

== University of Rochester ==
*Ming Li

== University of San Diego ==
*Emma Carleton 

== University of South Carolina ==
*Spencer Birnbaum

== University of Southern California ==
*Anna Ho
*Bryant Ly

== University of St. Andrews ==
*Tanya Verghese 

== University of Texas at Austin ==
*Luca Senise
*Samantha Unger

== University of Vermont ==
*Jackson Maslow
*Galen Stump

== University of Virginia ==
*Neil Desai
*Jinghao Yan

== Vanderbilt University ==
*Ramkumar Balasubramaniam
*August Jin Rim (CAS)

== Vassar College ==
*Lorraine Kwok
*Raymond Luu
*Alex Treitel

== Villanova University == 
*Andrew Kim
*Brian Kim
*Helen Lin
*Kevin Pang
*Jeshipio Yoon 
*Rickie Zheng

== Washington University in St. Louis ==
*Carolyn Dean Wolf (A/S)
*Alex Dong (A/S)
*Jordan Frank (ENG)
*David Levitt (A/S)
*David Shen (A/S)

== Wake Forest University ==
*Sara Shi

== Wellesley College ==
*Connie Chen
*Iris Lin
*Shirley Lu
*Jeanette Xu

== Wesleyan University ==
*Randy Arthur
*Willa Beckman
*Serena Berry
*Sam Furnival
*Elizabeth Litvitskiy
*Colin O'Connor
*Evan Schleifer-Katz
*Shourya Sen
*Samira Siddique

== Williams College ==
*Yogeeta Chatoredussy
*Sam Devine
*Denise Park
*Heidi Tan

== Yale College ==
*Lijin Chen
*Clay Gibson 
*Robert Juchnicki
*Emily Quint-Hoover
*Aia Sarycheva
*Ani Sefaj
*Vanessa Yuan</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>College decisions of the class of 2012</title>
    <id>260</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97195</id>
      <timestamp>2013-09-24T21:19:03Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>140.180.242.98</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Princeton University */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The following is a list of colleges and their attendees of the class of 2012.

{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot;
|-
! Abbreviation
! Meaning
|-
| AAP
| Architecture, Art, and Planning
|-
| BTM
| Business Technology Management
|-
| ALS
| Agriculture and Life Sciences
|-
| CAS
| College of Arts and Science
|-
| CALS
| College of Agriculture and Life Sciences
|-
| CCAS
| Columbian College of Arts and Sciences
|-
| CC
| Columbia College
|-
| CIT
| Carnegie Institute of Technology
|-
| ENG
| Engineering
|-
| HE
| Human Ecology
|-
| ILR
| School of Industrial and Labor Relations
|-
| SCS
| School of Computer Science
|-
| SEAS
| School of Engineering and Applied Science
|-
| TSA
| Tisch School of the Arts
|}

== American University ==
*Nabila Khatun
*Rebecca Ma
*Lorna Wu

==Amherst College==
*Aleksandra Burshteyn
*Krit McClean
*Kevin Mei
*Jenny Yip

==Babson College==
*Lena Wu
*Shirley Wu

==Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET)==
*Tarif Anzum


==Bard College==
*Joann Lee

==Barnard College==
*Nasrin Akter
*Elina Bystritskaya
*Jennifer Huang
*Xinni Liu
*Isabelle Ng
*Doris Xia

==Bates College==
*Jessica Plotnikov
*Gil Spivack

==Boston College==
*Catherine Choi :)

*David Kim

==Boston University==
*Jenny Kam
*Patrick Lee
*Earl Lin
*Lillian Lung
*Vijendra Ramlall
*Edwina Tam
*Jacob Tulchinskiy
*Eric Wang
*Simon Zeng

==Bowdoin College==
*Nick Brasse

==Brandeis University==
*Leah Ditmore

==Brown University==
*Graham Carling
*Mollie Forman
*Joseph Frankel
*Robert Kim
*Benjamin Koatz
*Jonathan Lessinger
*Michael Scheer

==Bucknell University==
*Patrick Bacon-Blaber
*Jack Chen

==California Institute of Technology==
*Kevin An

==Carnegie Mellon University==
*Emily Bram (SCS)
*Stephen Greco
*Jessica Guo
*Leo Jiang (CIT)
*Captain Natalie Kuang
*Donna Lee
*Benson Qiu
*Sharon Romero
*Rolando Schneiderman (SCS)
*Yelena Vayner (MCS)
*Ming Wu (HSS/Tepper)
*Hao Yang
*Keith Maverick Yeung
*Carmen Zeng
*Jamie Zhan (MCS/HSS)
*Christtia Zheng
*Maggie Li

==Carleton College==
*Lisa Qiu 

==Case Western Reserve University==
*Adhithya Baskar
*Denny Chen
*Sriharsha Jammula
*Richard Lee
*David (Fangzhou) Wang
*Kelvin Zheng

==Colgate University==
*Anastassia Bougakova (Benton Honors)
*Grace Littlefield

==Columbia University==
*Emily Atlas (CC)
*Rebecca Balaj (SEAS)
*Fedor Beloborodov (CC)
*Fayme Cai (CC)
*Phillip Godzin (SEAS)
*Alimul Islam (CC)
*Kamay Jin (CC)
*Maria van Keulen (SEAS)
*Brian Kim
*Jennifer Lam (SEAS)
*Kevin Ogunniyi (CC)
*Brady Pan (SEAS)
*Melissa Seto (CC)
*Anthony Yang (SEAS)
*Kevin Zheng

==Cooper Union==
*Jonathan Au
*Steven Chen (ENG)
*Josephine Chen (ENG)
*Hua Joe Fung (ENG)
*Reshad Hai (ENG)
*Jake Potter (ENG)
*Tiffany Tang (ENG)
*Nolana Wong (ENG)
*Harrison Zhao (ENG)

==Cornell University==
*Alice Anichkin (ILR)
*Manisha Basak (ENG)
*Justyna Bujno (ENG)
*Annie Chau (ENG)
*Samuel Chen (ENG)
*Shuo Cheng (AAP)
*David Cho (CAS)
*Madhurima Chowdhury (CAS)
*Pooja Desai (HE)
*Katharina Fung (ENG)
*Ashini Ganesalingam (CALS)
*Evan Gao (CALS)
*Joanna MOmaFuckin Awesome Gao (HE)
*Lili Gehorsam (ENG)
*Min Hui Guan (CAS)
*Margot Haas (ENG)
*Emily Hon (CALS)
*Richard Hsu (ENG)
*Sophie Huang (ENG)
*Michael Ko (ENG)
*Jessica Lee (ENG)
*Catherine Leung (HE)
*Samantha Levine (HE)
*Emma Lichtenstein (CALS)
*Danny Lin (CAS)
*Yilun Ma (CAS)
*Ivaylo Madzharov (CAS)
*Adam Matrab (ENG)
*Ziquan Miao (ENG)
*So Yeon (Jennifer) Pak (HE)
*Levi Patish (ENG)
*Shelley Poon (ENG)
*Michael Ren (ENG)
*Sami Sakizlioglu (AAP)
*Elie Shvidky  (CALS)
*Ning Wang (ENG)
*Fukang Wen (ENG)
*Anita Wu (ENG)
*Cindy Wu (ENG)
*Cheng Xing (ENG)
*Helen Yeung (CAS)
*Rene Zhang (ENG)
*Victor Zhao (CALS)
*Linda Zheng (ENG)
*Bobby Zhou (ENG)

==Culinary Institute of America==
*Jim Nguy

==CUNY Baruch==
*Sanjit Gill (Honors)
*Arthur Rentzler (Honors)
*John Thompson (Honors)

==CUNY City College of New York==
*Simon Gurvets (Macaulay Honors)
* Noshin Haque (Macaulay Honors)
*Anika Islam (Honors)
*Sangmee Kim (Sophie Davis BS-DDS)
*Kirtan Chauhan (Sophie Davis BS/MD)
*Choonghun Lee (Macaulay Honors)
*Eitan Pearl (Macaulay Honors)

==CUNY Hunter==
*Andzelika Dechnik (Macaulay Honors)
*Mitchell Domovsky
*Izzy Hechkoff
*Ravtej Kohli
*Yevgeniy Liverant (Macaulay Honors)
*Stephen Livshits
*Sarah Soo-Hoo (Macaulay Honors)
*Kevin Tang (Macaulay Honors)
*Hannah Whalen (Macaulay Honors)

==Dartmouth College==
*Tangent Cheng
*Kristina Mani
*Cecelia Shao
*Tiffany Wang
*Mick Zloof

==Duke University==
*Diana Lam
*Janan Zhu
*Cheng Ma

==Drexel University==
*Young Jae Lee

==Emory University==
*Jessie Cai (Oxford College)
*Kelly Kwan
*Reema Panjwani
*Anika Rastgir
*Alec Schaw

==Fordham University==
*Raisa Ahmed
*Allie Burns (Honors)
*Sharon Izrailov
*Jonathan Leung
*Eva Li
*David Plitt
*Zulkarium Rahman
*Mohammed Summon
*Brian Tong
*Vani Upadhyaya

==Franklin and Marshall College==
*Betty Chen

==Georgetown University==
*Claudia Chau
*Eric Han
*Anna Mastryukova 
*Jimmy Seo
*Tong Wan
*Catherine Yin

==George Washington University==
*Emily Chan (BA/MD)
*Melissa Chan (BA/MD)
*Howard Chen
*Leah Chevan (CCAS)
*Kevin Choi
*Jie Wen (Jasmine) Huang
*Sara Schaeffer

==Georgia Institute of Technology==
*Kevin Kotharu
*Christine Yee

==Harvard College==
*Nick Chavez
*Edward Cho
*Nader Daoud
*Angela Fan
*Jenny Fung
*Alex Ge
*Emmy Hu
*Margaret Kostova
*Batsheva Moriarty
*Irma Nomani
*Charlotte Ruby
*Daniel Solomon
*Konrad Surkont
*George Wu
*Mimi Yen

==Harvey Mudd College==
*Robert Bennett
*Jim Wu

==Hamilton College==
*Katie Bor
*Holly Chen
*Jessica Tang
*Wenlu Weng
*Erick Wong

==Ithaca College==
*Jay Jiang

==Johns Hopkins University==
*Kimberly Iboy
*Rebecca Jing 
*Christopher Jou
*Aarthi Kuppannan
*Eric Li
*Bill Ling
*Ching Xie
*Kevin Zhang
*Victoria Zhao

==Marist College==
*Stanley Yang

==Massachusetts Institute of Technology==
* Angel Carvajal
* Genghis Chau
* Blake Elias
* Vicky Gong
* Will Haack
* Wei-En Lee
* Vinay Mayar
* Kevin Peng
* Judy Pu
* Nick Rivera
* Mikhail Rudoy

== McGill ==
*Jack Harney
*Michael Hubbs
*Tong Niu
*Sofia Pidzyrailo
*Polina Rozina
*Joe Steele

==Middlebury College==
*Eliezer Hanft
*Debanjan Roychoudhury

==Mount Holyoke College==
*Emma Hoffman

==New York University==
*Odreka Ahmed 
*Lewis Byun (Stern)
*Shan Chan (Stern)
*Lucas Chen(Poly)
*Patricia Cheng 
*Albert Cheu (Poly-CS Honors)
*Captain Joseph Cheung
*Cory Dean Chung (Steinhardt)
*Jeremy Cohen
*Yuchen Dong
*Francesco Ferran
*Shady Gabal
*David Hu (Poly-CS)
*Lillian Hua
*Shengjie Ji
*Bumsoo Kim (Dual Degree in CAS/Poly)
*Jucky Kittyburger
*Eli Lavett (TSA)
*Christina Leong (CAS)
*Amy Li (Stern)
*Wendy Li
*Jonathan Kwok (Poly-BTM Honors)
*Victor Xin Ma (Stern)
*Jacky Ng
*Andreas Petrossiants
*Andrew Qiao (Stern)
*Syed Zakaria (CAS)
*Nelson Qu (CAS)

*Ana Slade (TSA)
*Kenny Tan(Poly)
*Tatiana Ting
*Billy Tsuda
*Jessica Wang
*Yinyin Wu
*Aolei Xu
*Farzana Yeasmin
*Maggie Yeung
*David Zheng (CAS)
*George Lin (Poly-CS)

==Northeastern University==
*Alex Chao
*Jason Chen
*Calvin Chong
*Brittany Chu (honors)
*Wendy Chu (University Scholar)
*Kevin Li
*Lucian Li
*Kris Lulaj
*Tina Su
*R. Lichi Chan

==Northwestern University==
*Ian Chan
*Donald Ho
*Dennis Kan
*Kirra Silver
*Chang Tang

==Oberlin College==
*Idalia Bamert
*Eva Fineberg
*Eli Rosenberg

==Occidental College==
*Mohammed Hoque

==Olin College==
*Abe Levitan

==Pomona College==
*Danny Swift

==Pratt Institute==
*Mindy Lam

==Princeton University==
*Noam Altman-Kurosaki
*Megan Harewood
*En-Wei Hu-Van Wright
*Jamie Oliver
*Loullyana Saney
*Devon Varrichione
*Jeffrey Yan
*Meisze Yau
*Debbie Yun

==Reed College==
*Emma Handte
*Lilja Walter

==Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute==
*Kevin Ng
*David Wong

==Rice University==
*Jun Xin Chen
*Xin Huang

==RIT==
*Xiau Ya (Amy) Huang
*Rumman Jafar
*Lily Chen

==Skidmore College==
*Madeleine Emerick

==Smith College==
*Claire Adams
*Karen Chau

==Stanford University==
*Stacy Chun
*Jeremy Majerovitz
*Nicholas Ryba
*Mark Schramm

==St. John's University==
* Muktasid Alam (Pharmacy)
* Irfan Hoque (Pharmacy)
* Lois Huang (Pharmacy)
* Mina Pavlova 
* Lucy Wei
* Jordan Yan (Management)

==SUNY-Binghamton==
*Rafita Ahlam (CAS)
*Gianluca Balestra
*Jahmar Campbell
*Cyndi Chin
*Frankie Choi
*Gilad Eisenberg
*Nick Fasano
*Jacky Feng
*Zoe Goldstein
*Ten-Young Guh (ENG)
*Shelby Hochberg
*Joey Hawthorne
*Rudy Kuang
*Jacinda Lee
*Alex Li
*Ricky Li
*Eric Liang
*Lytton Liao
*Nicole Radova
*Hamilton Sands
*Brian Walsh
*Sammy Wu

==SUNY-Stony Brook==
*Miraj Alam
*Alper Donmez
*Leon Pan
*Vasia Patov
*Videsh Persad
*Abraham Rabinowitz (CS Honors/Scholars)
*Safa Sattar (Honors)

==Swarthmore College==
*Kathleen Escoto
*Teo Gelles
*Ian Grant
*Ashley McQuiller

==Tufts University==
*Quinn Hood
*Noah Kagan

==University of California, Santa Barbara==
*Dripto Debroy (CCS)

==University of Chicago==
*Jake Araujo-Simon
*Donna Chen
*Patrick Chen
*Sho Zren Chen
*Sophia Chen
*James Cheung
*Brenden Collins
*Andrew Eckholm
*Renata Horowitz
*Joyce Huang
*Sofia Huang
*Yorkbell Jaramillo
*Andrew Kang
*Jong Lee
*Samuel Levine
*Yiru Luo
*Ariel Matalon
*Tasnim Rahman
*Tyler Ross
*Swara Saraiya
*Sam Saskin
*Andrew Scasny
*Melissa Watt
*Grant Weisberg

==University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign)==
*Austin Buschmann (ENG)
*William Francis Knight IV
*James Lang (ENG)
*Max Wang (ENG)
*Kelsey Yuen (ENG)

==University of Miami==
*Jake Sidransky

==University of Michigan==
*Eric Chen
*Mei Ki Cheung
*Syed Ferdous
*Andy Kim
*Ricky Kim
*Nancy Sun
*Tommy Tang
*Loren Weiss
*Winston Zou
*Kevin Yu

==University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill==
*Briana Byron

==University of Notre Dame==
*Rachael Biscocho
*Shirley Chen
*Janice Chung
*Lucy Du
*Glory Kim
*Wei Lin
*Jenny Shan
*Jessica Wang
*Margaret Zhao

==University of Pennsylvania==
*Charles Bagley (Huntsman Program)
*James Frier
*Doron Shapiro (SEAS)
*Yichen (Ethan) Shou (SEAS)
*Alex Wang (CAS)

==University of Pittsburgh==
*Phillip Gornstein (CAS)
*Jackie Wong

==University of Southern California==
*Jia Wei Chen (Marshall)
*Max Lavicka
*Jason Lee (Marshall)

==University of Texas at Austin==
*Paul Khermouch
*Josiah Thomas Mercer

==University of Virginia==
*Joseph Khubelashvili
*Jake Kozloski
*John Mennell (SEAS)

==Vanderbilt University==
*Karen Chan
*Liza Gribkova
*Viktoria Hallikäär
*Andrew Mah
*Gerald Nelson
*Felicia Rutberg
*Chris Su

==Vassar College==
*Jackie Krass

==Villanova University==
*Randy Chen
*Shirley Cheng
*Constantine Kostikas
*Kristin Lam
*Kevin Lin
*Adley Mai
*Sunny Wu

==Washington University in St. Louis==
*Connie Lu (CAS)
*Michael Madans (CAS)
*Dennis Rim (CAS)
*Elias Weinraub

==Wellesley College==
*Bernice Chan
*Jong Lee
*Vivian Ng
*Julie Rong
*Teresa Tai
*Claudia Yau

==Wesleyan University==
*Jules Berman
*Adriana Brau-Diaz
*Connor Justice
*Neil Maheshwari

==Williams College==
*Libby Dvir
*Cleo Nevakivi-Callanan

==Yale University==
*Maya Averbuch
*Alex Carrillo
*Wasif Islam
*Rudi-Ann Miller
*Jenny Nguyen
*Emma Tipton
*Patrick Yong
*Karen Zheng</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>College decisions of the class of 2013</title>
    <id>265</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97385</id>
      <timestamp>2013-12-16T22:15:59Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>68.173.135.167</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Williams College */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The following is a list of colleges and their attendees of the Class of 2013.  Please do not list someone else's name without his/her permission first.
Names are listed in alphabetical order.
&lt;br&gt;
{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot;
|-
! Abbreviation
! Meaning
|-
| AAP
| Architecture, Art, and Planning
|-
| BTM
| Business Technology Management
|-
| ALS
| Agriculture and Life Sciences
|-
| CAS
| College of Arts and Science
|-
| CALS
| College of Agriculture and Life Sciences
|-
| CCAS
| Columbian College of Arts and Sciences
|-
| CC
| Columbia College
|-
| CIT
| Carnegie Institute of Technology
|-
| ENG
| Engineering
|-
| GSOE
| Grove School of Engineering
|-
| HE
| Human Ecology
|-
| ILR
| School of Industrial and Labor Relations
|-
| SCS
| School of Computer Science
|-
| SDVA
| School of Design and Visual Art
|-
| SFPC
| San Francisco Penguin Club
|-
| SEAS
| School of Engineering and Applied Science
|-
| TSA
| Tisch School of the Arts
|}

&lt;br&gt;

==American University==
*Christine Kowlessar
*Connie Wu

==Amherst College==
*Matthew Choi
*Aleks Merkovich

==Bard College==
* Jeremy Kaplitt

==Barnard College==
* Olivia Balderes
* Jacqueline Chou
* Sabrina Khan
* Natalie Kozlova (3-2 program with SEAS)
* Elissa Li
* Victoria Stempel (Double Degree with the Jewish Theological Seminary)

==Bentley University==
* Santiago Torres

==Boston College==
* Nazifa Subah

==Boston University==
* Ashley Ramsawak
* Zambeta Tsapos

==Bowdoin College==
* Danielle Freeman

==Brandeis University==
* Christine Kim

==Brown University ==
* Muki Barkan
* Pranavan Chanthrakumar (PLME)
* Sunghee Han
* Lisa Lee
* Julia Stemmer
* Eric Xiao
* Raymond Zeng

==Bucknell University==
* Danbee Kim

==California Institute of the Arts==
* Katherine Chi (Character Animation)

==California Institute of Technology==
* Zofii Kaczmarek

==Carleton College ==
* Evie Rosenberg

==Carnegie Mellon University==
* Nathaniel Biggs (SCS)
* Brian Chen
* Yan Lin Chen
* Lillian Cho
* Christopher Chong (CIT)
* William Christerson
* Sarah Duncan
* Elizabeth Ji (SCS)
* Matthew Jin
* David Lu (SCS+Math Double Major)
* Rinko Maeshima (CIT)
* Saru Nanda
* Tiffany Phan
* Melanie Seah

==Case Western Reserve University ==
* Helen Ko
* Timothy Lee
* Matt Moy
* Lulin Peng
* Raeesa Hossain
* Magle Shi

==Colby College==
* Matt Hoffman
* Jun Sheng (Jenny) Lin

==Colgate University==
* Carlen Zhu

==College of William and Mary==
* Russel Skinner
* Patrick So

==Columbia University ==
* Erica Chan (CC)
* Jill Chow (CC)
* Claire Hripcsak (CC)
* Anna Juchnicki (SEAS)
* Derek Li (CC)
* Miranda Li (CC) 
* Adam Lieber (CC)
* Mengdi Lin (SEAS)
* Jenny Lotova (CC)
* Ava Myint (CC)
* Catalina Piccato (CC)
* Kori Porosnicu-Rodriguez (CC)
* Kaveri Sengupta (CC)
* Wilson Stamm (CC)
* Eugénie Thompson (Dual Degree with Sciences Po)
* Alfred Tsai (CC)
* Georgiana Yang (SEAS)
* Alison Xu (CC)

==Cooper Union ==
* Alexander Bu (CE)
* Eric Cerny (ME)
* Johnny Chen (ME)
* Aaron Chong (ChE)
* Adam O'Connor Jamia (EE)
* Ronnie Kabbani (CE)
* Minhyeong Kim (EE)
* Victor Lei (EE)
* Sinian Ma (CE)
* Jeffrey Shih (EE)
* Jaeryung (John) Song (EE)
* Romaniya Voloshchuk (ME)
* William Yu (EE)
* Tony Zhao (ME)

== Cornell University==
* Stephanie Bak (ENG)
* Kelsey Bernal (ILR)
* Mona Chen (ENG)
* Shuo Chen (CALS)
* Ying Xuan Chen (ENG)
* Sharon Chiu (ENG)
* James Chu (ENG)
* George Ding (ENG)
* Annie Fan (CAS)
* Windy Feng (ENG)
* Kayla Halvey (CALS)
* Hon Wei Khor (ENG)
* Raymond Lau (ENG)
* Crystal Lee (HE)
* Kelly Lee (HE) 
* Lily Lin (CAS)
* Geyanne Lui (ENG)
* Mauricio Moreyra (ENG)
* Sasson Rafailov (AAP)
* Phylicia Rodriguez
* Daryl Sew (ENG)
* Olivia So (AAP)
* Benjamin Sung (ENG)
* Kevin Wan
* Willie Xu (ENG)
* Jenny Yin
* Batya Zamansky (CAS)
* Zachary Zimmerman (ENG)
* Kai Feng Zhang (ENG)

==CUNY Baruch==
* Nishat M. Chowdhury
* Bena Huang
* Raymond Huang (Macaulay Honors)
* Stella Kong (Macaulay Honors)
* Kihun Kwon
* Kevin Lam
* Kyle Lan
* Christina Law
* Wendy Li (Macaulay Honors)
* Charles J. Liu 
* Jeffrey Mui
* Sanam Rahman
* Loriann Szeto
* Julian Tsang (Macaulay Honors)
* Amy You (Macaulay Honors)

==CUNY Borough of Manhattan Community College==
* Nicholas Bueta
* Timothy Wang

==CUNY Brooklyn==
* Tasnia Mahmud (BA/MD + Macaulay Honors)
* Lisa Ng (Macaulay Honors)

==CUNY City College of New York==
* Maxwell Berkow (Macaulay Honors)
* Henry Chen (Sophie Davis BS/MD)
* Erica D'Ippolito
* David Matsibekker (Sophie Davis BS/MD)
* Yejoon Seo (Macaulay Honors ENG)
* Les Wong (Macaulay Honors)

==CUNY Hunter==
* Norine Chan (Macaulay Honors College)
* Keo Chau (Macaulay Honors College)
* Nabanita Hossain (Macaulay Honors College)
* Rachel Kim
* Erica Kwong (Macaulay Honors College) 
* Heloise Lanoix
* Linda Luu (Macaulay Honors)
* Sreshta Paranji (Macaulay Honors College)
* Dipu Rahman
* Stephanie Yakoubovitch (Macaulay Honors College)

==Dartmouth College ==
* Sharon Cho
* Jane Handorff
* Hayden Karp-Hecker
* Lotanna Ezenwa

==Das It Mane State==
* Justin Robinson (ENG)

==Duke University==
* Isabelle &quot;Izzi&quot; Clark
* Maggie Wu
* Carolyn Yao (ENG)

==Emory University==
* Saiganesh Ravikumar (CAS)

==Fordham University==
* Soulin Haque
* Arnchie Qu

==Gap Year==
* Nina Peterson

==George Washington University==
* Annarose (AJ) Jacob (SMPA)
* Julia Magliozzo (CCAS)
* Isabelle Mahnke (CCAS)

==Georgetown University==
* Ezra Louvis (CAS)
* Aniqa Tahsin (CAS) 

==Goucher College==
* Alix Comeau

==Grinnell College==
* Bebe LeGardeur

==Hamilton College==
* Hazel Chan
* Irene Lin
* Jean Shim

==Hampshire College==
* Jeffrey Kuhn

==Harvard University==
* Tasnim Ahmed
* Amanda Boss
* Emma Frucht
* Gabriel (Gabe) Hurwitz
* Amanpreet Kandola 
* Nancy Ko
* Max Liebeskind
* Alison Reed
* Jamie Lee Solimano
* Jack Stevenson
* Kenneth Wang
* Mei Yin Wu

==Harvey Mudd College==

==Haverford College==
* Meg Palmer
* Demian Yoon

==Johns Hopkins University ==
* Tiffany Chan
* Nancy Chen
* Daryl Chin
* Cihang Gu
* Nadya Kronis
* Christine Lee
* Tyler Lee
* Miles McKey
* Elana Movshovich
* Ivana Su
* Kineta Wahl

==Lehigh University==
* Casey Ching

==Macalester College==
* Nihan Gencerliler
* Ben Huber
* Lucy Woychuk-Mlinac

==Marietta College==
* Karl Ni (Honors, Petroleum Engineering)

==Massachusetts Institute of Technology==
* Dina Lévy-Lambert
* Denis Li
* Jon Lu
* Helen Nie
* Irina Titova
* Richard Yip (Class of 2014)
* Joanna Zhu

==McGill University==
* Isaac Fiore
* Florence Gafanovich
* Lori Gutman
* Lavinia Lee
* Elizabeth Levitis
* Haymar Lim
* Everett Ross
* Clarissa Sorenson
* Elton Sun
* Victor Yu
* Rachel Zaurov
* Michael (Huai) Zhang

==Mount Holyoke College==
* Patricia Nguyen
* Sarah Robinson
* Selena Zhou

==New York University==
* Marcus Barahal (Tisch)
* Shuling Chan
* Yee Gee Cheng (Nursing)
* Bryan Echeverry
* Michael Frenkel (Stern)
* Mohan Hasan
* Jason Huang (Poly)
* Michael Ioudovitch (Poly)
* Gina Jung
* Moon Khan
* Evelyn Kim
* Sarah Kim
* Adithya Kumar (Stern)
* Jimmy Lee
* Roger Lee (Tisch)
* Aric Li (Stern)
* Wyman Li (Stern)
* Adam Liang
* Emily Liang
* Jeanney Liu (Stern)
* Bo Lu
* Sabid Manick
* David Mui (CAS Honors)
* Amy Ng 
* Lora Oh
* Vinit Shah (Stern)
* Ying Yu Situ (Gallatin)
* Dexter Tong (CAS)
* Samuel Vasilevskiy (Poly)
* Kevin Won
* Alex Wong
* Jiali Wu
* Carter Yu

==Northeastern University==
* Sarah Babski (Honors)
* Howard Cheung
* Bobo Chiu
* Nicholas Fung
* Tracey Lum (Honors)
* Christine Luong (Honors)
* Katie Mullaney (Honors)
* Cody Tong (Honors) 
* Justin Wong
* William Huang

==Northwestern University==
* Jenny Chen
* Susan Chen 
* Gabrielle Gillow
* David Jiang
* Calvin Ng
* Fei Wang

==Oberlin College==
* Joshua Bogatin
* Olivia Fountain
* Rachel Heineman
* Rachel Katz
* Aliya Tuzhilin
* Isabella Zelichenko

==Pomona College==
* Ellie Abrams
* Derrick Choe
* Evan Schechter

==Princeton University==
* Daniel Teehan
* Nina Wade
* Margot Yale
* Mark Zhang

==Reed College==
* Sydney LaStella

==Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute==
* Edwin Chen
* Alisa Emag
* Felix Fan
* Eric Lam
* Vivian Lin
* Ivan Smirnov
* Adam Sean Teyer
* Anna Wong
* Allen Wu

==Rice University==
* Victoria Yuan (ENG)

==Rochester Institute of Technology==
* Mark Philip
* Brendan Toyoshima
* Logan Yu (3D Digital Graphics)

==Rutgers University==
*Kimberly Yu (Pharmacy)

==Sarah Lawrence College==
* Emma Lesser

==Smith College==
* Teresa Huang

==Stanford University==
* Adam Schorin
* Jordan Wallach

==St. John's University==
* Karen Chen (Pharmacy)
* Kevin Chen (Pharmacy/Honors)
* Benjamin DeGioia (Actuarial Science/Honors)
* Mark Gelfand (Pharmacy)
* Jialin Hu (Actuarial Science) 
* Steven Stettner
* Phillip Wong
* Elliot Ziskin (Pharmacy)

==SUNY-Binghamton==

* Ryan El Naggar
* Daelin Fischman
* Allison Geismar
* Victor Li
* Amy Liang
* Moses Lin
* Tracy Liu
* Nicole Murphy
* Denis Plotkin
* David Rabinovich
* Zuzanna Rybicka
* Vicki Wen
* Anita Wong
* Andrew Wu
* Stacy Xie
* Chris Yoon
* Andrew Yu

==SUNY-Buffalo==
* Danish James
* Antara Majumdar (Honors)

==SUNY-New Paltz==
* Yein Kim

==SUNY-Stony Brook==
* Jonathan Tangent Chu
* Deepannita Das
* Menna Elaskandrany
* Dan Harel
* Jahwa Hossain
* Esther Luo
* Sam McKay
* Jacqualine (Jackie) Ng
* Liana Penny
* Debduth Pijush
* Horia (Lee) Popa
* Rabia Rashid
* Judy Tam
* Rachel Wong
* Ahsan Qureshi
* Josephine Pho
* Yimin Wang

==Swarthmore College==
* James Wallace-Lee

==Syracuse University==
* Mallory Miller
* Calvin He

==Tufts University==
*Bernard (Bernie) Birnbaum
*David Kheyman (ENG)

==Tulane University==

==University of California, Berkeley==
* Jacob Soiffer
* Jingwei (Jason) Tu (EECS) 
* Myra Xiong

==University of California, Los Angeles==

==University of Chicago ==
* Marta Bakula
* Peter Becht
* Hannah Brodheim
* Niki Chen
* Neeta D'Souza
* David Flomenbaum
* Xanthe Gallate
* Arielle Gerber
* Benno Giammarinaro
* Emmalina Glinskis
* Jack Haggerty
* Noah Hellermann
* Samantha Hom
* Carolyn Kang
* James Kogan
* Alen Makhmudov
* Eliza Mitnick 
* Kevin Moy
* Harry O'Neil
* Joaquin Pinto
* Emily Polner
* Andrew Nicotra Reilly
* Aminah Sallam
* Yixuan Song
* Edith Villavicencio
* Sofia Wyetzner
* Kenneth Zheng

==University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign==
* Curtis Bezault (ENG)
* Ying Chen (ENG)
* Junze He (ENG)
* Stacy Lee (ENG)
* Joshua Rhee (ENG)
* Kevin Wang (ENG)

==University of Miami ==
* Elska Kaczmarek
* Azra Tanovic

==University of Michigan ==
* Victoria Chen
* Jiaru Liang (ENG)
* Leon Liang
* Ari Nadrich
* Kristina Pan
* Wallace Wang
* Greeny Wong
* Annie Xu
* Jason Ye
* Phoebe Young
* Jennifer Zhou

==University of Notre Dame ==
* Ellen Chen
* Elizabeth Huang
* Julia Kim
* Christine Park
* Marta Poplawski

==University of Pennsylvania ==
* Joyce Lee (Computer and Cognitive Science Dual Degree)
* Sophie Pan (CAS)
* Kevin Park (Wharton)
* Dia Sotiropoulou (CAS)

==University of Richmond==
* Sandy Yu

==University of Rochester==
* Matthew Hochberg
* Audrey McCarthy
* Rosa Park
* Annie Zhang

==University of Southern California ==
* Asa Conover
* Sara Krevoy

==University of Texas at Austin==
* Al Gilardi
* George Kaiser

==University of Vermont==
* Danny Funaro

==University of Virginia==
* Remy Moorhead (AAP)
* Leopold Spohngellert (CAS)

==Vanderbilt University==
* Alex Argyriou
* Danielle Dai (Peabody)
* James Decker
* Zitong Huan
* Sam Lijin
* Benjamin Raja
* Win Wang

==Vassar College==
* Dan Fu Ruan

==Villanova University==
* Timothy Fong
* Shan Shi

==Washington University in St. Louis==
* Brianna Gordon 
* Miranda Kalish (SDVA)
* Brian Lam (SEAS)
* Michelle Yuan
* Ben Zang

==Wellesley College==
* Sarah Min
* Rafa Tasneem
* Alice Xu
* Anita Yau

==Wesleyan University==
* Josh Bloom
* Timmy Levin
* Michael Sheldon
* Gabriel Sunshine

==Williams College ==
* Ian Outhwaite
* Aglaia Ho

==Yale University ==
* David Kurkovskiy
* Tony Scott
* Bernard Stanford
* Alicia Vargas-Morawetz
* Ivy Wanta</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Colleges of class of 2010</title>
    <id>123</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1074</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-21T03:37:12Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>redirect to Colleges of the class of 2010</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Colleges of the class of 2010]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Colleges of the class of 2010</title>
    <id>188</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95047</id>
      <timestamp>2011-09-14T22:30:55Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Christmp</username>
        <id>76</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>oops typo</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[College decisions of the class of 2010]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Department schedules</title>
    <id>202</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3903</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-03T00:40:05Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Christmp</username>
        <id>76</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">'''Department schedules''' are tables containing the periods when and rooms where teachers of a certain department have class.  Pictures of department schedules are listed below.

''Note that the physics, chemistry, art/tech, and physical education departments have not yet posted their schedules.  We will get them to you as soon as we can.''

[[File:Department schedule biology spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|Biology]]

&lt;!--[[File:Department schedule chemistry spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|Chemistry]]--&gt;

[[File:Department schedule English spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|English (it is indeed the spring schedule, even though the title of the table says otherwise)]]

&lt;!--[[File:Department schedule health and physical education spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|Health and Physical Education]]--&gt;

[[File:Department schedule mathematics spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|Mathematics]]

&lt;!--[[File:Department schedule physics spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|Physics]]--&gt;

[[File:Department schedule social studies spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|Social Studies]]

[[File:Department schedule world languages spring 2011.JPG|700px|thumb|left|World Languages]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Digi Photo</title>
    <id>98</id>
    <revision>
      <id>755</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-02T04:36:32Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>646513109</username>
        <id>11</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Digital Photography]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Digital Photography]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Digiphoto</title>
    <id>97</id>
    <revision>
      <id>754</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-02T04:35:19Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>646513109</username>
        <id>11</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Digital Photography]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Digital Photography]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Early American Literature</title>
    <id>92</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97164</id>
      <timestamp>2013-08-12T16:56:31Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>69.203.218.132</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Mr. Shawn Gerety */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Early American Literature
| department    = English
| code          = E5EA
| teachers      = [[Ms. Jennie Chan]], [[Mr. Shawn Gerety]], [[Mr. Eric Grossman]], [[Mr. John La Bonne]], [[Mr. Philip Mott]], [[Ms. Holly Weiss]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]]
| terms         = Fall
| fills         = Junior English Requirement
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Sixth floor|Sixth]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Early American Literature''' is a half year, single period course.

==Curriculum==


==Teaching Style==
==Ms. Jennie Chan==
[[Ms. Jennie Chan]] is a relatively lax English teacher, however having her as a teacher truly allows you to appreciate the works studied in Early American Literature. Throughout her course, only two works are studied: Hawthorne's ''The Scarlet Letter'' and Twain's ''Adventures of Huckleberry Finn''. In the beginning, we read a selection of poetry and Hawthorne's short stories as an introduction to the course. Her insightful, highly analytical class discussions is what makes her class unique. Group work and independent writing are also notable features.
Her thought provoking projects are another notable feature of her class. Instead of writing analytical essays, Ms. Chan assigns personal essays that allow you to develop your unique personal identity. For example, after the Scarlet Letter, we had to explore a symbol of our choosing and create a story of our own using Hawthorne's Scarlet Letter as model. Later on, she allows you to visit museums relating to American literature and identities and asks you reflect on your experiences. However in recent years, students have complained about her anal policies as well as her low grading system. Unless you kiss her rotten ass, you will not get higher than a 80.

==Ms. Holly Weiss==
Ms. Holly Weiss is a good teacher.

==Mr. Eric Grossman==
Mr. Grossman assigns a heavy amount of reading, covering American papers, novels and poetry from the seventeenth, eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, as well as mixing in a few more modern 20th-century works with connections to this era. Reading assignments may be up to 40-50 pages per night. Literature covered begins with shorter works such as the sermon ''Sinners in the Hands of an Angry God'', by Jonathan Edwards, the Declaration of Independence, and excerpts from ''Founding Brothers'' by Joseph Ellis, a historical account of important moments in the early history of the United States. The course continues into novels such as Mark Twain's ''Huckleberry Finn'', The ''Narrative of the Life of Frederick Douglass'', Edith Wharton's ''The Age of Innocence'', Hawthorne's ''The Scarlet Letter'', Thoreau's ''Walden'' and William Faulkner's ''Go Down Moses''. The course concludes with the study of poetry by Walt Whitman and essays by Ralph Waldo Emerson. Typical assignments include thesis essays and a few creative pieces, such as a journal detailing an experience writing outside in the presence of nature (after reading ''Walden''), and a dramatic dialogue between characters and authors covered in the course.

==Mr. Shawn Gerety==</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>European Literature</title>
    <id>255</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95614</id>
      <timestamp>2012-03-14T00:27:14Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>108.21.4.119</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Ms. Moore */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = European Literature
| department    = English
| code          = E3EL, E4EL
| teachers      = [[Ms. Emily Moore]], [[Ms. Rosa Mazzurco]], [[Mr. Eric Grossman]], [[Mr. Hugh Francis]], [[Ms. Kim Manning]], [[Ms. Sophie Oberfield]]
| typical_year  = [[Sophomore year|Sophomore]]
| terms         = Both
| fills         = Sophomore English Requirement
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = 
| website       = 
}}

'''European Literature''', often referred to as '''Euro Lit''', is a full year, single period selective course for sophomores. Students are required to choose between Classical Literature and European Literature to fulfill their English requirement. Although the topics covered in European Literature are intended to complement the [[AP European History]] class, the class is offered to all sophomores, and taking [[AP European History]] does not afford students any significant advantage. Teachers of this course expect students to be reasonably comfortable with the basics learned in [[Freshman Composition]], such as the MLA format and the mechanics of English.

==Curriculum==
The curriculum changes from year to year, as each teacher makes their own alterations. However, the following texts are almost always taught: Homer's ''The Odyssey'', Voltaire's ''Candide'', Oscar Wilde's ''The Picture of Dorian Gray'', and James Joyce's ''Dubliners''.

==Teaching Style==
===Ms. Brown===
Ms. Brown is a fairly lax, friendly and open teacher. For the most part, class is discussion based and highly structured. On a typical day, students walk into class, take out their notebooks, copy down the Aim and homework for the day, then begin working on the Do Now. This may be an independent writing assignment based on the reading, or a thought provoking question to discuss with a neighbor. After the Do Now is completed, Ms. Brown guides a class discussion. The majority of learning is achieved during these class discussions.
====Assignments====
Assignments are very open ended: in the past, she has assigned traditional essays, presentations, film projects, poetry, satires, and the like. The essay assignments are given well in advance of the due date, and students are expected to adhere to several deadlines (i.e. thesis, first draft, etc.). All thesis statements must be approved by her before a student begins working on an essay. Generally, a list of essay topics is given out, and if students wish to write a different essay, they must consult with her first; this is, in fact, encouraged. Her policy on lateness is the department standard and is strictly enforced (an A paper that is a day late becomes an A-), although extensions are given if a student wishes to use the writing center. Essays are graded according to department policy, and she very rarely gives a paper a perfect score. Many of the nontraditional assignments are handed out with their own rubric. The amount of reading assigned nightly is moderate, and plenty of time is given to write essays. Deadlines are often extended if she feels the class is not ready.

====Grading Policy====
Grades are based mostly on class participation and performance on assignments. Although class is very enjoyable, grades are usually not generous.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Football</title>
    <id>176</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95419</id>
      <timestamp>2011-12-17T02:37:45Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>72.229.157.97</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Games */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox clubpub
| name          = Football
| coaches       = Francisco Rivera (JV), Mark Strasser (Varsity), Michael Tauber (Varsity)
| months        = September - November (season), August (Conditioning), Winter (lifting), Spring (conditioning)
| website       = http://psal.org/psalsports/school/psal_schoolprofile.asp?cschool=02519
| contact       = stuyfootball@gmail.com
}}
'''Stuyvesant's football team''' (called the '''Peglegs''') is divided into two sections, [[varsity]] and [[junior varsity]] (JV). The junior varsity team consists of freshmen and sophomores while the varsity team mostly consists of juniors and seniors. Rarely (one or two a year), talented sophomores are allowed onto the varsity team. Although the teams are walk-on, one should not join if one is not dedicated; football is a large time commitment.

== Junior Varsity ==
The JV team is coached by [[Fransisco Rivera]]. Players will develop and learn the skills necessary to play football at a competitive level. It can be seen as preparation for varsity level play, because if one is considered ready, he will be moved to varsity. A player may not transfer between JV and varsity midseason.

=== Practice ===
Practice is every day after school from roughly 3:30 to 6:00. Practice is held at [[Pier 40]], which is a 15 minute walk along the [[Hudson River]] from Stuyvesant. Players are recommended to acquire a [[ZT10]] (10th period sports team free) so that they may arrive on time. Alternatively, one may take the [[Wikipedia:1 (New York City Subway service)|1 Train]] to Houston Street, but jogging to practice is recommended for conditioning. Activities in practice range from tackling drills to position-specific drills.

=== Games ===
Games are typically every Saturday or Sunday in the morning or afternoon. Some games which are at Pier 40 are Friday after school. In the 2011-2012 season, the team was 5-3

== Varisty ==
The varsity team is coached by [[Mark Strasser]] and [[Michael Tauber]]. 

=== Games ===
The game schedule is very similar to the JV schedule. In 2011-2012 season, the team was 5-4.

== Other Information ==
=== Equipment ===
Equipment includes a helmet, two jerseys (home and away), pads, along with several other things such as a ticket to the football banquet in the spring. The helmet and pads are rented and must be returned at the end of the season. The game jerseys may be kept but the practice jersey must be returned. It is highly recommended that one purchases cleats (about $70) for better traction. Under Armor (about $35) is also helpful since the season is mostly during winter months.

=== Forms ===
As with all PSAL sports, one has to acquire a medical form and a parental consent form to participate. All forms may be found [http://psal.org/psalsports/pegasus/psal_pforms.asp?menu=links here].</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Freshman Composition</title>
    <id>173</id>
    <revision>
      <id>2553</id>
      <timestamp>2010-07-24T22:03:42Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1456397348</username>
        <id>59</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with '{{Infobox class | name          = Freshman Composition | department    = English | code          = E1FE | teachers      =  | typical_year  = Freshman | terms         = Fall and S…'</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Freshman Composition
| department    = English
| code          = E1FE
| teachers      = 
| typical_year  = Freshman
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| floor         = Ninth
}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Geometry</title>
    <id>155</id>
    <revision>
      <id>2515</id>
      <timestamp>2010-07-19T20:30:41Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1456397348</username>
        <id>59</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Curriculum */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Geometry
| department    = [[Mathematics]]
| code          = Fall: MG21/MG21E Spring: MG22/MG22H
| teachers      = [[Mr. David Park]], [[Mr. Richard Ku]], [[Ms. Melinda Protass]], [[Mr. D'Alleva]], [[Mr. Jonas Kalish]], [[Mr. Bill Kavanagh]], [[Mr. Robert Maksudian]], [[Ms. Dawn Vollaro]], [[Ms. Deena Avigdor]], [[Ms. Debbie Goldberg]] 
| typical_year  = [[Freshman year|Freshman]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| pre/coreq_for = Trigonometry (pre-req for)
| floor         = [[Fourth floor|Fourth]]
}}

'''Geometry''' is a required full-year course taught to many freshman. This course prepares students for the geometry [[regents]] and other mathematics courses that one will take during their high school years. The material taught includes logic, basic theorems, constructions, and 3-D geometry.


== Curriculum ==

The fall term teaches students about logic, proofs, and mostly qualitative theorems. Basic definitions and postulates are first introduced. With these fundamental tools, the teacher will prove new theorems and eventually build up to new concepts. As the semester approaches an end, there are significantly less proofs and students will begin to solve short answer problems. 

During the spring term, students learn about quantitative theorems, analytic geometry, constructions, and 3-D figures. Unlike the fall term in which statements and reasons are used to prove another statement, this term involves much more algebra and calculations. A student should be able to calculate area, understand lengths of chords, and know about the ratios of sides in special triangles by the end of the term.

== Teaching Style ==
===Ms. Goldberg===
====Class====
The class generally begins with three simultaneous processes:
1. Students work on a [[Do Now]] at the front board.
2. Ms. Goldberg checks the homework which is passed up at the start of the class.
3. Students write up their solutions to selected homework problems at the back.

After Ms. Goldberg is done checking the homework, the class goes over the homework solutions at the back board. Mistakes, errors, and sometimes new solutions are briefly discussed. When this is done, the class will move on to going over the [[Do Now]]. 

The [[Do Now]] usually provides students with a review of the previous lesson or prepares them for the lesson of the day (written on the [[Aim]]).

When introduced to new concepts, students are usually challenged to write up their own formal definitions for mathematical terms. A class discussion on the most appropriate definition will later determine the definition used for the term. Using these newly defined terms, postulates are formally stated. As the basic building blocks, the postulates are used to prove new theorems. After theorems are taught, an entire period is dedicated to practicing problems. About a week later, a test will be given. 

====Homework====
Ms. Goldberg's homework varies in length, but they are often a few tough problems. They provide students with practice for applying the theorems taught in class. She does not require a student to have a complete solution if they can't solve them, but she does require there to be attempts on the problems. Each student will pass up homework during the beginning of class every day. The only exception to this is when a student is writing up a solution on the back board and therefore must have the homework with them (but it will be checked).

During the beginning of class, a group of students are allowed to write up solutions in the back board, unless there is no homework or instructed otherwise. These groups are selected at the beginning of the year and will be maintained throughout the semester. For instance, it might be set that the first two rows can go up the board on Mondays, middle two rows go up on Tuesdays, last two rows go up on Wednesdays, females go up on Thursdays, and males go up on Fridays.

====Tests====
Unless otherwise stated, her test covers all of the material taught from the time of the previous test to the lessons approximately a week before the next test. Her tests can be considered fair since many of the students score around the low 90's to the 80's. Students can finish the test in a period, but it is not unusual to have a number of students not finish. There is an extra credit on the test hence a maximum score of 105 points for each test.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Human Diseases</title>
    <id>117</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3466</id>
      <timestamp>2010-10-17T00:48:12Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>rvv</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Human Diseases
| department    = [[Biology department|Biology]]
| code          = SB3PHD1
| teachers      = [[Mr. Jerry Citron]]
| typical_year  =  [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Science elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Biology]]
| pre/coreq_for = [[Hospital Internship]]
| textbooks     = Microbiology: An Introduction (Tortora, Funke &amp; Case)
| floor         = [[Seventh Floor|Seventh]]
| website       = http://bioremediation.pageout.net/page.dyn/student/course/course_home?course_id=132121
}}
'''Human Diseases''' is a single semester science elective which focuses on the basics of pathogens, epidemiology, the immune system, and treatments for disease. The course covers a number of common diseases, such as tetanus, influenza, and autoimmune diseases. There is also a focus on drugs (particularly antibiotics) and medical techniques. Though the [http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/bio_descriptions/sb9.html Stuyvesant course site] states that the course includes laboratory work, this has been eliminated due to budget cuts as of the 2009-2010 school year.

==Teaching style==
[[Mr. Jerry Citron]] is very dynamic within the classroom. Though disorganized and absent minded, he knows the material well and explains it well. He gives semi-regular homework, although he collects it on a random basis. Most classes are taught as lectures, with frequent questions for students. Mr. Citron often mixes personal stories and tangents into the class. He previously worked as a paramedic and thus has many anecdotes related to the subject matter. Mr. Citron often uses powerpoint presentations for lessons, although he usually supplements these with notes on the board.

==Tests==
Mr. Citron's tests are generally considered difficult in comparison with the general difficulty of homework and the day-to-day class. Many students only do well if they thoroughly review the appropriate sections of the textbook. Tests usually consist of a multiple choice section and a set of short answer questions, from which students must pick a certain number to answer. Occasionally Mr. Citron gives a list of short answer questions before the test, and then includes a subset on the actual test. Mr. Citron may curve the scores, but this happens rarely. There are approximately six tests during the semester.

==Grading==
The course website states that the grading breakdown is as follows:

*Exams and Quizzes &amp;mdash; 75%
*Participation and Homework &amp;mdash; 15%
*End of term disease presentation &amp;mdash; 10%

However, Mr. Citron readily acknowledges that he does not like paper work and is not meticulous at keeping track of grades, meaning that these guidelines may not be followed exactly. Also, the disease presentation does not always occur in a given semester.

==External links==
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/bio_descriptions/sb9.html Stuyvesant course description site]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Index.php</title>
    <id>248</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94774</id>
      <timestamp>2011-09-04T20:18:50Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>46.33.241.195</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt; [http://topmeds10.com/?aid=73e86866e5&amp;q=phentermine stuyclopedia]&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;[http://topmeds10.com/?aid=73e86866e5&amp;q=phentermine &gt;&gt;stuyclopedia&lt;&lt;]&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[http://topmeds10.com/?aid=73e86866e5&amp;q=phentermine stuyclopedia!]&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Index of class articles</title>
    <id>99</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97194</id>
      <timestamp>2013-09-21T20:50:42Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>173.77.23.94</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Electives */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The following is a list of started or completed class articles:

==Biology/Geo-Science==
===Regents Courses===
===Electives===
*[[Human Diseases]]
*[[Molecular Biology]]
*[[Biological Lab Techniques]]
===AP Courses===
*[[AP Psychology and Research]]

==Chemistry/Physics==
*[[AP Chemistry]]
*[[AP Physics B]]
*[[Organic Chemistry]]

==English==
===Sophomore Year===
*[[Classical Literature]]
*[[European Literature]]

===Junior Year===
*[[Early American Literature]]
*[[American Studies]]

===Senior Year===

==Math==
===Regular Courses===
*[[Geometry]]
*[[Algebra II and Trigonometry]]
*[[Precalculus]]
*[[Calculus]]

===Electives===
*[[AP Computer Science]]
*[[Math Research]]

==Music/Fine Arts==
*[[AP Music Theory]]
*[[Jazz Band]]
*[[Symphony Orchestra]]

==Physical Education==
*[[Rollerblading]]

==Social Studies==
*[[Wall Street with Merrill Lynch]]
*[[NYC History]]
*[[American Studies]]

==Technology==
===5-Tech===
*[[Digital Photography]]
*[[Video Production]]
===10-Tech===
*[[System Level Programming]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Index of club articles</title>
    <id>132</id>
    <revision>
      <id>96253</id>
      <timestamp>2012-09-18T02:19:42Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>74.73.136.186</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">[http://www.schoolwiki.jesseweiman.com/A_Cappella A Cappella Club]
[http://www.schoolwiki.jesseweiman.com/Photo_Club Photo Club]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>JSA Minutes</title>
    <id>133</id>
    <revision>
      <id>2247</id>
      <timestamp>2010-06-15T22:37:43Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>96.250.11.112</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Blanked the page</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" />
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Jazz Band</title>
    <id>90</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3467</id>
      <timestamp>2010-10-17T00:50:35Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>rvv</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Jazz Band
| department    = [[Music and Fine Arts]]
| code          = AUJJZ
| teachers      = [[Dr. Gregor Winkel]]
| typical_year  = [[Freshman]], [[Sophomore]], [[Junior]], or [[Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Music Appreciation (with three terms)]], [[10 tech (with eight terms)]]
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[First]]
| website       = 
}}
'''Jazz Band''' is one of the five bands at Stuyvesant and the only band that plays jazz music. Acceptance into the jazz band is by audition, rather than through online sign-up. The jazz band plays at various school events, such as open houses for incoming freshmen, as well as at least one concert each term. Students in the jazz band also have the opportunity to be in a jazz combo. Dr. Winkel is the only jazz band teacher and it is only offered first period.

==Curriculum==
Though there is no strict curriculum for the jazz band to follow, the jazz band tends to begin at the basics of jazz music every year, despite a majority of sophomores, juniors, and seniors every year. A few lessons deal with the expression, phrasing, and dynamics of jazz music and how they differ from those of classical music, but most classes are spent playing music in preparation for concerts. The music played in this band is usually at a low level recommended for beginner jazz students, though the band does play higher level jazz pieces once in a while.

==Teaching Style==
Dr. Winkel usually begins the class with a warm-up, which includes major scales, mixolydian mode, dorian mode, and seventh chords. He does this in order to reinforce the importance of recognizing and hearing chords when improvising. After warming up, he goes directly into the repertoire of any upcoming performances.

Dr. Winkel encourages every student to improvise, especially freshmen who may be too shy to improvise. Occasionally, he chooses a piece with a solo section and goes around the room, asking each student to improvise for a 16-bar phrase. In doing so, he helps students overcome their fear of playing badly.

===Grading Policy===
This class is based heavily on attendance. Excessive lateness or cutting can result in a low grade or even a failing grade, regardless of the student's skill in music.

==Jazz Combo==
Select students from the jazz band are asked to play in a jazz combo, which consists of about five students. In addition to the concerts and open houses that the jazz band plays in, the combo plays at various events around New York City after school and on weekends. The combo plays much more challenging music than the band and also allows its members more opportunities to improvise. If they have an upcoming event, combo members rehearse together first period, missing band rehearsal.

==External Links==
*[http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/art%26music_descriptions/usb0.html Stuyvesant course description]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Key Club</title>
    <id>252</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94412</id>
      <timestamp>2011-07-29T10:21:42Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Mishel2TCt</username>
        <id>110</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with '&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt; [http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 club]&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 &gt;&gt;club&lt;&lt;]&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 club!]&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;b…'</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt; [http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 club]&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 &gt;&gt;club&lt;&lt;]&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[http://pillsm.com/?a=7539 club!]&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>List of Teachers</title>
    <id>101</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1740</id>
      <timestamp>2010-04-26T02:57:32Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>173.70.90.100</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{|class=&quot;wikitable sortable&quot; border=1 cellpadding=5
|+ Stuyvesant High School Teachers
|-
! Title
! First Name
! Last Name
! Department(s)
! Classes Taught
! # Of Years In Stuyvesant
|-
| Mr.
| [[Joseph Tamosaitis|Joseph]]
| [[Joseph Tamosaitis|Tamosaitis]]
| [[Music and Fine Arts]]
| [[AP Music Theory]], [[Intermediate Orchestra]], [[Advanced Orchestra]], [[Symphonic Orchestra]]
|
|-
| Mr.
| [[Michael Waxman|Michael]]
| [[Michael Waxman|Waxman]]
| [[Social Studies]], [[World Languages]]
| [[Economics]], [[Hebrew]]
|
|-
| Mr.
| [[William Boericke|William]]
| [[William Boericke|Boericke]]
| [[Social Studies]]
| [[Economics]], [[AP US Government]]
|
|-
| Mr.
| [[Jerry Citron|Jerry]]
| [[Jerry Citron|Citron]]
| [[Biology and Geo-Science]]
| [[Human Diseases]], [[Medical Diagnosis]], [[AP Environmental Science]],[[Regents Biology]]
|
|-
| Mr.
| [[John Avallone|John]]
| [[John Avallone|Avallone]]
| [[Chemistry and Physics]]
| [[AP Physics B]]
|
|-
| Ms.
| [[Sushma Arora|Sushma]]
| [[Sushma Arora|Arora]]
| [[Chemistry and Physics]]
| [[AP Chemistry]]
|
|-
| Ms.
| [[Maryann Ferrara|Maryann]]
| [[Maryann Ferrara|Ferrara]]
| [[Mathematics]]
| [[Math Team]], [[AP Calculus AB]]
|
|-
| Mr.
| [[George Kennedy|George]]
| [[George Kennedy|Kennedy]]
| [[Social Studies]]
| [[US History]], [[Wall Street with Merrill Lynch]]
|
|-
| Dr.
| [[Steven O'Malley|Steven]]
| [[Steven O'Malley|O'Malley]]
| [[Chemistry and Physics]]
| [[Honors Chemistry]], [[Organic Chemistry]]
|
|-
| Mr.
| [[Michael Orlando|Michael]]
| [[Michael Orlando|Orlando]]
| [[Chemistry and Physics]]
| [[Chemistry]]
|
|}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Mandarin Chinese</title>
    <id>156</id>
    <revision>
      <id>2330</id>
      <timestamp>2010-07-01T03:14:57Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1347632498</username>
        <id>8</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <text xml:space="preserve">'''Mandarin Chinese''' is a sequence of language courses available at Stuyvesant. Students learn to understand, speak read and write in modern standard Chinese. There are tracks for both native and non-native Mandarin speakers, as well as a full-year AP course for  students from both the native and non-native classes who have completed the sequence. For non-native students who desire to take another year of Mandarin Chinese without taking the AP course, Conversational Mandarin (FM7-FM8) is available.

{{Infobox class
| name          = Mandarin Chinese
| department    = [[World Languages]]
| code          = FM1-FM6(regents), FM1N-FM4N(native), FM7-FM8(conversational), FM7X-FM8X(AP)
| teachers      = [[Ms. Fan Guan]], [[Ms. Ching-Yun Yang]], [[Mr.Carl Tan]]
| typical_year  = [[Freshman-Senior year]]
| terms         = both
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| Textbook(s)   = Hanyu for Beginning Students Vol 1-3, Hanyu for Intermediate Students vol 1-3
| floor         = [[seventh floor, tenth floor]]
| website       = [stuychinese.com]
}}

==Curriculum==
===FM1-FM6===
Mandarin Chinese for non-native speakers typically begins with an introduction to the Chinese writing system and tonal pronunciation aided by pinyin, a romanization system for spoken Chinese syllables. Once the basics of pronunciation and writing are covered, several units of vocabulary are introduced. The first year covers subjects such as greetings, family members, school subjects and classroom objects, clothing and shopping, and body parts/physical description. Later terms of Mandarin introduce basic elements of Chinese culture and geography, including major cities and regions of China, Chinese holidays and traditional foods. grammar is woven throughout the curriculum and new structures are introduced in each unit.

==Teaching Style==
=== Ms. Guan===
Ms. Guan teaches from the textbook and from a series of handouts for each unit that students are expected to print out from the class website. Classes are spent reviewing sets of vocabulary words and grammatical structures from the handouts and sometimes competing sets of translation or fill-in-the-blank questions as a class. On some days Ms. Guan has volunteers read dialogues aloud from the textbook, gives students time to practice with classmates, and then selects another pair of volunteers to perform the dialogue. Tests occur about once a month, and quizzes are given about once every two weeks. Homework is usually given weekly, and consists of translation questions from the textbook and/or compositions of about 100-150 characters each. Group presentation projects are sometimes assigned at the end of the term. In FM6, much of the class is devoted to reviewing for the Regents exam, and the usual activities may be replaced with reviewing past regents exams and practicing speaking and composition questions for the Regents. 

===Ms. Yang===
Ms. Yang focuses more heavily on speaking. She often has students create surveys or interviews and walk around the classroom conversing with other students in Chinese to obtain the answers to the questions. Students are also given a large packet of grammar and a new page is reviewed weekly (more frequently as the final exam approaches). There are usually a number of projects each term, which may be short skits and decorated/illustrated pieces of writing such as letters, invitations, or advertisements. There are tests at the end of each unit, and quizzes nearly every week. However, quizzes tend to be fairly easy and usually consist of matching characters in a list to their meanings.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Math Research</title>
    <id>175</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95886</id>
      <timestamp>2012-04-23T00:03:26Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>67.80.75.134</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Math Research
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = 
| teachers      = [[Mr. Rubinstein]]
| typical_year  = [[Freshman year|Freshman]] or [[Sophmore year|Sophmore]]
| terms         = winter, spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Fourth floor|Four]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Math Research''' is a one-term math elective that can be taken in the winter or spring term by sophmores and freshmen. This class covers both topics taught and not taught in the Integrated Algebra, Integrated Geometry, and Algebra II and Trigonometry curriculums. It is currently taught by Mr. Rubinstein.

Homework is regularly given and a few quizzes will be given. However, the homework and quizzes are generally easy since Mr. Rubinstein gives a practice quiz very similar to the real quiz right before the quiz and he collects homework on a specified day, giving ample time to do it. Some topics may be taught in a few days or one to two weeks and the topics are generally interesting and easy to learn. Students will be given a month to complete tasks on Geometer's Sketchpad, a mathematical drawing program specially designed for creating geometric constructions and are required to submit a 12-page feedback. Tasks to be finished by Geometer's Sketchpad include creating fractals, reconstructing geometric proofs of the Pythagorean theorem and other theorems, reconstructing classic geometric constructions, squaring the circle, and constructing inscribed polygons.  In the last month of the course, class-time is entirely devoted to working on a 12- page research paper about a mathematical topic approved by Mr. Rubinstein.

==Possible Class Topics==
*Fermat's Last Theorem
*Solving Rubik's Cube
*RSA encryption
*Chinese Remainder Theorem
*Proving the Pythagorean Theorem
*Pythagorean Triples
*Pascal's Triangle
*Combinations and Permutations
*Continued Fractions
*Amicable Numbers
*Algorithms to Estimate Square Root Values
*Euclidean Algorithm
*Modules
*Finding Functions for Geometric Series
*Geometric Constructions</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Math Team</title>
    <id>171</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95601</id>
      <timestamp>2012-02-21T01:14:53Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>75.151.130.145</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Math Team
| department    = [[Mathematics]]
| code          = Freshman: MM1PPS Sophomore: MM3PPS Junior/Senior: METS3
| teachers      = MM1PPS: [[Glen Chew]], [[Debbie Goldberg]], [[Sebastian Stoenescu]] MM3PPS: [[Ashvin Jaishankar]], [[Oana Pascu]] METS3: [[Jim Cocoros]] 
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| textbooks     = Art of Problem Solving
| floor         = [[Fourth]]
}}

'''Math Team''' is a two-term elective class. This elective provides students with a chance to participate in math competitions and develop problem solving skills. There are no grades for this class, but good performance in math contests can be excellent to mention in college applications. 

==Class==
All math team classes occur first period.

===Grading===
Math Team is graded with a pass or fail. At the end of a term, you will receive CR, meaning &quot;credit&quot; for the class.

==Competitions==

===Continental Math League===
Only freshmen take this contest.

This contest is considered the easiest of the contests we have in Stuyvesant. There are six meets with six problems each. Each set of six problems is to be done in thirty minutes. An award is given to the top twelve students in this contest and special awards are given to those who get a perfect score in all of the meets. This competition is taken in class.

Abbreviation: CML

===New York Mathematics League===
All grades take this contest.

This contest has a total of six meets with six problems each. Thirty minutes is given to solve each set of six problems. An award is given to a perfect scorer. This competition is taken in class.

Abbreviation: NYML

===New York City Interscholastic Mathematics League===
A group of students are selected to take this contest. There are three divisions: Soph-frosh, Junior, and Senior. Freshman take the Soph-frosh. Sophomores and juniors take the Junior. Juniors and seniors take the Senior contest. Some exceptions are made.

Students are split into teams, but this contest is to be done individually. The total score of the students in a team is the score of the team. 

There are a total of six meets for Soph-frosh and Junior division, three of which are in the fall and three in spring. For Senior division, there are ten meets total with five meets for fall and five meets for spring. Each meet has a total of six problems. Ten minutes is given to solve three sets of two problems for each meet. 

The highest scoring individual(s) of each division is given an award and top three teams also get awards. 

This is an after-school competition. 

Abbreviation: NYCIML

===Mandelbrot Competition===
All grades take this contest. Freshmen and sophomores take the regional contest. Juniors and seniors take the national contest.

This contest is considered one of the hardest in the school year and certainly the hardest contest for students who are not selected for additional competitions. 

Both the regional and national competition has five rounds total. Each round consists of seven problems to be solved in forty minutes. The value of the problems are weighed; the first two problems are worth one point each, the next three are worth two-points each, and the last two are worth three points each. Higher point values indicate harder problems.

This contest is taken in class.

No abbreviations for this contest.

===New York State Mathematics League===
Selected students take this contest. These students are put into teams and each team will consist of fifteen students.

There are several components to this contest: a power question, a team test, an individual round, and a relay. The total scores for all of these components becomes the team score. Obviously, the individual scores of students will only include the individual round.

'''Power Question'''

This part of the competition is worth a total of 50 points. There is usually some background information before a set of problems. The goal of this component is to aid students in discovering new concepts. Problems do not necessarily have the same point values and a number of these problems will require proofs or work shown. The time limit is 60 minutes.

'''Team Test'''

This part of the competition is worth a total of 50 points. A team of students are given twenty minutes to solve ten problems. Each problem is worth five points. All answers are submitted on the answer sheet. No work is required for this component.

'''Individual Round'''

This part of the competition will be the only part that counts into the individual score. Each problem is worth one point. There are five sets of two problems each. 10 minutes is given to solve each set of problems. The sum of the individual scores will make the team score.

'''Relay'''

This part of the competition is done in sub-teams of three students each. Students will simultaneously work on the problems they are each given. These problems will generally require the answer from the previous student to do. The first student may pass their answer and only their answer to the second student. The second student may pass their answer and only their answer to the third student. Only these passes are allowed. The first and second student may pass back an answer as often as they wish. The third student can hand in their answers after three minutes or six minutes (although the third minute answer will not count if a six minute answer is handed in). A correct answer in three minutes is worth 5 points. A correct answer in six minutes is worth 3 points. An incorrect answer is worth no points.

'''Tiebreakers'''

Students with a high enough individual score take the tiebreaker. This will determine the ranks of students with the same score. 

Abbreviation: NYSML

===American Regions Mathematics League===
''Same as New York State Mathematics League (NYSML). However, New York State Mathematics League took the format from American Regions Mathematics League.''

Abbreviation: ARML

===Princeton University Mathematics Competition===

===Harvard-MIT Mathematics Tournament===

===American Mathematics Competition Series===</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Mathematical Explorations</title>
    <id>159</id>
    <revision>
      <id>2345</id>
      <timestamp>2010-07-04T01:34:38Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>686698358</username>
        <id>61</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Teaching Stlye */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Mathematical Explorations
| department    = [[Mathematics Department|Mathematics]]
| code          = MM3PME
| teachers      = [[Mr. D'Alleva]]
| typical_year  = [[Senior]], [[Junior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Fourth]]

}}

'''Mathematical Explorations''' is a one term math elective course that explores various areas of mathematics not typically covered in a high school mathematics curriculum. 

==Curriculum==
Topics covered in class are actually quite far-flung. There is no organized set of topics that Mr. Dalleva teaches but rather, what he feels like covering that day. Students are expected to do three presentations per marking period with each presentation on a different subject of math. 


==Teaching Stlye==
===Mr. D'Avella=== 
[[Mr. D'Avella]] teaches in a very relaxed manner and likes to take things slowly. Lessons are taught in lectures and exercises are often given out to ensure that students understand the material. There are no tests nor homework. If there is any homework, it is given sparingly.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Medical Human Genetics</title>
    <id>158</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95024</id>
      <timestamp>2011-09-13T03:32:32Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>71.167.132.184</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>+</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Medical Human Genetics 
| department    = Biology and Earth Science 
| code          = SB3PHG
| teachers      = [[Dr. Maria Nedwidek]]
| typical_year  = [[Sophmore year|Sophmores]], [[Junior year|Juniors]], [[Senior year|Seniors]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = Senior elective requirement
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Living Environment]] (pre)
| pre/coreq_for = [[AP Biology]]
| floor         = [[Seventh floor|seventh]]
| website       =
}}

'''Medical Human Genetics''' is a single term biology elective that introduces high school students to genetics. Genetics is a branch of science that deals with heredity and the likelihood of certain traits passed down to the offspring. In this class, as the name suggests, students will learn about genetics and apply their knowledge in a medical context, culminating in a final project in which cures are proposed for various genetic diseases.

==Curriculum==
The course begins with a review of the genetics one learned in [[Regents Living Environment]]. Next, students will learn about hereditary diseases and pedigrees, which are like family trees but instead, track the disease in question.

==Dr. Nedwidek==
[[Dr. Maria Nedwidek]], casually '''Dr.Ned''', usually starts the class with a do now before giving her lesson. The material is taught in lecture format and notes are written on the board, although at times, she will just dictate. She usually asks about a term on the board to make sure the class knows what it means. Homework is usually given by email with several day's advance notice, although there are breaks when Dr.Ned feels she is being overwhelmed by other work. Dr. Ned goes over the homework often, again to make sure her students understand the material.

There is a final project where the student chooses a genetic disease, researches it and proposes a cure. Selecting a disease begins as early as two months into the course and the student is expected to work on it periodically. In the end, the student will have handed in several drafts and a final version. The student will also have to make a short presentation on his or her disease. The entire project counts for 20% of the final grade.

She is aware that her course is not easy and hands out a course outline, complete with a time schedule, within the first few days on class. She asks the students to look it over and after reading through all of it, to decide whether or not they would drop the class. Dr. Ned does expect a lot of effort from those who stay (very few actually do drop it). She is considered one of the most intensive teachers in Stuy&amp;mdash;you may or may not hear about her endeavors with &quot;those Freshmen&quot;.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Molecular Biology</title>
    <id>151</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94416</id>
      <timestamp>2011-07-29T20:39:05Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>71.167.249.43</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Teaching Style */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">'''Molecular Biology/Molecular Genetics''', usually referred to as merely &quot;Molecular&quot;, or &quot;Molecular Science&quot;, is a one-year college-level sequence studying classic experiments in molecular biology and dealing with common laboratory techniques used in molecular biology, including gel electrophoresis and transformation. Depending on the number of sections, the class is taught by [[Dr. John M. Utting]] and sometimes [[Ms. Anne Manwell]]. In the 2009-2010 school year, only one section was taught by Dr.Utting.

== Curriculum ==
Much of the first semester is spent reading classic scientific papers, such as Avery, MacLeod, and McCarty's discovery of DNA as the transforming principle and Watson and Crick's discovery of the structure of DNA. These papers are on a very high level, and the speed at which they are studied leaves about half the class not understanding what the papers are about. However, the class is meant to be a laboratory, not a lecture-style, class. Laboratories conducted in the first-term are relatively basic and simple compared to those of second term. An example of a first term lab is determination of a standard curve of methylene blue. Students also learn very basic techniques, such as using a micropipette and producing sterile agar plates. Dr.Utting also explains how to write our laboratory papers which are modeled off the structure of real scientific papers, including Introduction, Materials and Methods, Results, and Conclusion/Discussion sections.

The second term is spent on more modern developments and techniques. A few lessons are taught explaining the background of scientific phenomena such as transformation and the history of their discoveries. Labs deal with denaturation of DNA and protein, transformation, gel electrophoresis, and DNA purification. Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is done if there is time. Laboratory papers are written for all labs, including first term labs. The difference between writing lab papers in first term versus second term is that first term, Dr.Utting guides the students through writing the papers, while second term, the papers are written largely without Dr.Utting's help. The class culminates in a final notebook project, where all labs are cut out and glued to a notebook with a table of contents and appendices for recipes, aseptic techniques, and safety procedures. Many students pull all-nighters trying to finish this notebook.

== Teaching Style ==
Dr.Utting is extremely popular among students. He has a patient and calm attitude, despite students frequently making mistakes or not understanding what to do. He enjoys poking fun at students and making jokes. He also genuinely cares about his students. 

Non-lab classes are usually discussion-based. When learning about the background for certain phenomena, Dr.Utting often asks us to think like the scientists and propose our own solutions before Dr.Utting reveals the discovery. Incorrect hypotheses give Dr.Utting room for a little teasing, but nonetheless he still encourages his students to keep trying. 

When performing labs, the class is usually divided up into 4 or 5 groups. Labs get confusing at times to many students, especially since for most labs there is no instruction sheet besides the students' personal notes from a discussion the day before. As a result, failed experiments are not uncommon in the class.

=== Grading Policy ===
Dr.Utting has no official policy for grading or grade breakdown. However, he gives generous grades at times, and students generally get grades above 90. Grades are mainly based on laboratory papers written. Dr.Utting rarely gives tests in this class; In 2009-2010, the students received only one quiz. This is not strange, however, because, as stated above, Molecular Biology/Molecular Genetics is mainly a laboratory class. Class participation - in discussions of scientific papers and in laboratories - also plays a factor into the grade. If no papers are written or graded by Dr.Utting in a marking period, the grade is based on participation. Homework is rarely given as well, and homeworks usually are merely to &quot;think&quot; like the scientists being studied to propose hypotheses to the problem investigated by the scientists, or to search up on the Internet a topic. These do not have to be written on paper and are only discussed verbally as a class.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>NYC History</title>
    <id>253</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94674</id>
      <timestamp>2011-08-19T14:56:37Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>71.167.247.28</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Curriculum */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">NYC History is a single-semester course that surveys the history of the development of New York City as a metropolis. The course spans the Dutch colonial era to the second-half of the twentieth century. If time permits, the class also studies issues of the 21st century. The course is taught by Mr. Sandler. 

==Curriculum==
The course begins with a study of New Amsterdam (New York City under the Dutch) and Peter Stuyvesant. Topics, which are covered in chronological order, include DeWitt Clinton and the Erie Canal, Walt Whitman, the Five Points slum, Tammany Hall and New York during the Gilded Age, the City Beautiful movement, Jacob Riis, F. Scott Fitzgerald and the Roaring Twenties, New York during the Great Depression, Robert Moses, and mayors such as Fiorello Laguardia, John Lindsay, Ed Koch and Rudy Giuliani. Clearly, much is covered in this single-semester course.

Trips heavily involve themselves in the course. Mr. Sandler may bring the students on 3 trips or more per semester. In the Spring of the 2010-2011 school year, there were two trips around lower Manhattan and one trip to Morningside Heights/Harlem. The students visit interesting sites such as Katz's deli (renowned for its pastrami sandwich on rye and which has been featured in the movie ''When Harry Met Sally''), Columbia University, the inside of City Hall (in the Fall of 2011-2012, the students caught a glimpse of Mayor Bloomberg), the old City Hall station (closed off to the public) and Cathedral St. John the Divine (the tallest cathedral in the world). For a fee, students are offered a chance to climb up to the top of the cathedral with Mr. Sandler. 

If the course is taken seriously, it can be pretty intense because Mr. Sandler assigns heavy nightly reading. However, the overwhelming majority of the students in the class are second-term seniors (the class is only offered in the spring), so many students do not take the course seriously. Either way, it is enjoyable regardless of whether the student does the reading because the trips and the interesting facts learned in the course make the course entertaining. 

The numerous guest speakers per semester enrich the course as well. In the 2010-2011 spring semester, guest speakers included Professor Robert Cohen from NYU who gave a lecture on student activists at Columbia University in the 60s, Dr. J. Emilio Carillo who spoke about New York during the Dinkins era, and Nicholas Dagen Bloom, author of ''Public Housing that Worked: New York in the Twentieth Century''.

==Teaching Style==
===Mr. Sandler===
Mr. Sandler is a very friendly and cool teacher. He is not excessively strict, but neither is he a teacher to mess around with. He often befriends students in the class. 

Mr. Sandler's lessons are tend to follow a predictable sequence: a roughly 20-minute lecture based off the previous night's reading, followed by a viewing of excerpts of the documentary companion to the textbook. During Mr. Sandler's lectures, he tries to elicit as much participation as possible, inviting students to share their opinions and comments in response to lesson topics or the previous night's homework.
====Grading Policy====
Mr. Sandler is fairly generous with grades for this elective.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Organic Chemistry</title>
    <id>122</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97204</id>
      <timestamp>2013-09-26T03:02:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>WenhaoDu</username>
        <id>124</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Organic Chemistry
| department    = Chemistry and Physics
| code          = SC5POC (Organic Chemistry I), SC6POC (Organic Chemistry II)
| teachers      = [[Dr. Steven O'Malley]], [[Mr. Michael Orlando]]
| typical_year  = [[junior]] or [[Senior year|senior]]
| terms         = both
| fills         = science elective requirement
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Chemistry]] or [[Honors Chemistry]] (pre)
| pre/coreq_for = 
| floor         = [[Ninth floor|ninth]]
| website       =
}}

'''Organic Chemistry''', sometimes referred to as '''orgo''', is a single-period elective course available to any student who has completed [[Regents Chemistry]] or [[Honors Chemistry]] with an overall grade of 95 or higher. The course is divided into two terms, the second of which is optional. Organic Chemistry focuses on the structure and reactions of carbon compounds. This includes discussion of compound nomenclature, functional groups, reaction mechanisms and organic synthesis. The first term covers material on line structure drawing, hydrocarbons, radical mechanisms, and reactions of alkenes, alkynes and alcohols. The second term covers more advanced topics such as structure determination, aromatic rings, enols and enolates, reactions of amines and finally some biochemical molecules and reactions. Organic Chemistry I is taught by [[Dr. Steven O'Malley]].

== Teaching Style ==
===Dr. O'Malley===

Dr. O'Malley teaches by lecturing and providing students with convenient handouts that supply important information for each lesson and several practice problems. He speaks and draws mechanisms on the board extremely quickly, but very clearly and will slow down if asked. He usually makes the class laugh and have fun, but does not distract the class and stays on topic. Demos are also common in his class


==Tests and quizzes==
Tests in Organic Chemistry occur approximately once a month, and may occur on any day of the week despite department policy. Tests consist of 15-20 multiple-choice questions and several free-response questions. Tests are graded on a scale of zero to 50 points, with each multiple choice worth 2 points. Free-response questions are graded differently on each test, and partial credit is available. Most tests have one or two extra-credit problems as well. Dr. O'Malley usually grades tests the next day. After each test, a &quot;leader board&quot; displaying the names of the highest-scoring students is posted up on the wall. 
Quizzes are given sporadically and without warning, but they are open-book and students are permitted to help each other solve the problems.   

==Homework==
Homework, usually given weekly, is fairly short but can be difficult. It consists of online multiple-choice problem sets that are graded digitally upon completion. moderate-length Projects, which consist of oral presentation and/or powerpoint, are given for each term. There is ample opportunity for extra credit at the end of the term - usually in the form additional project and an optional cumulative online test. In Organic Chemistry II, each student is required to study a &quot;named reaction&quot; of their choice and present on a Friday. named reaction-related questions appear on every test as extra-credit problems.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Orgo</title>
    <id>207</id>
    <revision>
      <id>4310</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-08T23:33:11Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SkyCL</username>
        <id>77</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>redirect</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Organic Chemistry]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Physics B</title>
    <id>84</id>
    <revision>
      <id>596</id>
      <timestamp>2010-01-02T05:32:53Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>oops, it redirected to itself</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[AP Physics B]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Queen Jane Joyce Argodale</title>
    <id>272</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97210</id>
      <timestamp>2013-10-06T06:12:05Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>129.59.115.4</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with 'Jane Joyce Argodale is a queen.'</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">Jane Joyce Argodale is a queen.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Robotics Team</title>
    <id>120</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1048</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-11T06:15:58Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1244591903</username>
        <id>5</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Stuypulse]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Stuypulse]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Rocketry</title>
    <id>184</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3480</id>
      <timestamp>2010-11-24T21:03:32Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>100000420217578</username>
        <id>4</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Rocketry]]&quot; ([edit=sysop] (indefinite) [move=sysop] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">This is the official site of the Stuyvesant High School Rocketry and Aeronautics Club.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Rollerblading</title>
    <id>79</id>
    <revision>
      <id>694</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-01T22:29:16Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>/* Lateness policy */  pruned</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Rollerblading
| department    = [[Health and Physical Education]]
| code          = PE5R, PE7R
| teachers      = [[Mr. Lawrence Barth]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall or Spring
| fills         = [[Physical Education]] selective requirement
| floor         = [[First floor|First]]
}}
'''Rollerblading''' is a [[Physical Education]] course that teaches students the basics of rollerblading and allows them to practice their rollerblading, both indoors and outdoors. This class, taught by [[Mr. Lawrence Barth]], is during first period for [[Junior year|juniors]] and third period for [[Senior year|seniors]]. Instead of using the regular gym [[locker rooms]], this class uses the lockers on the 1st floor by the student lounge. 

==Curriculum==
The first few classes consist of giving out equipment (though if a student chooses, they can bring their own), explaining the rules, regulations, and other important things to know, and teaching and practicing basic rollerblading, such as side-to-side motion and braking, in the sixth floor gymnasium. Later on, more advanced skills such as the front and back crossover are taught as well. After the first few classes, they are held outdoors in front of the school besides West Street. Here, veteran skaters can rollerblade around a &quot;middle&quot; area, where novices continue to practice getting used to being on skates and other rollerblading basics. After a few weeks of this, the class goes rollerblading to the downtown area. The rollerblading path takes students along the Hudson River, as they pass Rockefeller Park and the World Financial Center, and then back via mostly the same path. On rainy or other unfavorable days, either the class is held in the sixth floor gymnasium or a maintenance lesson is held on the first floor by the lockers. In a maintenance lesson, as [[Mr. Lawrence Barth|Mr. Barth]] demonstrates, all students takes apart a wheel(s) on their skates, cleans them up, and tightens them if they are loose, to prevent them from wearing out as well as being unsafe.

==Teaching style==
Mr. Barth is generally laid-back. When he gives a lesson, usually about rollerblading techniques, he explains how to execute the technique or trick, as well as demonstrating it. Then he gives the class time to practice it. While the class is skating outdoors or indoors in the sixth floor gymnasium, he usually skates alongside his students at his own pace, as he watches out for them. He also advises students to skate in pairs to be safer.

==Lateness policy==
The lateness policy for this class is similar to the other physical education classes. Coming to class unprepared and/or late too many times will result in a failing grade, though Mr. Barth can be slightly lenient at times. In addition, to allow more time for skating, the class is treated as if it began at 7:55 and all students must be ready to head outside or upstairs by 8:01. If a student does not arrive on time or before the rest of the class goes outside (or starts skating), they must wait by the benches near the lockers until the class returns at the end of the period and cannot skate with the class that day. If a student arrives late, and the class is no longer present at the lockers, they should also check the sixth floor gym, especially on a day not suitable to skate outside on, in case the class is skating in the gymnasium instead of outside. In this case, the student should get changed to skate, rather than sit near the lockers for the rest of the period.

==External links==
* [http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/all_%20courses/health_and_pe.htm Health and physical education courses] in the [http://register.stuy.edu/program_office/course_descriptions.html Course guide]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>SING!</title>
    <id>128</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1738</id>
      <timestamp>2010-04-26T01:10:40Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>661763939</username>
        <id>21</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Undo revision 1389 by [[Special:Contributions/68.173.34.115|68.173.34.115]] ([[User talk:68.173.34.115|Talk]])</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">'''SING!''' is an annual theater competition between the senior, junior, and &quot;soph-frosh&quot; (sophmores and freshmen combined) grades. The entire production is written, directed, produced, and funded by students. Their involvement ranges from being members of the production's casts, choruses, or costume, prop and tech crews to Step, Belly Dance, Hip-Hop, Swing, Ballet, Jazz, Latin, or multiple other dance groups. SING! begins in late January to February and the final performances occur on three nights in March or April. Scoring is done on each night's performances and the winner is determined by the overall total.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>SING! 2010</title>
    <id>127</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1267</id>
      <timestamp>2010-03-07T21:48:17Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>100000086344494</username>
        <id>6</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with ''''SING!''' is an annual theater competition between the senior, junior, and &quot;soph-frosh&quot; (sophmores and freshmen combined) grades. The entire production is written, directed, pr…'</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">'''SING!''' is an annual theater competition between the senior, junior, and &quot;soph-frosh&quot; (sophmores and freshmen combined) grades. The entire production is written, directed, produced, and funded by students. Their involvement ranges from being members of the production's casts, choruses, or costume and tech crews to Step, Belly Dance, Hip-Hop, Swing, Ballet, Jazz, Latin, or multiple other dance groups. SING! begins in late January to February and the final performances occur on three nights in March or April. Scoring is done on each night's performances and the winner is determined by the overall total.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Senioritis</title>
    <id>125</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3497</id>
      <timestamp>2011-01-30T19:24:10Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>updated for 2011</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[College decisions of the class of 2011]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Signup List</title>
    <id>2</id>
    <revision>
      <id>85</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-06T03:08:25Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>100000420217578</username>
        <id>4</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[M:Signup List]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[M:Signup List]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Stuypulse</title>
    <id>121</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94390</id>
      <timestamp>2011-07-27T17:01:49Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>74.64.16.63</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>RVV</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox clubpub
| name             = Stuypulse
| founded_in       = 2001
| president        = 
| vice_pres        = 
| secretary        = 
| treasurer        = 
| other_officers   = 
| teacher_advisor  = [[Mr.Rafael Colón|Mr. Colón]], [[Mr. James Lonardo|Mr. Lonardo]]
| size             = 200
| meeting_freq     = 
| meeting_day      = 
| publication_freq = 
| website          = http://stuypulse.com/
}}

'''Stuypulse''' is the official Stuyvesant High School robotics team, and competes in the prestigious [http://www.usfirst.org/ FIRST Robotics] competition. It is one of the largest clubs in the school, with approximately 60 active members as of the 2009 season. There are two groups, FRC (FIRST Robotics Challenge) and FTC (FIRST Tech Challenge). Competition time is usually around March/April and can go into May. 

== Faculty Advisors ==
*Mr. Colon
*Mr. Lonardo

== FRC ==
FRC or FIRST Robotics Challenge is a competition where teams try to build a robot to play a certain game, chosen by FIRST that year. The Kickoff is around New Year's and this is when the game is released, although a few hints that are seemingly unrelated are let out beforehand. The team then has 6 weeks to build the robot. This hectic time is known as the Build Season. The Build Season ends around February/March with the Ship Date, the day we must put our robot into its crate and send it to competition. We then go to the Jacob Javits Center to compete in the New York City Regional. Competition time starts around March and ends around April or May. It's an incredible experience and really brings the team together. There are three main branches of the FRC team:

=== Engineering ===
The largest branch of Stuypulse. The Engineers are responsible for building the robot and maintaining the past ones. They mainly work inside the robotics lab and use many power tools. Smaller parts include field construction, pneumatics, and electronics. Engineering works closely with the Programmers to make sure the robot can do what is needed of it. Engineering never has enough 7/16 wrenches. 

=== Programming ===
This branch is responsible for all the programming needed for the team. They write in languages such as Java and C++. The Programmers are a small but crucial part of the team. They work closely with Engineering to make sure the code fits with the robot. The Programmers have 7 computers: No Touchy, No Duchy, No Boxxy, No Lana, No Sleepy, No Lifey, and No Really.

=== Marketing ===
Marketing is the business and advertisement aspect of the team. They maintain the websites firstconnects.us and the team's website www.stuypulse.com. They also organize events such as bake sales and demonstrations. Every year, they aim for the prestigious Chairman's Award, given to the team that helps spread the spirit of FIRST the most and reaches out to the community. 

== FTC (FIRST Tech Challenge) ==

FIRST Tech Challenges consists of two teams, team 479 aka Fission and team 310 aka Fusion. They work using TETRIX and LEGO robotics kits and build multiple smaller robots as opposed to the single large FRC robot.

== The Robots==
*2001: Stuyle 

 Game: Diabolical Dynamics
*2002: Jack 

 Game: Zone Zeal

*2003: Lola 

 Game: Stack Attack

*2004: Larry 

 Game: FIRST Frenzy: Raising the Bar

*2005: Yvette

 Game: Triple Play

*2006: Joshua

 Game: Aim High

*2007: Tom

 Game: Rack'n'Roll

*2008: DESbot

 Game: FIRST Overdrive

*2009: Michael 1

 Game: Lunacy 
 Objective:

*2010: Donovan

 Game: Breakaway
 Objective: 

== Current Officers ==
*Presidents of Engineering: Adam Yabroudi and Johnny Lambert (Lambroudi?)
*Vice President of Engineering: Jake Potter
*President of Marketing: Mao &quot;Chairman&quot; Hu
*Vice President of Marketing: Doron Shapiro
*Director of Programming: Alex Carillo
*Presidents of FTC: Robert &quot;Mr. President&quot; Juchnicki and Abhi Ghosh

== Quotes ==
6-9-4! 6-9-4!

Joe Ricci is The Beast.

There are never enough 7/16 wrenches.

== External Links ==
*[http://usfirst.org/ USFIRST Website]
*[http://firstconnects.us/ firsconnects.us]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Stuypulse Robotics Team</title>
    <id>118</id>
    <revision>
      <id>1046</id>
      <timestamp>2010-02-11T06:15:29Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1244591903</username>
        <id>5</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Stuypulse]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">#REDIRECT [[Stuypulse]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Stuyvesant High School</title>
    <id>172</id>
    <revision>
      <id>2537</id>
      <timestamp>2010-07-21T01:20:55Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>1456397348</username>
        <id>59</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">The following link directs you to the Wikipedia article about '''Stuyvesant High School'''.
[http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuyvesant_High_School]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Symphony Orchestra</title>
    <id>205</id>
    <revision>
      <id>4113</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-08T04:03:13Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SkyCL</username>
        <id>77</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Symphony Orchestra
| department    = [[Music and Fine Arts]]
| code          = AUYSO
| teachers      = [[Joseph Tamosaitis]]
| typical_year  = [[Freshman]], [[Sophomore]], [[Junior]], or [[Senior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring
| fills         = [[Music Appreciation (with three terms)]], [[10 tech (with eight terms)]]
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = None required
| floor         = [[First]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Symphony Orchestra''' is one of the three orchestras at Stuyvesant and the top of the three. Acceptance into the symphony orchestra is by audition, rather than through online sign-up. The symphony orchestra plays at various school events, such as at least one concert each term. Students in the symphony orchestra also have the opportunity to be in a quartet. Mr. Tamosaitis is the only symphony orchestra teacher and it is only offered fifth period.

==Curriculum==
Though there is no strict curriculum for the symphony orchestra to follow, the symphony orchestra tends to begin at the basics of classical music every year, despite a majority of sophomores, juniors, and seniors every year, but most classes are spent playing music in preparation for concerts. The music played in this orchestra is usually at a high level recommended for experienced classical students.

==Teaching Style==
Mr. Tamosaitis usually begins the class with a tuning and a quick talk. After tuning, he goes directly into the repertoire of any upcoming performances.

==Grading Policy==
This class is based heavily on attendance. Excessive lateness or cutting can result in a low grade or even a failing grade, regardless of the student's skill in music.

==Quartets==
Select students from the symphony orchestra are asked to play in a quartet, which consists of about four students. In addition to the concerts that the symphony orchestra plays in, the quartet plays at various events around New York City after school and on weekends. The quartets plays much more challenging music than the orchestra and also allows its members to flourish and excel.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>System Level Programming</title>
    <id>96</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3867</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-02T06:07:05Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>69.127.20.173</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Textbooks */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Systems Level Programming
| department    = [[Mathematics department|Mathematics]]
| code          = ML5
| teachers      = [[Mr. Mike Zamansky|Mr. Zamansky]] and [[Mr. JonAlf Dyrland-Weaver|Mr. Dyrland-Weaver]]
| typical_year  = [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = Fall
| fills         = [[senior elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[AP Computer Science]]
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = The manual
| floor         = [[Third floor|Three]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Systems Level Programming''' is a senior computer science elective for students who took [[AP Computer Science]] as juniors.  The class focuses on using C to do more low-level programming than that in the AP class, such as networking.

==Curriculum==

The class is organized around various projects (around 5).  Projects often include an address book program and a shell for interpreting and running commands. Students are encouraged to pair up for projects: they tend to be more work than those in APCS.  In the first few weeks, the students are taught how to use C.  The curriculum covers venturing through files, forking processes, roots, accounts, and networking.  There is a final project at the end, where students are expected to use their knowledge to write a program of their choosing.  There are usually no tests.

==Teaching Style==

===Mr. Dyrland-Weaver===
Mr. DW's class is extremely relaxed. Much time is spent off topic, a fact which Mr. DW readily acknowledges. Homework is extremely sparse (3-4 assignments in total). Projects are done using svn repositories.

===Mr. Zamansky===
Mr. Zamansky's class tends to be fairly relaxed, moreso than his AP class.  The deadlines tend to not be too strict.

==Textbooks==

There is a manual included with the linux computers.  Type man _____ to look up a command.  You can use '''apropos''' to search for commands.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Topics in Neurobiology</title>
    <id>146</id>
    <revision>
      <id>95054</id>
      <timestamp>2011-09-14T22:46:36Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>74.64.16.63</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>rvv</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Topics in Neurobiology
| department    = [[Biology and Earth Science]]
| code          = 
| teachers      = [[Dr. Hemal Pathak|Dr. Pathak]]
| typical_year  = [[Senior year|Senior]] or [[Junior year|Junior]]
| terms         = Fall and Spring (one term only)
| fills         = [[Senior Elective requirement]], [[Science Elective requirement]]
| pre/coreqs    = [[Regents Living Environment]]
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = In Search of Memory: The Emergence of a New Science of Mind, Neuroscience: Exploring the Brain 
| floor         = [[Seventh]]

}}
'''Topics in Neurobiology''' is a new one term biology course on college level Neurobiology started in the 2009-2010 school year. Neurobiology is the study of the anatomy, function, and structure of the brain. The course discusses all the major brain structures and chemicals, disorders and diseases, and the latest research done in the field of Neurobiology. Another major topic is the molecular processes involved in functions of the brain, such as action potentials and neurotransmitters. There are also related labs throughout the term. As of now, there is only one class, and the class is currently being taught solely by [[Dr. Pathak]].

==Curriculum==
As this is still a new class, there is no set curriculum. The class frequently jumps from topic to topic. The class usually starts off with the molecular and chemical basis of the action potential in neurons, then gets broader, covering the various regions of the brain. 

Throughout the course, students will be instructed to read the memoir: In Search of Memory: The Emergence of a New Science of Mind, by Eric Kandel, which discusses Kandel's experiences in the field of Neuroscience. Once a week, students will be given a question sheet, which must be answered and handed in. Dr. Pathak will also assign students reading from the textbook: Neuroscience: Exploring the Brain. 

Sometime throughout the term, there will be laboratory sessions where students will examine brain slices and identify structures, and at the end of the term, there will be a sheep brain dissection, where Dr. Pathak will instruct students to identify the brain structures found in it. 
There may also be a cow's eye dissection, but as of now, it has not happened due to time constraints. 

==Teaching Style==
===General===
Dr. Pathak is a very lenient and lax teacher, and unfortunately has a hard time controlling the class due to his passiveness. He generally does not expect anything out of his students, and does not care if assignments are handed in a few days late. Usually it takes between 5 to 10 minutes for him to get the class settled before he can start his lesson. 

===Tests and homework===
Dr. Pathak tends to give high 90s to most of his students, as long as they hand in their assignments and stay attentive in class. During the first term of the class, he gave one test in the middle of the year, which covered topic he did not teach, resulting in a significant portion of the class failing. He also gave a optional final. Generally, the curve is ridiculously high, and most people end up with a 90+ even if they do terribly on his tests.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Video Production</title>
    <id>95</id>
    <revision>
      <id>94389</id>
      <timestamp>2011-07-27T17:00:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>74.64.16.63</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>rvv</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Video Production
| department    = [[Technology department|Technology]]
| code          = TQPPVP5
| teachers      = [[Ms. Elka Gould]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] 
| terms         = Fall or Spring
| fills         = [[5-tech]] requirement
| pre/coreqs    = [[Advanced Video Production]]
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = Voice and Vision: A Creative Approach to Narrative Film and DV Production
| floor         = [[First floor|First]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Video Production''' is a one-term single period 5-Tech class that introduces students to and teaches the basics of creating short films. Students work collaboratively to learn about the production process and to create short films of their own. Video Production is taught solely by 
[[Ms. Elka Gould]]. 

Notably, Video Production is one of the most sought after 5-Tech classes, alongside Digital Photography, for its engaging and enjoyable atmosphere. 


==Curriculum==
Students must pay a fee at the beginning of the term in order to handle the equipment and use the lab rooms for the remainder of the term. The films are edited on computers in 5 small, enclosed rooms within the main classroom. 

The term begins with a preview of the course and may incorporate clips of movies that Ms. Gould wishes to show. Several basic lessons on film-making terminology are given, along with a rudimentary explanation of proper conduct when handling equipment. The following week, the students are divided into groups of 5 and 6, which remain the same for the rest of the term. The course then shifts to more in-depth lessons on individual aspects of film, such as cameras, screen resolutions, sound, lighting, and shot types. 

After these basic lessons, the groups are given the first assignment — an in-class 2 minute narrative film project. The groups begin work by brainstorming possible ideas and plots. Further lessons on script writing and film teamwork supplement the process. 

The focus shifts to each group's respective project, with occasional short lessons on the video editing program in use, Final Cut Pro. Upon completing the first project, students are given another set of lessons, along with a second assignment — a 5 minute documentary. Lessons at this point generally cover the documentary genre of film, as well as the difference between a documentary and a narrative.

==Teaching Style==
===Grading===
Ms. Gould assigns a grade every marking period that is based on each group's respective video project(s) for that period. She generally grades fairly leniently, especially for projects that are incomplete.

===General===
Periods are either work periods or lesson periods. Prior to each work period, groups must fill out log sheets reporting attendance and assigning group roles, such as director, cameraman, line director, grip, etc. During such periods, groups will be allowed to develop their film projects. Scripts and other documents must be completed before groups can begin working with the cameras and tapes. Once groups have filled out their daily log sheets, they can leave the room to film at other locations in the school. Groups that have finished filming take their tapes to the editing rooms to sequence and arrange the final video.

Lesson periods take place in the main classroom. There are no assigned seats; students sit on stools and chairs facing a projector screen. The lessons are given by computer projector and often involve demonstration of said information. 

Ms. Gould alternates between work periods and lesson periods, keeping a balance between producing films and learning. 

===Homework===
On occasion, Ms. Gould may assign homework from the Voice and Visions textbook. Students are to read assigned chapters and sections of the book and summarize them, typed, in detail. This homework is generally collected at the end of class or at the end of the lesson, in the event there is remaining time for work.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Wall Street with Merrill Lynch</title>
    <id>94</id>
    <revision>
      <id>4014</id>
      <timestamp>2011-02-05T22:30:45Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>173.52.29.10</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Curriculum */</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Wall Street with Merrill Lynch
| department    = [[Social Studies Department|Social Studies]]
| code          = HF5PWS
| teachers      = [[Mr. George Kennedy]]
| typical_year  = [[Senior year|Senior]] or [[Junior year|Junior]] with preference to Seniors
| terms         = Fall or Spring
| fills         = 
| pre/coreqs    = 
| pre/coreq_for = 
| textbooks     = 
| floor         = [[Third Floor|Third]]
| website       = 
}}

'''Wall Street with Merrill Lynch''' is a single term single-period History course that introduces students to basic finances. The course material includes how financial markets function and covers current financial events.

==Curriculum==
The curriculum begins with the introduction of Wall Street finance. Stocks, mutual funds, bonds, and options are some of the markets highlighted by the course. The course also implements the Stock Market Game to give students the opportunity to simulate the management of a portfolio. The course also goes over the history of finance with respect to stocks. Students are also expected to keep updated with current events in the financial world.  

As of winter of 2010, the Wall Street class's relationship with Merrill Lynch (now Bank of America Merill Lynch) was reinstated.  Students will have an opportunity to visit the Bank of America Tower located at 1 Bryant Park.  Throughout the day, students will hear from guest speakers and visit the trading floor.

==Teaching style==
===Mr. Kennedy===
Mr. Kennedy takes a very discussion-oriented approach to the class. Mr. Kennedy will write terms and phrases on the board prior to beginning his discussion, which will often include articles read from the Wall Street Journal distributed in the beginning of the class. He will often incorporate films into the class to cover topics such as the leveraged buyout of RJR Nabisco, the fall of Long Term Capital Management, the financial meltdown of 2008, etc. He will accept late homework until the marking period ends, but he prefers that homework is done on time. His tests are almost always based on the homework and reading he has assigned.  Also he requires a book report on a current book on finance as a term project.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Weight Training</title>
    <id>187</id>
    <revision>
      <id>3488</id>
      <timestamp>2011-01-29T02:40:38Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>100001479529869</username>
        <id>64</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox class
| name          = Weight Training
| department    = Health and Education
| code          = 
| teachers      = [[Mr. Miller]]
| typical_year  = [[Junior year|Junior]] or [[Senior year|Senior]]
| terms         = fall and spring
| fills         = [[gym requirement]]
| floor         = [[Fifth floor|Five]]
}}

'''Weight training''' is a one-term gym class in the weight room. Students are allowed free access to all equipment and machines within the weight room. During class, students may choose to exercise either within the weight room or the fifth floor hallway. Machines and equipment available include, but are not limited to: dumbbells of various weights, jump ropes, balancing platforms, rowing machine, chest press machine, leg press, bicep curls, and bicycle machine.</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Writing Across the Curriculum</title>
    <id>267</id>
    <revision>
      <id>97172</id>
      <timestamp>2013-08-12T19:02:44Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>69.203.218.132</ip>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Infobox
| name          = &quot;Writing Across the Curriculum&quot;
| Years in effect          = 2008-2012
}}
&lt;center&gt;'''''NOTE: Writing across the curriculum is no longer in effect as of Fall 2013'''''&lt;/center&gt;

'''Writing Across the Curriculum''' is a movement implemented by former Principal [[Stanley Teitel]] in order to increase the writing abilities of students at Stuyvesant and to address the growing perception that Stuyvesant is merely a Math and Science High School. Under the policy, all classes are expected to have at least one &quot;major&quot; written assignment every marking period. This is similar to the policies of many prestigious American Universities, most notably at MIT&lt;ref&gt;[http://writing.mit.edu/wac MIT]&lt;/ref&gt;


==Reception==
The policy generated mixed responses. A few teachers often felt it was unnecessary and/or useless. Many Math and Science teachers complied with the policy, although few put any emphasis(especially grade-wise) on these assignments.

One part of the policy was implementing essays into the the [[Summer Reading]] assignment for Freshman, [[Microbe Hunters]]. However, the finished packets of student work were often ignored by most science teachers who by policy had to collect the assignments around the beginning of the school year. Physics teachers especially did not grade the assignments. 

In 2012, the humor department of the [[Spectator]] mocked the policy by extending it towards lunch.&lt;ref&gt;[http://stuyspectator.com/2012/04/15/writing-across-the-curriculum-extended-to-lunch-classes/ Spectator Humor]&lt;/ref&gt;
==Notes==
&lt;references/&gt;

==External links==
* [http://stuyspectator.com/2008/10/08/teitel%E2%80%99s-new-initiative-writing-across-the-curriculum/ The Stuyvesant Spectator] 
* {{Wikipedia|Advanced Placement Game Theory}}
* {{Wikipedia|Game Theory}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Infobox</title>
    <id>14</id>
    <revision>
      <id>261</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-13T17:10:00Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Template:Infobox]]&quot; ([edit=sysop] (indefinite) [move=sysop] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;table class=&quot;infobox {{{bodyclass|}}}&quot; cellspacing=&quot;5&quot; style=&quot;width:22em; text-align:left; font-size:88%; line-height:1.5em; {{{bodystyle|}}}&quot;&gt;&lt;!--
 Caption
--&gt;{{#if:{{{title|}}}|&lt;caption class=&quot;{{{titleclass|}}}&quot; style=&quot;font-size:125%; font-weight:bold; {{{titlestyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{{title}}}&lt;/caption&gt;}}&lt;!--
 Header
--&gt;{{#if:{{{above|}}}|{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{above|}}} |headerstyle=text-align:center; font-size:125%; font-weight:bold; {{{abovestyle|}}}
 |class={{{aboveclass|}}} |rowclass={{{aboverowclass|}}}
}} }}&lt;!--
 Subheader1
--&gt;{{#if:{{{subheader|}}}|{{Infobox/row
 |data={{{subheader|}}}     |datastyle={{{subheaderstyle|}}}
 |class={{{subheaderclass|}}}   |rowclass={{{subheaderrowclass1|}}}
}} }}&lt;!--
 Subheader2
--&gt;{{#if:{{{subheader2|}}}|{{Infobox/row
 |data={{{subheader2|}}}     |datastyle={{{subheaderstyle|}}}
 |class={{{subheaderclass|}}}   |rowclass={{{subheaderrowclass2|}}}
}} }}&lt;!--
 Image1
--&gt;{{#if:{{{image|{{{image1|}}}}}}|{{Infobox/row
 |data={{{image|{{{image1}}} }}}{{#if:{{{caption|{{{caption1|}}}}}}|&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;{{{captionstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{{caption|{{{caption1}}}}}}&lt;/span&gt;}}     |datastyle={{{imagestyle|}}}
 |class={{{imageclass|}}}   |rowclass={{{imagerowclass1|}}}
}} }}&lt;!--
 Image2
--&gt;{{#if:{{{image2|}}}|{{Infobox/row
 |data={{{image2|}}}{{#if:{{{caption2|}}}|&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;{{{captionstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{{caption2|}}}&lt;/span&gt;}}     |datastyle={{{imagestyle|}}}
 |class={{{imageclass|}}}   |rowclass={{{imagerowclass2|}}}
}} }}&lt;!--
--&gt;{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header1|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label1|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data1|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class1|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass1|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header2|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label2|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data2|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class2|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass2|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header3|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label3|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data3|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class3|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass3|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header4|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label4|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data4|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class4|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass4|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header5|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label5|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data5|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class5|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass5|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header6|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label6|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data6|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class6|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass6|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header7|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label7|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data7|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class7|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass7|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header8|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label8|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data8|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class8|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass8|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header9|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label9|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data9|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class9|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass9|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header10|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label10|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data10|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class10|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass10|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header11|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label11|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data11|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class11|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass11|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header12|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label12|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data12|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class12|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass12|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header13|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label13|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data13|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class13|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass13|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header14|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label14|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data14|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class14|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass14|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header15|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label15|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data15|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class15|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass15|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header16|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label16|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data16|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class16|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass16|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header17|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label17|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data17|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class17|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass17|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header18|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label18|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data18|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class18|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass18|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header19|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label19|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data19|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class19|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass19|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header20|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label20|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data20|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class20|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass20|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header21|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label21|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data21|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class21|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass21|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header22|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label22|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data22|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class22|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass22|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header23|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label23|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data23|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class23|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass23|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header24|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label24|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data24|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class24|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass24|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header25|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label25|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data25|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class25|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass25|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header26|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label26|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data26|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class26|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass26|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header27|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label27|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data27|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class27|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass27|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header28|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label28|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data28|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class28|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass28|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header29|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label29|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data29|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class29|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass29|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header30|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label30|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data30|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class30|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass30|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header31|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label31|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data31|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class31|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass31|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header32|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label32|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data32|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class32|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass32|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header33|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label33|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data33|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class33|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass33|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header34|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label34|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data34|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class34|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass34|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header35|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label35|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data35|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class35|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass35|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header36|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label36|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data36|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class36|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass36|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header37|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label37|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data37|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class37|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass37|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header38|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label38|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data38|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class38|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass38|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header39|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label39|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data39|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class39|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass39|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header40|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label40|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data40|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class40|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass40|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header41|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label41|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data41|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class41|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass41|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header42|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label42|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data42|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class42|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass42|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header43|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label43|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data43|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class43|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass43|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header44|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label44|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data44|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class44|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass44|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header45|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label45|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data45|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class45|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass45|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header46|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label46|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data46|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class46|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass46|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header47|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label47|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data47|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class47|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass47|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header48|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label48|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data48|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class48|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass48|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header49|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label49|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data49|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class49|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass49|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header50|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label50|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data50|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class50|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass50|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header51|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label51|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data51|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class51|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass51|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header52|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label52|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data52|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class52|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass52|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header53|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label53|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data53|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class53|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass53|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header54|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label54|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data54|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class54|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass54|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header55|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label55|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data55|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class55|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass55|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header56|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label56|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data56|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class56|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass56|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header57|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label57|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data57|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class57|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass57|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header58|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label58|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data58|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class58|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass58|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header59|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label59|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data59|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class59|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass59|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header60|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label60|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data60|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class60|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass60|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header61|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label61|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data61|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class61|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass61|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header62|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label62|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data62|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class62|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass62|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header63|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label63|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data63|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class63|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass63|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header64|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label64|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data64|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class64|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass64|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header65|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label65|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data65|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class65|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass65|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header66|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label66|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data66|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class66|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass66|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header67|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label67|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data67|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class67|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass67|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header68|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label68|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data68|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class68|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass68|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header69|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label69|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data69|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class69|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass69|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header70|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label70|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data70|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class70|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass70|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header71|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label71|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data71|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class71|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass71|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header72|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label72|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data72|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class72|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass72|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header73|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label73|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data73|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class73|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass73|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header74|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label74|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data74|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class74|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass74|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header75|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label75|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data75|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class75|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass75|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header76|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label76|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data76|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class76|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass76|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header77|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label77|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data77|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class77|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass77|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header78|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label78|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data78|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class78|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass78|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header79|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label79|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data79|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class79|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass79|}}}
}}{{Infobox/row
 |header={{{header80|}}} |headerstyle={{{headerstyle|}}}
 |label={{{label80|}}}   |labelstyle={{{labelstyle|}}}
 |data={{{data80|}}}     |datastyle={{{datastyle|}}}
 |class={{{class80|}}}   |rowclass={{{rowclass80|}}}
}}&lt;!-- Below
--&gt;{{#if:{{{below|}}}|&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;{{{belowclass|}}}&quot; style=&quot;text-align:center; {{{belowstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{{below}}}&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;}}&lt;!--
 Navbar
--&gt;{{#if:{{{name|}}}|&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;text-align:right&quot;&gt;{{navbar|{{{name}}}|noedit={{{noedit|0}}}}}&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;}}
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;noinclude&gt;
{{pp-template|small=yes}}
{{documentation}}
&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Infobox/row</title>
    <id>25</id>
    <revision>
      <id>277</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-13T17:20:50Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Template:Infobox/row]]&quot; ([edit=sysop] (indefinite) [move=sysop] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{#if:{{{header|}}}
 |&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;text-align:center; {{{headerstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{{header}}}&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 |{{#if:{{{data|}}}
  |&lt;tr class=&quot;{{{rowclass|}}}&quot;&gt;{{#if:{{{label|}}}
   |&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left; {{{labelstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{{label}}}&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td class=&quot;{{{class|}}}&quot; style=&quot;{{{datastyle|}}}&quot;&gt;
   |&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;{{{class|}}}&quot; style=&quot;text-align:center; {{{datastyle|}}}&quot;&gt;
  }}{{{data}}}&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 }}
}}</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Infobox class</title>
    <id>61</id>
    <revision>
      <id>580</id>
      <timestamp>2010-01-02T04:56:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Teacher(s)</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;noinclude&gt;{{start infobox page}}&lt;/noinclude&gt;&lt;!--
--&gt;{{Infobox

| bodystyle  = width:20em; text-align:left; font-size:90%;
| above      = {{{name&lt;includeonly&gt;|&lt;/includeonly&gt;}}}
| abovestyle = background:#ccffcc;
| labelstyle = padding:0.2em; background:transparent; line-height:1.1em; width:33%;
| datastyle  = padding:0.2em; line-height:1.2em; vertical-align:middle;

| label1     = Department
| data1      = {{{department|}}}
| label2     = Code
| data2      = {{{code|}}}
| label3     = Teacher(s)
| data3      = {{{teachers|}}}
| label4     = Typical year taken
| data4      = {{{typical_year|}}}
| label5     = Term(s)
| data5      = {{{terms|}}}
| label6     = Fills
| data6      = {{{fills|}}}
| label7     = Pre- and corequisite(s)
| data7      = {{{pre/coreqs|}}}
| label8     = Pre- or corequisite for
| data8      = {{{pre/coreq_for|}}}
| label9     = Textbook(s)
| data9      = {{{textbooks|}}}
| label10    = Floor
| data10     = {{{floor|}}}
| data11     = {{#if:{{{website&lt;includeonly&gt;|&lt;/includeonly&gt;}}}
                 | '''Website'''&lt;br/&gt;{{{website|}}}}}
}}&lt;noinclude&gt;
{{end infobox page}}

&lt;!---Please add metadata to the &lt;includeonly&gt; section on the /doc subpage, not here!---&gt;
&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Wikipedia</title>
    <id>76</id>
    <revision>
      <id>520</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-28T01:15:49Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Template:Wikipedia]]&quot; ([edit=sysop] (indefinite) [move=sysop] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;includeonly&gt;[[Wikipedia:{{{1|{{PAGENAME}}}}}|{{{2|{{{1|{{PAGENAME}}}}}}}}]] at [[Wikipedia:|Wikipedia]]&lt;/includeonly&gt;&lt;noinclude&gt;{{doc}}&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Infobox clubpub</title>
    <id>64</id>
    <revision>
      <id>415</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-22T03:52:55Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Template:Infobox clubpub]]&quot; ([edit=autoconfirmed] (indefinite) [move=autoconfirmed] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;noinclude&gt;{{start infobox page}}&lt;/noinclude&gt;&lt;!--
--&gt;{{Infobox

| bodystyle  = width:20em; text-align:left; font-size:90%;
| above      = {{{name&lt;includeonly&gt;|&lt;/includeonly&gt;}}}
| abovestyle = background:#F0E68C;
| labelstyle = padding:0.2em; background:transparent; line-height:1.1em; width:33%;
| datastyle  = padding:0.2em; line-height:1.2em; vertical-align:middle;

| label1     = Type
| data1      = {{{type|}}}
| label2     = Founded in
| data2      = {{{founded_in|}}}
| label3     = President
| data3      = {{{president|}}}
| label4     = Vice president
| data4      = {{{vice_pres|}}}
| label5     = Secretary
| data5      = {{{secretary|}}}
| label6     = Treasurer
| data6      = {{{treasurer|}}}
| label7     = Other officer(s)
| data7      = {{{other_officers|}}}
| label8     = Teacher advisor
| data8      = {{{teacher_advisor|}}}
| label9     = Size
| data9      = {{{size|}}}
| label10    = Meeting frequency
| data10     = {{{meeting_freq|}}}
| label11    = Usual meeting day
| data11     = {{{meeting_day|}}}
| label12    = Publication frequency
| data12     = {{{publication_freq|}}}
| data13     = {{#if:{{{website&lt;includeonly&gt;|&lt;/includeonly&gt;}}}
                 | '''Website'''&lt;br/&gt;{{{website|}}}}}
}}&lt;noinclude&gt;
{{end infobox page}}

&lt;!---Please add metadata to the &lt;includeonly&gt; section on the /doc subpage, not here!---&gt;
&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Navbar</title>
    <id>16</id>
    <revision>
      <id>267</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-13T17:12:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Template:Navbar]]&quot; ([edit=sysop] (indefinite) [move=sysop] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;includeonly&gt;{{#if:{{{nodiv|}}}|&amp;nbsp;&lt;span|&lt;div}} class=&quot;noprint plainlinks navbar&quot; style=&quot;background:none; padding:0; font-weight:normal;{{{fontstyle|}}}; font-size:xx-small; {{{style|}}}&quot;&gt;&lt;!--

--&gt;{{#if:{{{mini|}}}{{{plain|}}}|&lt;!--nothing--&gt;|&lt;!--else:
--&gt;This box:&amp;#32;}}&lt;!--

--&gt;{{#if:{{{brackets|}}}|&amp;#91;}}&lt;!--

--&gt;[[{{transclude|{{{1}}}}}|&lt;span title=&quot;View this template&quot; style=&quot;{{{fontstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;&lt;!--
--&gt;{{#if:{{{mini|}}}|v|view}}&lt;/span&gt;]]&lt;!--

--&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:80%;&quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;[[{{TALKPAGENAME:{{transclude|{{{1}}}}}}}|&lt;span title=&quot;Discuss this template&quot; style=&quot;{{{fontstyle|}}}&quot;&gt;{{#if:{{{mini|}}}|d|talk}}&lt;/span&gt;]]&lt;!--

--&gt;{{#if:{{{noedit|}}}|&lt;!--nothing--&gt;|&lt;!--else:
--&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:80%;&quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;[{{fullurl:{{transclude|{{{1}}}}}|action=edit}}&lt;span title=&quot;Edit this template&quot; style=&quot;{{{fontstyle|}}};&quot;&gt;{{#if:{{{mini|}}}|e|edit}}&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;!--
--&gt;}}&lt;!--

--&gt;{{#if:{{{brackets|}}}|]}}&lt;!--

--&gt;{{#if:{{{nodiv|}}}|&lt;!--then:
--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;|&lt;!--else:
--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;}}&lt;/includeonly&gt;&lt;noinclude&gt;

{{pp-template|small=yes}}
{{documentation}}
&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Template:Transclude</title>
    <id>30</id>
    <revision>
      <id>276</id>
      <timestamp>2009-12-13T17:20:20Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>569698669</username>
        <id>7</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Protected &quot;[[Template:Transclude]]&quot; ([edit=sysop] (indefinite) [move=sysop] (indefinite))</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{#switch: {{NAMESPACE: {{{1}}} }}
 |#default = {{FULLPAGENAME: {{{1}}} }} &lt;!-- eg &quot;User:Foo&quot; --&gt;
 |{{ns:0}} = 
    {{#ifeq: {{NAMESPACE: {{{1}}} }} | {{NAMESPACE: Template{{{1}}} }}
      | Template:{{{1}}}            &lt;!-- no leading colon, eg &quot;Foo&quot; --&gt;
      | {{PAGENAME: {{{1}}} }}      &lt;!-- leading colon, eg &quot;:Foo&quot;, so we want the article --&gt;
    }}
}}&lt;noinclude&gt;
{{documentation}}
&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
